<cards>
<name>Fourth Edition</name>
<releaseDate>1995-04-01</releaseDate>
<shortname>4ED</shortname><list>
<mc>
  <id>2014</id>
  <name>Aladdin's Lamp</name>
  <cost>{10}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{X}, {T}: The next time you would draw a card this turn, instead look at the top X cards of your library, shuffle all but one of them, put the shuffled cards on the bottom of your library, then draw a card. X can't be 0.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{X}, {T}: Instead of drawing a card from the top of your library, draw X cards but choose only one to put into your hand. Shuffle the leftover cards and put them at the bottom of your library. X cannot be 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>10</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2015</id>
  <name>Aladdin's Ring</name>
  <cost>{8}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{8}, {T}: Aladdin's Ring deals 4 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"After these words the magician drew a ring off his finger, and put it on one of Aladdin's, saying: --'It is a talisman against all evil, so long as you obey me.'"The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2016</id>
  <name>Amulet of Kroog</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Prevent 1 damage to any creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Among the first allies Urza gained were the people of Kroog. As a sign of friendship, Urza gave the healers of the city potent amulets; afterwards, thousands journeyed to Kroog in hope of healing.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2017</id>
  <name>Ankh of Mishra</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a land comes into play, Ankh of Mishra deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each time a player puts a land into play, Ankh of Mishra deals 2 damage to that player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2018</id>
  <name>Armageddon Clock</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a doom counter on Armageddon Clock. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your draw step, Armageddon Clock deals damage to each player equal to the number of doom counters on it. &lt;br&gt;{4}: Remove a doom counter from Armageddon Clock. Any player may play this ability but only during any upkeep step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, put one doom counter on Armageddon Clock. At the end of your upkeep, Armageddon Clock deals X damage to each player, where X is the number of doom counters on Armageddon Clock. During any upkeep, any player may pay {4} to remove a doom counter from Armageddon Clock.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2019</id>
  <name>Ashnod's Battle Gear</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Ashnod's Battle Gear during your untap step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{2}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +2/-2 as long as Ashnod's Battle Gear remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +2/-2 as long as Ashnod's Battle Gear remains tapped. You may choose not to untap Ashnod's Battle Gear during your untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>This invention shows why Ashnod was feared by her troops as well as her foes.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2020</id>
  <name>Battering Ram</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your combat phase, Battering Ram gains banding until end of combat. &lt;br&gt;Whenever Battering Ram becomes blocked by a Wall, destroy that Wall at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding when attacking&lt;br&gt;At the end of combat, destroy all walls blocking Battering Ram.</printedText>
  <flavorText>By the time Mishra was defeated, no mage was foolish enough to rely heavily on walls.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2021</id>
  <name>Black Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Black Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Black Mana Battery: Add {B} to your mana pool, then add an additional {B} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Put one charge counter on Black Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool and remove as many charge counters as you wish. For each charge counter removed from Black Mana Battery, add {B} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2022</id>
  <name>Black Vise</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>As Black Vise comes into play, choose an opponent. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, Black Vise deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of cards in his or her hand minus 4.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of target opponent's upkeep, Black Vise deals that player 1 damage for each card in his or her hand in excess of four.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2023</id>
  <name>Blue Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Blue Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Blue Mana Battery: Add {U} to your mana pool, then add an additional {U} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Put one charge counter on Blue Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool and remove as many charge counters as you wish. For each charge counter removed from Blue Mana Battery, add {U} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2024</id>
  <name>Bottle of Suleiman</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, Sacrifice Bottle of Suleiman: Flip a coin. If you lose the flip, Bottle of Suleiman deals 5 damage to you. If you win the flip, put a 5/5 Djinn artifact creature token with flying into play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Sacrifice Bottle of Suleiman. Flip a coin; target opponent calls heads or tails while coin is in the air. If the flip ends up in opponent's favor, Bottle of Suleiman deals 5 damage to you. Otherwise, put a Djinn token into play. Treat this token as a 5/5 artifact creature with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2025</id>
  <name>Brass Man</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Brass Man doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {1}. If you do, untap Brass Man.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Brass Man does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{1}: Untap Brass Man. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2026</id>
  <name>Bronze Tablet</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Bronze Tablet from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Bronze Tablet comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{4}, {T}: Target nontoken permanent's controller may pay 10 life. If he or she does, remove Bronze Tablet from the game. If he or she doesn't and Bronze Tablet is in play, you own that permanent and that player owns Bronze Tablet, then remove Bronze Tablet and that permanent from the game.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Comes into play tapped.&lt;br&gt;{4}, {T}: Remove Bronze Tablet and target card opponent owns from the game. You become owner of opponent's card, and opponent becomes owner of Bronze Tablet. Opponent may prevent this exchange by paying 10 life; if he or she does so, destroy Bronze Tablet. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life. Play this ability as an interrupt.&lt;br&gt;Remove Bronze Tablet from your deck before playing if not playing for ante.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2027</id>
  <name>Celestial Prism</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2028</id>
  <name>Clay Statue</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Golem</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}: Regenerate Clay Statue.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>Tawnos won fame as Urza's greatest assistant. After he created these warriors, Urza ended his apprenticeship, promoting him directly to the rank of master.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2029</id>
  <name>Clockwork Avian</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Clockwork Avian comes into play with four +1/+0 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;Clockwork Avian can't have more than four +1/+0 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;At end of combat, if Clockwork Avian attacked or blocked this turn, remove a +1/+0 counter from it. &lt;br&gt;{X}, {T}: Put X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;When Clockwork Avian comes into play, put four +1/+0 counters on it. At the end of any combat in which Clockwork Avian is assigned to attack or block, remove a counter.&lt;br&gt;{X}, {T}: Put X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Avian. You may have no more than four of these counters on Clockwork Avian. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2030</id>
  <name>Clockwork Beast</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Beast</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Clockwork Beast comes into play with seven +1/+0 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;At end of combat, if Clockwork Beast attacked or blocked this turn, remove a +1/+0 counter from it. &lt;br&gt;{X}, {T}: Put up to X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast. This ability can't cause the total number of +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast to be greater than seven. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Clockwork Beast comes into play, put seven +1/+0 counters on it. At the end of any combat in which Clockwork Beast is assigned to attack or block, remove a counter.&lt;br&gt;{X}, {T}: Put X +1/+0 counters on Clockwork Beast. You may have no more than seven of these counters on Clockwork Beast. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2031</id>
  <name>Colossus of Sardia</name>
  <cost>{9}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Golem</type>
  <power>9</power>
  <toughness>9</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample (If this creature would deal enough combat damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player.) &lt;br&gt;Colossus of Sardia doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{9}: Untap Colossus of Sardia. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Colossus does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{9}: Untap Colossus. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>From the Sardian mountains wakes ancient doom:&lt;br&gt;Warrior born from a rocky womb.</flavorText>
  <cmc>9</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2032</id>
  <name>Conservator</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}, {T}: Prevent up to 2 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2033</id>
  <name>Coral Helm</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, Discard a card at random: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Discard a card at random from your hand to give target creature +2/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2034</id>
  <name>Crystal Rod</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a blue spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life for a successfully cast blue spell. Use this effect either when the spell is cast or later in the turn but only once for each blue spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2035</id>
  <name>Cursed Rack</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>As Cursed Rack comes into play, choose an opponent. &lt;br&gt;The chosen player's maximum hand size is four.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target opponent discards down to four cards during his or her discard phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Ashnod invented several torture techniques that could make victims even miles away beg for mercy as if the End had come.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2036</id>
  <name>Dancing Scimitar</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>Bobbing merrily from opponent to opponent, the scimitar began adding playful little flourishes to its strokes; it even turned a couple of somersaults.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2037</id>
  <name>Diabolic Machine</name>
  <cost>{7}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}: Regenerate Diabolic Machine.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The bolts of our ballistae smashed into the monstrous thing, but our hopes died in our chests as its gears continued turning."&lt;br&gt;--Sevti Mukul, The Fall of Alsoor</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2038</id>
  <name>Dingus Egg</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a land is put into a graveyard from play, Dingus Egg deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each time a player puts a land into the graveyard from play, Dingus Egg deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2039</id>
  <name>Disrupting Scepter</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Play this ability only during your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}, {T}: Target player chooses and discards one card from his or her hand. Use this ability only during your turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2040</id>
  <name>Dragon Engine</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}: Dragon Engine gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>Those who believed the city of Kroog would never fall to Mishra's forces severely underestimated the might of his war machines.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2041</id>
  <name>Ebony Horse</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Untap target attacking creature you control. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Untap target attacking creature you control. That creature neither receives nor deals damage during combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2042</id>
  <name>Fellwar Stone</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add one mana to your mana pool. This mana may be of any type that any land opponent controls can produce. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What do you have that I cannot obtain?"&lt;br&gt;--Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2043</id>
  <name>Flying Carpet</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn. If that creature is put into the graveyard before end of turn, destroy Flying Carpet.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2044</id>
  <name>Glasses of Urza</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Look at target player's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Look at target player's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2045</id>
  <name>Grapeshot Catapult</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Grapeshot Catapult deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Grapeshot Catapult deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Recent research suggests these creatures were invented by Urza's and Mishra's original master, Tocasia, and that both brothers used them.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2046</id>
  <name>Green Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Green Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Green Mana Battery: Add {G} to your mana pool, then add an additional {G} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Put one charge counter on Green Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool and remove as many charge counters as you wish. For each charge counter removed from Green Mana Battery, add {G} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2047</id>
  <name>Helm of Chatzuk</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}, {T}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2048</id>
  <name>Howling Mine</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's draw step, if Howling Mine is untapped, that player draws a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each player draws one extra card during his or her draw phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2049</id>
  <name>Iron Star</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a red spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life for a successfully cast red spell. Use this effect either when the spell is cast or later in the turn but only once for each red spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2050</id>
  <name>Ivory Cup</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a white spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life for a successfully cast white spell. Use this effect either when the spell is cast or later in the turn but only once for each white spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2051</id>
  <name>Ivory Tower</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, you gain X life, where X is the number of cards in your hand minus four.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the beginning of your upkeep, gain 1 life for each card in your hand in excess of four.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Valuing scholarship above all else, the inhabitants of the Ivory Tower reward those who sacrifice power for knowledge.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2052</id>
  <name>Jade Monolith</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to target creature this turn, that source deals that damage to you instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Redirect to yourself all damage done to any creature. The source of the damage does not change.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2053</id>
  <name>Jandor's Saddlebags</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Untap target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}, {T}: Untap target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Each day of their journey, Jandor opened the saddlebags and found them full of mutton, quinces, cheese, date rolls, wine, and all manner of delicious and satisfying foods.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2054</id>
  <name>Jayemdae Tome</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: Draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4}, {T}: Draw one card.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2055</id>
  <name>Kormus Bell</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>All Swamps are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All swamps become 1/1 black creatures. The swamps still count as lands but cannot be tapped for mana the turn they come into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2056</id>
  <name>Library of Leng</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>You have no maximum hand size. &lt;br&gt;If an effect causes you to discard a card, discard it, but you may put it on top of your library instead of into your graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Skip the discard phase of your turn. If a spell or effect forces you to discard, you may discard to the top of your library rather than to your graveyard. If the discard is random, you may look at the card before choosing where to discard it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2057</id>
  <name>Mana Vault</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Mana Vault doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {4}. If you do, untap Mana Vault. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your draw step, if Mana Vault is tapped, it deals 1 damage to you. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Mana Vault does not untap during your untap phase. If it remains tapped during your upkeep, Mana Vault deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{4}: Untap Mana Vault. Use this ability only during your upkeep.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add three colorless mana to your mana pool. Play these additions as interrupts.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2058</id>
  <name>Meekstone</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with power 3 or greater don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No creatures with power greater than 2 untap during their controllers' untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2059</id>
  <name>Millstone</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Take the top two cards from target player's library and put them into that player's graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText>More than one mage was driven insane by the sound of the Millstone relentlessly grinding away.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2060</id>
  <name>Mishra's War Machine</name>
  <cost>{7}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Juggernaut</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you discard a card, tap Mishra's War Machine and it deals 3 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, choose and discard one card from your hand, or Mishra's War Machine deals 3 damage to you. If Mishra's War Machine deals damage to you in this way, tap it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2061</id>
  <name>Nevinyrral's Disk</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Nevinyrral's Disk comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt;{1}, {T}: Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and enchantments.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Comes into play tapped.&lt;br&gt;{1}, {T}: Destroy all creatures, enchantments, and artifacts, including Nevinyrral's Disk itself.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2062</id>
  <name>Obsianus Golem</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Golem</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"The foot stone is connected to the ankle stone, the ankle stone is connected to the leg stone . . . ."&lt;br&gt;--Song of the Artificer</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2063</id>
  <name>Onulet</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>When Onulet is put into a graveyard from play, you gain 2 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Onulet is put into the graveyard from play, you gain 2 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>An early inspiration for Urza, Tocasia's Onulets contained magical essences that could be cannibalized after they stopped functioning.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2064</id>
  <name>Ornithopter</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Thopter</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>Many scholars believe that these creatures were the result of Urza's first attempt at mechanical life, perhaps created in his early days as an apprentice to Tocasia.</flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2065</id>
  <name>Primal Clay</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Primal Clay comes into play as your choice of a 3/3 artifact creature, a 2/2 artifact creature with flying, or a 1/6 Shapeshifter Wall artifact creature with defender.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Primal Clay comes into play, choose whether to make it a 1/6 wall, a 2/2 creature with flying, or a 3/3 creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2066</id>
  <name>Red Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Red Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Red Mana Battery: Add {R} to your mana pool, then add an additional {R} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Put one charge counter on Red Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool and remove as many charge counters as you wish. For each charge counter removed from Red Mana Battery, add {R} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2067</id>
  <name>Rod of Ruin</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Rod of Ruin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}, {T}: Rod of Ruin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2068</id>
  <name>Shapeshifter</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>7-*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>As Shapeshifter comes into play, choose a number between 0 and 7. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may choose a number between 0 and 7. &lt;br&gt;Shapeshifter's power is equal to the last chosen number and its toughness is equal to 7 minus that number.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Shapeshifter has power and toughness that add up to seven, but neither may be more than seven. Set them when Shapeshifter comes into play; you may change them during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2069</id>
  <name>Soul Net</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from play, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life when a creature is put into the graveyard from play. Use this effect only once each time a creature is put into the graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2070</id>
  <name>Sunglasses of Urza</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>You may spend white mana as though it were red mana.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may use white mana in your mana pool as either white or red mana.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2071</id>
  <name>Tawnos's Wand</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Target creature with power no greater than 2 becomes unblockable until end of turn. Other effects may later be used to increase the creature's power beyond 2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2072</id>
  <name>Tawnos's Weaponry</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Tawnos's Weaponry during your untap step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{2}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 as long as Tawnos's Weaponry remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 as long as Tawnos's Weaponry remains tapped.&lt;br&gt;You may choose not to untap Tawnos's Weaponry during your untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>When war machines became too costly, Tawnos's Weaponry replaced them.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2073</id>
  <name>Tetravus</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Tetravus comes into play with three +1/+1 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may remove any number of Tetravites created with Tetravus from the game. For each Tetravite removed this way, put a +1/+1 counter on Tetravus. Then you may remove any number of +1/+1 counters from Tetravus. For each +1/+1 counter removed this way, put into play a 1/1 Tetravite artifact creature token with flying and with "Tetravite can't be enchanted."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;When Tetravus comes into play, put three +1/+1 counters on it.&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, you may move each of these counters on or off of Tetravus, regardless of who controls them. Counters that are removed become Tetravite tokens. Treat these tokens as 1/1 artifact creatures with flying. These creatures cannot have enchantment played on them and do not share any enchantments on Tetravus.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2074</id>
  <name>The Hive</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{5}, {T}: Put a 1/1 Insect artifact creature token with flying named Wasp into play. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>5, {T}: Put a Wasp token into play. Treat this token as a 1/1 artifact creature with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2075</id>
  <name>The Rack</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>As The Rack comes into play, choose an opponent. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the chosen player's upkeep, The Rack deals X damage to that player, where X is 3 minus the number of cards in his or her hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of target opponent's upkeep, The Rack deals that player 1 damage for each card in his or her hand fewer than three.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Invented in Mishra's earlier days, the Rack was once his most feared creation.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2076</id>
  <name>Throne of Bone</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a black spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life for a successfully cast black spell. Use this effect either when the spell is cast or later in the turn but only once for each black spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2077</id>
  <name>Triskelion</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Construct</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Triskelion comes into play with three +1/+1 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;Remove a +1/+1 counter from Triskelion: Triskelion deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Triskelion comes into play, put three +1/+1 counters on it.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove one of these counters from Triskelion to have Triskelion deal 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>A brainchild of Tawnos, the Triskelion later proved both versatile and useful.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2078</id>
  <name>Urza's Avenger</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{0}: Urza's Avenger gets -1/-1 and gains your choice of banding, flying, first strike, or trample until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Urza's Avenger gets -1/-1 until end of turn and your choice of flying, banding, first strike, or trample until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Unable to settle on just one design, Urza decided to create one versatile being.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2079</id>
  <name>Wall of Spears</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike, counts as a wall</printedText>
  <flavorText>Even the most conservative generals revised their tactics after the Battle of Sarinth, during which a handful of peasant-pikemen held off a trio of rampaging Craw Wurms.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2080</id>
  <name>White Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony S. Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on White Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from White Mana Battery: Add {W} to your mana pool, then add an additional {W} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}, {T}: Put one charge counter on White Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool and remove as many charge counters as you wish. For each charge counter removed from White Mana Battery, add {W} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2081</id>
  <name>Winter Orb</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>As long as Winter Orb is untapped, players can't untap more than one land during their untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No player may untap more than one land during his or her untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2082</id>
  <name>Wooden Sphere</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a green spell, you may pay {1}. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Gain 1 life for a successfully cast green spell. Use this effect either when the spell is cast or later in the turn but only once for each green spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2083</id>
  <name>Yotian Soldier</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Vigilance</oracleText>
  <printedText>Attacking does not cause Yotian Soldier to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>After Kroog was destroyed while most of its defenders were at his side, Urza vowed that none of his allies would ever need to fear for their own defense again, even while laying siege to a city far from their homes.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2084</id>
  <name>Abomination</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Abomination blocks or becomes blocked by a green or white creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of combat, destroy all green and white creatures blocking or blocked by Abomination.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2085</id>
  <name>Animate Dead</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature card in a graveyard &lt;br&gt;When Animate Dead comes into play, if it's in play, it loses "enchant creature card in a graveyard" and gains "enchant creature put into play with Animate Dead." Return enchanted creature card to play under your control and attach Animate Dead to it. When Animate Dead leaves play, that creature's controller sacrifices it. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets -1/-0.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Take target creature from any graveyard and put it directly into play under your control with -1/-0. Treat this creature as though it were just summoned. If Animate Dead is removed, bury the creature in its owner's graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2086</id>
  <name>Ashes to Ashes</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove two target nonartifact creatures from the game. Ashes to Ashes deals 5 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Ashes to Ashes removes two target non-artifact creatures from the game and deals 5 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"All rivers eventually run to the sea. My job is to sort out who goes first."&lt;br&gt;--Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2087</id>
  <name>Bad Moon</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Black creatures get +1/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All black creatures get +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2088</id>
  <name>Black Knight</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)&lt;br&gt;Protection from white (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything white.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from white, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>Battle doesn't need a purpose; the battle is its own purpose. You don't ask why a plague spreads or a field burns. Don't ask why I fight.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2089</id>
  <name>Blight</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target land becomes tapped, destroy it at end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2090</id>
  <name>Bog Imp</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Imp</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>On guard for larger dangers, we underestimated the power and speed of the Imp's muck-crusted claws.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2091</id>
  <name>Bog Wraith</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wraith</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls a Swamp.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>'Twas in the bogs of Cannelbrae&lt;br&gt;My mate did meet an early grave&lt;br&gt;'Twas nothing left for us to save&lt;br&gt;In the peat-filled bogs of Cannelbrae.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2092</id>
  <name>Carrion Ants</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: Carrion Ants gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"War is no picnic," my father liked to say. But the Ants seemed to disagree.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2093</id>
  <name>Cosmic Horror</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you pay {3}{B}{B}{B}, sacrifice Cosmic Horror and it deals 7 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, pay {3}{B}{B}{B} or destroy Cosmic Horror. If you destroy Cosmic Horror in this way, it deals 7 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . Screams of horror rend th' affrighted skies."Alexander Pope, The Rape of the Lock</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2094</id>
  <name>Cursed Land</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted land's controller, Cursed Land deals 1 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cursed Land deals 1 damage to target land's controller during his or her upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2095</id>
  <name>Cyclopean Mummy</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward P. Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>When Cyclopean Mummy is put into a graveyard from play, remove Cyclopean Mummy from the game.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Mummy is put into the graveyard from play, remove it from the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The ritual of plucking out an eye to gain future sight is but a curse that enables the living to see their own deaths.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2096</id>
  <name>Dark Ritual</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2097</id>
  <name>Deathgrip</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}{B}: Counter target green spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{B}: Counter target green spell. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2098</id>
  <name>Deathlace</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Target spell or permanent becomes black. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the color of target spell or target permanent to black. Costs to cast, tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target remain unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2099</id>
  <name>Drain Life</name>
  <cost>{X}{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Spend only black mana on X. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Drain Life deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more life than the player's life total before Drain Life dealt damage or the creature's toughness.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Drain Life deals 1 damage to a target creature or player for each {B} you pay in addition to the casting cost. You then gain 1 life for each 1 damage dealt. You cannot gain more life than the toughness of the creature or the total life of the player Drain Life damages.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2100</id>
  <name>Drudge Skeletons</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Skeleton</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: Regenerate Drudge Skeletons. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>Bones scattered around us joined to form misshapen bodies. We struck at them repeatedly--they fell, but soon formed again, with the same mocking look on their faceless skulls.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2101</id>
  <name>El-Hajjj</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Lifelink (Whenever this creature deals damage, you gain that much life.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain 1 life for every 1 damage El-Hajjaj deals. You cannot gain more life in this way than the toughness of the creature or the total life of the player that El-Hajjaj damages.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2102</id>
  <name>Erg Raiders</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>At the end of your turn, if Erg Raiders didn't attack this turn, Erg Raiders deals 2 damage to you unless it came under your control this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If you do not attack with Erg Raiders during your turn, it deals 2 damage to you at end of turn. Erg Raiders deals no damage to you the turn it comes into play on your side.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2103</id>
  <name>Evil Presence</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land is a Swamp.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target land becomes a basic swamp.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2104</id>
  <name>Fear</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked except by black creatures and artifact creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2105</id>
  <name>Frozen Shade</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Shade</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: Frozen Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There are some qualities, some incorporate things, / That have a double life, which thus is made / A type of twin entity which springs / From matter and light, evinced in solid and shade."&lt;br&gt;--Edgar Allan Poe, "Silence"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2106</id>
  <name>Gloom</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>White spells and activated abilities of white enchantments cost {3} more to play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>White spells cost an additional {3} to cast. White enchantments with activation costs require an additional {3} to use.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2107</id>
  <name>Greed</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Pay 2 life to draw a card. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There is no calamity greater than lavish desires. . . . And there is no greater disaster than greed."&lt;br&gt;--Tao Te Ching 46</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2108</id>
  <name>Howl from Beyond</name>
  <cost>{X}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2109</id>
  <name>Hypnotic Specter</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Specter</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever Hypnotic Specter deals damage to an opponent, that player discards a card at random.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;An opponent damaged by Specter discards a card at random from his or her hand. Ignore this effect if opponent has no cards in hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . There was no trace&lt;br&gt;Of aught on that illumined face . . . ."&lt;br&gt;--Samuel Coleridge, "Phantom"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2110</id>
  <name>Junn Efreet</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Efreet</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Junun Efreet unless you pay {B}{B}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, pay {B}{B} or bury Junun Efreet.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2111</id>
  <name>Lord of the Pit</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Demon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, trample (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach. If this creature would deal enough combat damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature other than Lord of the Pit. If you can't, Lord of the Pit deals 7 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, trample&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, sacrifice a creature. If you cannot sacrifice a creature, Lord of the Pit deals 7 damage to you. You cannot sacrifice Lord of the Pit to itself.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2112</id>
  <name>Lost Soul</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit Minion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>Her hand gently beckons, &lt;br&gt;she whispers your name--&lt;br&gt;But those who go with her&lt;br&gt;are never the same.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2113</id>
  <name>Marsh Gas</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures get -2/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures get -2/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Comes right outta th' ground. If ya can smell it, it's too late."&lt;br&gt;--Keevy Bogsbury</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2114</id>
  <name>Mind Twist</name>
  <cost>{X}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player discards X cards at random.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player discards X cards at random from his or her hand. If that player does not have enough cards, his or her entire hand is discarded.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2115</id>
  <name>Murk Dwellers</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Murk Dwellers attacks and isn't blocked, it gets +2/+0 until end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When attacking and not blocked, Murk Dwellers gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>When Raganorn unsealed the catacombs, he found more than the dead and their treasures.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2116</id>
  <name>Nether Shadow</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Haste &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, if Nether Shadow is in your graveyard with three or more creature cards above it, you may put Nether Shadow into play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of your upkeep, if Shadow is in your graveyard with at least three creature cards above it, you may return it to play. Shadow can attack the turn it comes into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2117</id>
  <name>Nightmare</name>
  <cost>{5}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Nightmare Horse</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;Nightmare's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Swamps you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Nightmare has power and toughness each equal to the number of swamps its controller controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Nightmare arises from its lair in the swamps. As the poisoned land spreads, so does the Nightmare's rage and terrifying strength.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2118</id>
  <name>Paralyze</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;When Paralyze comes into play, tap enchanted creature. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {4}. If he or she does, untap the creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature does not untap during its controller's untap phase. That player may pay an additional {4} during his or her upkeep to untap it. Tap target creatures when Paralyze comes into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2119</id>
  <name>Pestilence</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of turn, if no creatures are in play, sacrifice Pestilence. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{B}: Pestilence deals 1 damage to each creature and each player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of any turn, if there are no creatures in play, bury Pestilence.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Pestilence deals 1 damage to all creatures and players.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2120</id>
  <name>Pit Scorpion</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Scorpion</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Pit Scorpion deals damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Pit Scorpion damages a player, he or she gets a poison counter. If a player has ten or more poison counters, he or she loses the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Sometimes the smallest nuisance can be the greatest pain.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2121</id>
  <name>Plague Rats</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Rat</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Plague Rats's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures named Plague Rats in play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Plague Rats has power and toughness each equal to the number of Plague Rats in play, no matter who controls them. For example, if there are two Plague Rats in play, each has power and toughness 2/2.</printedText>
  <flavorText>During the dark times, the rats seemed to grow ever stronger.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2122</id>
  <name>Rag Man</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Minion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Target opponent reveals his or her hand and discards a creature card at random. Play this ability only during your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{B}{B}, {T}: Look at target opponent's hand. If that player has any creature cards in hand, he or she discards one of them at random. Use this ability only during your turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Aw, he's just a silly, dirty little man. What's to be afraid of?"</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2123</id>
  <name>Raise Dead</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Take target creature from your graveyard and put it into your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2124</id>
  <name>Royal Assassin</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Assassin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Destroy target tapped creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Destroy target tapped creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Trained in the arts of stealth, the Royal Assassins choose their victims carefully, relying on timing and precision rather than brute force.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2125</id>
  <name>Scathe Zombies</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"They groaned, they stirred, they all uprose, &lt;br&gt;Nor spake, nor moved their eyes;&lt;br&gt;It had been strange, even in a dream,&lt;br&gt;To have seen those dead men rise."&lt;br&gt;--Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2126</id>
  <name>Scavenging Ghoul</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of turn, put a corpse counter on Scavenging Ghoul for each creature put into a graveyard from play that turn. &lt;br&gt;Remove a corpse counter from Scavenging Ghoul: Regenerate Scavenging Ghoul.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of each turn, put a corpse counter on Scavenging Ghoul for each creature put into the graveyard during that turn.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove a corpse counter from Scavenging Ghoul to regenerate it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2127</id>
  <name>Sengir Vampire</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Vampire</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature dealt damage by Sengir Vampire this turn is put into a graveyard, put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire each time a creature is put into the graveyard the same turn Sengir Vampire damaged it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2128</id>
  <name>Simulacrum</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>You gain life equal to the damage dealt to you this turn. Simulacrum deals damage to target creature you control equal to the damage dealt to you this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All damage done to you so far this turn is instead retroactively applied to a target creature you control. Further damage this turn is treated normally.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2129</id>
  <name>Sorceress Queen</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature other than Sorceress Queen becomes 0/2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature other than Sorceress Queen becomes 0/2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2130</id>
  <name>Spirit Shackle</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward P. Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, put a -0/-2 counter on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put a -0/-2 counter on target creature every time it becomes tapped. These counters remain even if Spirit Shackle is removed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2131</id>
  <name>Terror</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target nonartifact, nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target non-black, non-artifact creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2132</id>
  <name>Uncle Istvan</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Uncle Istvan by creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All damage done to Uncle Istvan by creatures is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Solitude drove the old hermit insane. Now he only keeps company with those he can catch.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2133</id>
  <name>Unholy Strength</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2134</id>
  <name>Vampire Bats</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bat</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;{B}: Vampire Bats gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Play this ability no more than twice each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{B}: +1/+0 until end of turn. You cannot spend more than {B}{B} in this way each turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"For something is amiss or out of place &lt;br&gt;When mice with wings can wear a human face."&lt;br&gt;--Theodore Roethke, "The Bat"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2135</id>
  <name>Wall of Bone</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Skeleton Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{B}: Regenerate Wall of Bone.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Wall of Bone is said to be an aspect of the Great Wall in Hel, where the bones of all sinners wait for Ragnarok, when Hela will call them forth for the final battle.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2136</id>
  <name>Warp Artifact</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted artifact's controller, Warp Artifact deals 1 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Warp Artifact deals 1 damage to target artifact's controller during his or her upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2137</id>
  <name>Weakness</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature&lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets -2/-1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets -2/-1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2138</id>
  <name>Will-o'-the-Wisp</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.) &lt;br&gt;{B}: Regenerate Will-o'-the-Wisp. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{B}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"About, about in reel and rout&lt;br&gt;The death-fires danced at night;&lt;br&gt;The water, like a witch's oils,&lt;br&gt;Burnt green, and blue and white."&lt;br&gt;--Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2139</id>
  <name>Word of Binding</name>
  <cost>{X}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap X target creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap X target creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"That was the worst experience of my days: standing there helpless as they killed my whole troop."&lt;br&gt;--Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2140</id>
  <name>Xenic Poltergeist</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Until your next upkeep, target noncreature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target non-creature artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its casting cost. Target retains all original abilities. This change lasts until your next upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2141</id>
  <name>Zombie Master</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Other Zombie creatures have swampwalk. &lt;br&gt;All other Zombies have "{B}: Regenerate this permanent."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All zombies gain swampwalk and&lt;br&gt;"{B}: Regenerate."</printedText>
  <flavorText>They say the Zombie Master controlled these foul creatures even before his own death, but now that he is one of them, nothing can make them betray him.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2142</id>
  <name>Air Elemental</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>These spirits of the air are winsome and wild and cannot be truly contained. Only marginally intelligent, they often substitute whimsy for strategy, delighting in mischief and mayhem.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2143</id>
  <name>Animate Artifact</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact &lt;br&gt;Enchanted artifact is a creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost. It's still an artifact.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target artifact becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its casting cost; target retains all its original abilities. Animate Artifact does not affect artifact creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2144</id>
  <name>Apprentice Wizard</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{U}, {T}: Add {3} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{U}, {T}: Add {3} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2145</id>
  <name>Backfire</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to you, Backfire deals that much damage to that creature's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Backfire deals 1 damage to target creature's controller for each 1 damage dealt to you by that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2146</id>
  <name>Blue Elemental Blast</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Counter target red spell; or destroy target red permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target red spell or destroy target red permanent.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2147</id>
  <name>Control Magic</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;You control enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain control of target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2148</id>
  <name>Counterspell</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2149</id>
  <name>Creature Bond</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, Creature Bond deals damage equal to that creature's toughness to the creature's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target creature is put into the graveyard, Creature Bond deals damage equal to the creature's toughness to that creature's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2150</id>
  <name>Drain Power</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player plays a mana ability of each land he or she controls, then empties his or her mana pool. Add mana to your mana pool equal to the type and amount emptied from that player's mana pool this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player must draw all mana from his or her available lands; then, all mana in target player's mana pool drains into your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2151</id>
  <name>Energy Flux</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>All artifacts have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this artifact unless you pay {2}."</oracleText>
  <printedText>During each player's upkeep, destroy all artifacts that player controls. The player may pay an additional {2} for each artifact he or she wishes to prevent Energy Flux from destroying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2152</id>
  <name>Energy Tap</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap target untapped creature you control. If you do, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap target creature you control. Add an amount of colorless mana equal to that creature's casting cost to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2153</id>
  <name>Erosion</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted land's controller, destroy that land unless that player pays {1} or 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During his or her upkeep, target land's controller pays {1} or 1 life, or target land is destroyed. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2154</id>
  <name>Feedback</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant enchantment &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted enchantment's controller, Feedback deals 1 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Feedback deals 1 damage to controller of target enchantment during that player's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2155</id>
  <name>Flight</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has flying. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2156</id>
  <name>Flood</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dennis Detwiller</artist>
  <oracleText>{U}{U}: Tap target creature without flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{U}{U}: Tap target creature without flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A dash of cool water does wonders to clear a cluttered battlefield."&lt;br&gt;--Vibekke Ragnild, Witches and War</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2157</id>
  <name>Gaseous Form</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature neither deals nor receives damage during combat.</printedText>
  <flavorText>" . . . And gives to airy nothing&lt;br&gt;A local habitation and a name."&lt;br&gt;--William Shakespeare, A Midsummer-Night's Dream</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2158</id>
  <name>Ghost Ship</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{U}{U}{U}: Regenerate Ghost Ship.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{U}{U}{U}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"That phantom prow split the storm as lightning cast its long shadow on the battlefield below."&lt;br&gt;--Mireille Gaetane, The Valeriad</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2159</id>
  <name>Giant Tortoise</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Turtle</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 as long as it's untapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Giant Tortoise gets +0/+3 while untapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2160</id>
  <name>Hurkyl's Recall</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Return all artifacts target player owns to his or her hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All artifacts in play owned by target player are returned to that player's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>This spell, like many attributed to Drafna, was actually the work of his wife and former student, Hurkyl.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2161</id>
  <name>Island Fish Jasconius</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Fish</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>8</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Island Fish Jasconius can't attack unless defending player controls an Island. &lt;br&gt;Jasconius doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {U}{U}{U}. If you do, untap Jasconius. &lt;br&gt;When you control no Islands, sacrifice Jasconius.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;Cannot attack if defending player controls no islands. If at any time you control no islands, bury Island Fish Jasconius.&lt;br&gt;{U}{U}{U}: Untap Island Fish. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2162</id>
  <name>Jump</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2163</id>
  <name>Leviathan</name>
  <cost>{5}{U}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Leviathan</type>
  <power>10</power>
  <toughness>10</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Leviathan comes into play tapped and doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may sacrifice two Islands. If you do, untap Leviathan. &lt;br&gt;Leviathan can't attack unless you sacrifice two Islands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Comes into play tapped and does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, you may sacrifice two islands to untap Leviathan.&lt;br&gt;Leviathan cannot attack unless you sacrifice two islands during your attack.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>9</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2164</id>
  <name>Lifetap</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a Forest an opponent controls becomes tapped, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain 1 life each time a forest controlled by target opponent becomes tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2165</id>
  <name>Lord of Atlantis</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Merfolk</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Other Merfolk creatures get +1/+1 and have islandwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All Merfolk gain islandwalk and get +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText>A master of tactics, the Lord of Atlantis makes his people bold in battle merely by arriving to lead them.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2166</id>
  <name>Magical Hack</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one basic land type with another. (For example, you may change "swampwalk" to "plainswalk.") (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the text of target spell or target permanent by replacing all occurrences of one basic land type with another. For example, you may change "swampwalk" to "plainswalk."</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2167</id>
  <name>Mahamoti Djinn</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Djinn</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>Of royal blood among the spirits of the air, the Mahamoti Djinn rides on the wings of the winds. As dangerous in the gambling hall as he is in battle, he is a master of trickery and misdirection.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2168</id>
  <name>Mana Short</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap all lands target player controls and empty his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Mana Short empties target player's mana pool and taps that player's lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2169</id>
  <name>Merfolk of the Pearl Trident</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Merfolk</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Most human scholars believe that Merfolk are the survivors of sunken Atlantis, humans adapted to the water. Merfolk, however, believe that humans sprang forth from Merfolk who adapted themselves in order to explore their last frontier.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2170</id>
  <name>Mind Bomb</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Each player may discard up to three cards. Mind Bomb deals damage to each player equal to 3 minus the number of cards he or she discarded this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Mind Bomb deals 3 damage to each player. All players may discard up to three cards of their choice from their hands. Each card a player discards in this manner prevents 1 damage to that player from Mind Bomb.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2171</id>
  <name>Phantasmal Forces</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Phantasmal Forces unless you pay {U}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, pay {U} or destroy Phantasmal Forces.</printedText>
  <flavorText>These beings embody the essence of true heroes long dead. Summoned from the dreamrealms, they rise to meet their enemies.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2172</id>
  <name>Phantasmal Terrain</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;As Phantasmal Terrain comes into play, choose a basic land type. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land is the chosen type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target land becomes any basic land type of your choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2173</id>
  <name>Phantom Monster</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>"While, like a ghastly rapid river,&lt;br&gt;Through the pale door,&lt;br&gt;A hideous throng rush out forever,&lt;br&gt;And laugh--but smile no more."&lt;br&gt;--Edgar Allan Poe, "The Haunted Palace"</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2174</id>
  <name>Pirate Ship</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Pirate</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Pirate Ship can't attack unless defending player controls an Island. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Pirate Ship deals 1 damage to target creature or player. &lt;br&gt;When you control no Islands, sacrifice Pirate Ship.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot attack if defending player controls no islands. If at any time you control no islands, bury Pirate Ship.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Pirate Ship deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2175</id>
  <name>Power Leak</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant enchantment &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted enchantment's controller, that player may pay up to {2}. For each one mana less than {2} he or she pays this way, Power Leak deals 1 damage to him or her.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During the upkeep of target enchantment's controller, Power Leak deals 2 damage to him or her. That player may pay {1} for each damage he or she wishes to prevent from Power Leak.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2176</id>
  <name>Power Sink</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter a target spell if its caster does not pay {X}. Target spell's caster must draw and pay all available mana from lands and mana pool until {X} is paid; he or she may also pay mana from other sources if desired.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2177</id>
  <name>Prodigal Sorcerer</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Prodigal Sorcerer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Prodigal Sorcerer deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Occasionally a member of the Institute of Arcane Study acquires a taste for worldly pleasures. Seldom do they have trouble finding employment.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2178</id>
  <name>Psionic Entity</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Psionic Entity deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to itself.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Psionic Entity deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to itself.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Creatures of the Aether are notorious for neglecting their own well-being.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2179</id>
  <name>Psychic Venom</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, Psychic Venom deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever target land becomes tapped, Psychic Venom deals 2 damage to that land's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2180</id>
  <name>Relic Bind</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact an opponent controls &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted artifact becomes tapped, choose one - Relic Bind deals 1 damage to target player; or target player gains 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When target artifact opponent controls becomes tapped, you may give 1 life or have Relic Bind deal 1 damage to target player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2181</id>
  <name>Sea Serpent</name>
  <cost>{5}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Serpent</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Sea Serpent can't attack unless defending player controls an Island. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;When you control no Islands, sacrifice Sea Serpent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot attack if defending player controls no islands. If at any time you control no islands, bury Sea Serpent.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Legend has it that Serpents used to be bigger, but how could that be?</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2182</id>
  <name>Segovian Leviathan</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Leviathan</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Islandwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Islandwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Leviathan, too Can you catch him with a fish-hook or run a line round his tongue?"&lt;br&gt;--Job 40:25</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2183</id>
  <name>Sindbad</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Draw a card and reveal it. If it isn't a land card, discard it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Draw a card. If it is not a land, discard it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2184</id>
  <name>Siren's Call</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Siren's Call only during an opponent's turn and only before attackers are declared. &lt;br&gt;Creatures the active player controls attack this turn if able. &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, destroy all non-Wall creatures that player controls that didn't attack this turn. Ignore this effect for each creature the player didn't control continuously since the beginning of the turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All of target opponent's creatures that can attack must do so. At end of turn, destroy any non-wall creatures that did not attack. Play only during opponent's turn, before opponent's attack. Siren's Call does not affect creatures brought under opponent's control this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2185</id>
  <name>Sleight of Mind</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (For example, you may change "target black spell" to "target blue spell.") (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the text of target spell or target permanent by replacing all occurrences of one color word with another. For example, you may change "Counters black spells" to "Counters blue spells." Sleight of Mind cannot change mana symbols.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2186</id>
  <name>Spell Blast</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell with converted mana cost X.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell. X is the casting cost of the target spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2187</id>
  <name>Stasis</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Fay Jones</artist>
  <oracleText>Players skip their untap steps. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Stasis unless you pay {U}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Players do not get an untap phase. During your upkeep, pay {U} or destroy Stasis.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2188</id>
  <name>Steal Artifact</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact &lt;br&gt;You control enchanted artifact.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain control of target artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2189</id>
  <name>Sunken City</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Sunken City unless you pay {U}{U}. &lt;br&gt;Blue creatures get +1/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All blue creatures get +1/+1. During your upkeep, pay {U}{U} or destroy Sunken City.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2190</id>
  <name>Thoughtlace</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target spell or permanent becomes blue. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the color of target spell or target permanent to blue. Costs to cast, tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target remain unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2191</id>
  <name>Time Elemental</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>When Time Elemental attacks or blocks, at end of combat, sacrifice it and it deals 5 damage to you. &lt;br&gt;{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent that isn't enchanted to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent to owner's hand. You cannot use this ability on permanents with enchantment cards played on them. If Time Elemental blocks or attacks, destroy it at end of combat. In this case, Time Elemental deals 5 damage to its controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2192</id>
  <name>Twiddle</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap or untap target land, artifact, or creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2193</id>
  <name>Unstable Mutation</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +3/+3. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -1/-1 counter on that creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +3/+3. During each of its controller's upkeeps, put a -1/-1 counter on the creature. These counters remain even if Unstable Mutation is removed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2194</id>
  <name>Unsummon</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Return target creature to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Return target creature to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2195</id>
  <name>Volcanic Eruption</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy X target Mountains. Volcanic Eruption deals damage to each creature and each player equal to the number of Mountains destroyed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy X target mountains. Volcanic Eruption deals 1 damage to each creature and player for each mountain put into the graveyard in this way.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2196</id>
  <name>Wall of Air</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This --'standing windstorm' can hold us off indefinitely? Ridiculous" Saying nothing, she put a pinch of salt on the table. With a bang she clapped her hands, and the salt disappeared, blown away.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2197</id>
  <name>Wall of Water</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{U}: Wall of Water gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{U}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>A deafening roar arose as the fury of an enormous vertical river supplanted our serenity. Eddies turned into whirling geysers, leveling everything in their path.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2198</id>
  <name>Water Elemental</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Unpredictable as the sea itself, Water Elementals shift without warning from tranquility to tempest. Capricious and fickle, they flow restlessly from one shape to another, expressing their moods with their physical forms.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2199</id>
  <name>Zephyr Falcon</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, vigilance</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Attacking does not cause Zephyr Falcon to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Although greatly prized among falconers, the Zephyr Falcon is capricious and not easily tamed.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2200</id>
  <name>Aspect of Wolf</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +X/+Y, where X is equal to half the number of Forests you control, rounded down, and Y is equal to half the number of Forests you control, rounded up.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Increase target creature's power and toughness by half the number of forests you control, rounding down for power and up for toughness.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2201</id>
  <name>Birds of Paradise</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2202</id>
  <name>Carnivorous Plant</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Plant Wall</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"It had a mouth like that of a great beast, and gnashed its teeth as it strained to reach us. I am thankful it possessed no means of locomotion."&lt;br&gt;--Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2203</id>
  <name>Channel</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Until end of turn, any time you could play a mana ability you may pay 1 life. If you do, add {1} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Until end of turn, you may add colorless mana to your mana pool at a cost of 1 life per one mana. Play these additions as interrupts. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2204</id>
  <name>Cockatrice</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Cockatrice</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Whenever Cockatrice blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;At the end of combat, destroy all non-wall creatures blocking or blocked by Cockatrice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2205</id>
  <name>Craw Wurm</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wurm</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The most terrifying thing about the Craw Wurm is probably the horrible crashing sound it makes as it speeds through the forest. This noise is so loud it echoes through the trees and seems to come from all directions at once.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2206</id>
  <name>Crumble</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact. It can't be regenerated. That artifact's controller gains life equal to its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target artifact. Artifact's controller gains life equal to the artifact's casting cost.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The spirits of Argoth grant new life to those who repent the folly of enslaving their labors to devices.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2207</id>
  <name>Desert Twister</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target permanent.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2208</id>
  <name>Durkwood Boars</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Boar</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Kimble</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"And the unclean spirits went out, and entered the swine: and the herd ran violently . . . ."&lt;br&gt;--Mark 5:13</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2209</id>
  <name>Elven Riders</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Elven Riders can't be blocked except by Walls and/or creatures with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be blocked except by walls and by creatures with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sometimes it is better to be swift of foot than strong of swordarm."&lt;br&gt;--Elven proverb</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2210</id>
  <name>Elvish Archers</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Archer</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>I tell you, there was so many arrows flying about you couldn't hardly see the sun. So I says to young Angus, "Well, at least now we're fighting in the shade"</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2211</id>
  <name>Fog</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No creatures deal damage in combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2212</id>
  <name>Force of Nature</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>8</power>
  <toughness>8</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample (If this creature would deal enough combat damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it deal the rest of its damage to defending player.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, Force of Nature deals 8 damage to you unless you pay {G}{G}{G}{G}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, pay {G}{G}{G}{G} or Force of Nature deals 8 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2213</id>
  <name>Fungusaur</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Fungus Lizard</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Fungusaur is dealt damage, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of any turn in which Fungusaur receives damage but does not leave play, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Rather than sheltering her young, the female Fungusaur often injures her own offspring, thereby ensuring their rapid growth.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2214</id>
  <name>Gaea's Liege</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Avatar</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>As long as Gaea's Liege isn't attacking, its power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control. As long as Gaea's Liege is attacking, its power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests defending player controls. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target land becomes a Forest until Gaea's Liege leaves play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gaea's Liege has power and toughness each equal to the number of forests you control; when Gaea's Liege attacks, these are instead equal to the number of forests defending player controls.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Target land becomes a basic forest until Gaea's Liege leaves play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2215</id>
  <name>Giant Growth</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2216</id>
  <name>Giant Spider</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spider</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Can block creatures with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>While it possesses potent venom, the Giant Spider often chooses not to paralyze its victims. Perhaps the creature enjoys the gentle rocking motion caused by its captives' struggles to escape its web.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2217</id>
  <name>Grizzly Bears</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bear</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Don't try to outrun one of Dominia's Grizzlies; it'll catch you, knock you down, and eat you. Of course, you could run up a tree. In that case you'll get a nice view before it knocks the tree down and eats you.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2218</id>
  <name>Hurricane</name>
  <cost>{X}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Hurricane deals X damage to each player and each creature with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2219</id>
  <name>Instill Energy</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has haste. &lt;br&gt;{0}: Untap enchanted creature. Play this ability only during your turn and only once each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature can attack the turn it comes into play on your side.&lt;br&gt;{0}: During your turn, untap target creature Instill Energy enchants. Use this ability only once each turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2220</id>
  <name>Ironroot Treefolk</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Treefolk</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The mating habits of Treefolk, particularly the stalwart Ironroot Treefolk, are truly absurd. Molasses comes to mind. It's amazing the species can survive at all given such protracted periods of mate selection, conjugation, and gestation.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2221</id>
  <name>Killer Bees</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}: Killer Bees gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>The communal mind produces a savage strategy, yet no one could predict that this vicious crossbreed would unravel the secret of steel.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2222</id>
  <name>Land Leeches</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Leech</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The standard cure for leeches requires the application of burning embers. Alternative methods must be devised should an ember of sufficient size prove more harmful than the leech."&lt;br&gt;--Vervamon the Elder</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2223</id>
  <name>Ley Druid</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Untap target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Untap target land. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>After years of training, the Druid becomes one with nature, drawing power form the land and returning it when needed.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2224</id>
  <name>Lifeforce</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{G}{G}: Counter target black spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}{G}: Counter target black spell. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2225</id>
  <name>Lifelace</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Target spell or permanent becomes green. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the color of target spell or target permanent to green. Costs to cast, tap, maintain or use a special ability of target remain unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2226</id>
  <name>Living Artifact</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact &lt;br&gt;Whenever you're dealt damage, put that many vitality counters on Living Artifact. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may remove a vitality counter from Living Artifact. If you do, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put a vitality counter on Living Artifact for each damage dealt to you.&lt;br&gt;{0}: During your upkeep, remove a vitality counter to gain 1 life. Remove only one vitality counter during each of your upkeeps.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2227</id>
  <name>Living Lands</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>All Forests are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All forests become 1/1 creatures. The forests still count as lands but cannot be tapped for mana the turn they come into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2228</id>
  <name>Llanowar Elves</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Hardened by their life in the haunted Llanowar Forest, these fierce beings are outcasts among elvenkind.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2229</id>
  <name>Lure</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures able to block target creature must do so. Lure does not prevent a creature from blocking more than one creature if blocker has that ability. If blocker is forced to block more creatures than it is allowed to, defender chooses which of these creatures to block, but must block as many creatures as allowed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2230</id>
  <name>Marsh Viper</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Snake</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Marsh Viper deals damage to an opponent, that player gets two poison counters. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Marsh Viper damages a player, he or she gets two poison counters. If a player has ten or more poison counters, he or she loses the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"All we had left were their black and bloated bodies."&lt;br&gt;--Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2231</id>
  <name>Nafs Asp</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Snake</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Nafs Asp deals damage to a player, that player loses 1 life at the beginning of his or her next draw step unless he or she pays {1} before that draw step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Nafs Asp damages a player, it also deals 1 damage to that player during his or her next draw phase. Before then, the player may pay {1} to prevent this damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2232</id>
  <name>Pradesh Gypsies</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Nomad</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2233</id>
  <name>Radjan Spirit</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2234</id>
  <name>Rebirth</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Rebirth from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Each player may put the top card of his or her library into the ante. If a player does, his or her life total becomes 20.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each player may be healed to 20 life. Any player choosing to be healed antes an additional card from the top of his or her library. Remove Rebirth from your deck before playing if not playing for ante.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2235</id>
  <name>Regeneration</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}: Regenerate target creature Regeneration enchants.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2236</id>
  <name>Sandstorm</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Sandstorm deals 1 damage to each attacking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sandstorm deals 1 damage to all attacking creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Even the landscape turned against Sarsour, first rising up and pelting him, then rearranging itself so he could no longer find his way.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2237</id>
  <name>Scryb Sprites</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Faerie</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>The only sound was the gentle clicking of the Faeries' wings. Then those intruders who were still standing turned and fled. One thing was certain: they didn't think the Scryb were very funny anymore.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2238</id>
  <name>Shanodin Dryads</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dryad</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Forestwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Forestwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>Moving without sound, swift figures pass through branches and undergrowth completely unhindered. One with the trees around them, the Dryads of Shanodin Forest are seen only when they wish to be.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2239</id>
  <name>Stream of Life</name>
  <cost>{X}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player gains X life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player gains X life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2240</id>
  <name>Sylvan Library</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your draw step, you may draw two cards. If you do, choose two cards in your hand drawn this turn. For each of those cards, pay 4 life or put the card on top of your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may draw two extra cards during your draw phase. If you do so, put two of the cards drawn this turn back on top of your library (in any order) or pay 4 life per card not replaced. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2241</id>
  <name>Thicket Basilisk</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Basilisk</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Thicket Basilisk blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of combat, destroy all non-wall creatures blocking or blocked by Basilisk.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Moss-covered statues littered the area, a macabre monument to the Basilisk's power.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2242</id>
  <name>Timber Wolves</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolf</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding</printedText>
  <flavorText>Though many think of Wolves as solitary predators, they are actually extremely social animals. During a hunt they often call to each other, which can be quite unsettling for their prey.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2243</id>
  <name>Titania's Song</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kersten Kaman</artist>
  <oracleText>Each noncreature artifact loses its abilities and becomes an artifact creature with power and toughness each equal to its converted mana cost. If Titania's Song leaves play, this effect continues until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All non-creature artifacts lose all their usual abilities and become artifact creatures with toughness and power each equal to their casting costs. If Titania's Song leaves play, artifacts return to normal just before the untap phase of the next turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2244</id>
  <name>Tranquility</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all enchantments.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all enchantments.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2245</id>
  <name>Tsunami</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all Islands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all islands.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2246</id>
  <name>Untamed Wilds</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card into play. Then shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Search your library for any one basic land and put it directly into play. This does not count towards your one land per turn limit. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2247</id>
  <name>Venom</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy the other creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of combat, destroy all non-wall creatures blocking or blocked by target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I told him it was just a flesh wound, but the next time I looked at him, poor Tadhg was dead and gone."&lt;br&gt;--Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2248</id>
  <name>Verduran Enchantress</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Druid</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kev Brockschmidt</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever you play an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Draw a card when you successfully cast an enchantment. Use this effect only once for each enchantment cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Some say magic was first practiced by women, who have always felt strong ties to the land.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2249</id>
  <name>Wall of Brambles</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate Wall of Brambles.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What else, when chaos&lt;br&gt;draws all forces inward&lt;br&gt;to shape a single leaf."&lt;br&gt;--Conrad Aiken</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2250</id>
  <name>Wall of Ice</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"And through the drifts the snowy cliffs&lt;br&gt;Did send a dismal sheen:&lt;br&gt;Nor shapes of men nor beasts we ken--&lt;br&gt;The ice was all between."&lt;br&gt;--Samuel Coleridge, "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2251</id>
  <name>Wall of Wood</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Everybody knows that to ward off trouble, you knock on wood. But usually it's better to make a wall out of the wood and let trouble do the knocking.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2252</id>
  <name>Wanderlust</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Wanderlust deals 1 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Wanderlust deals 1 damage to target creature's controller during that player's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2253</id>
  <name>War Mammoth</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elephant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample</printedText>
  <flavorText>I didn't think Mammoths could ever hold a candle to a well-trained battle horse. Then one day I turned my back on a drunken soldier. His blow never landed; Mi'cha flung the brute over ten meters.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2254</id>
  <name>Web</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and has reach. (It can block creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +0/+2 and can block creatures with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2255</id>
  <name>Whirling Dervish</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Monk</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from black &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, if Whirling Dervish dealt damage to an opponent this turn, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black&lt;br&gt;Put a +1/+1 counter on Whirling Dervish at the end of each turn in which it damages opponent.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2256</id>
  <name>Wild Growth</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Wild Growth adds {G} to your mana pool each time target land is tapped for mana.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2257</id>
  <name>Winter Blast</name>
  <cost>{X}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap X target creatures. Winter Blast deals 2 damage to each of those creatures with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap X target creatures. Winter Blast deals 2 damage to each of these target creatures with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Blow, winds, and crack your cheeks rage blow"&lt;br&gt;--William Shakespeare, King Lear</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2258</id>
  <name>Ali Baba</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Rogue</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}: Tap target Wall.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: Tap target wall.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"When he reached the entrance of the cavern, he pronounced the words, --'Open, Sesame'"&lt;br&gt;--The Arabian Nights, Junior Classics trans.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2259</id>
  <name>Ball Lightning</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample, haste &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, sacrifice Ball Lightning.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Ball Lightning can attack the turn it comes into play. At the end of any turn, bury Ball Lightning.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2260</id>
  <name>Bird Maiden</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Bird</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>Four things that never meet do here unite&lt;br&gt;To shed my blood and to ravage my heart,&lt;br&gt;A radiant brow and tresses that beguile&lt;br&gt;And rosy cheeks and a glittering smile."&lt;br&gt;--The Arabian Nights, trans. Haddawy</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2261</id>
  <name>Blood Lust</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>If target creature has toughness 5 or greater, it gets +4/-4 until end of turn. Otherwise, it gets +4/-X until end of turn, where X is its toughness minus 1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +4/-4 until end of turn. If this reduces creature's toughness to less than 1, creature's toughness becomes 1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2262</id>
  <name>Brothers of Fire</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Shaman</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{R}{R}: Brothers of Fire deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>1{R}{R}: Brothers of Fire deals 1 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Fire is never a gentle master.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2263</id>
  <name>Burrowing</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has mountainwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains mountainwalk.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2264</id>
  <name>Cave People</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Cave People attacks, it gets +1/-2 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{1}{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature gains mountainwalk until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When attacking, Cave People gets +1/-2 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;1{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature gains mountainwalk until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2265</id>
  <name>Chaoslace</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Target spell or permanent becomes red. (Its mana symbols remain unchanged.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the color of target spell or target permanent to red. Costs to cast, tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target remain unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2266</id>
  <name>Crimson Manticore</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Manticore</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{R}, {T}: Crimson Manticore deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{R}, {T}: Manticore deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Noted neither for their good looks nor their charm, Manticores can be fearsome allies.  As dinner companions, however, they are best left alone.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2267</id>
  <name>Detonate</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact with converted mana cost X. It can't be regenerated. Detonate deals X damage to that artifact's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target artifact. Detonate deals X damage to the artifact's controller, where X is the casting cost of the artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2268</id>
  <name>Disintegrate</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Disintegrate deals X damage to target creature or player. That creature can't be regenerated this turn. If the creature would be put into a graveyard this turn, remove it from the game instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Disintegrate deals X damage to target creature or player. The target cannot regenerate until end of turn. If the target receives lethal damage this turn, remove it from the game entirely.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2269</id>
  <name>Dragon Whelp</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dragon</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{R}: Dragon Whelp gets +1/+0 until end of turn. At end of turn, if this ability has been played four or more times this turn, sacrifice Dragon Whelp.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{R}: +1/+0 until end of turn. If you spend more than {R}{R}{R} in this way during one turn, destroy Dragon Whelp at end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"O to be a dragon . . . of silkworm size or immense . . ."Marianne Moore, "O to Be a Dragon"</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2270</id>
  <name>Dwarven Warriors</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dwarf Warrior</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature with power no greater than 2 becomes unblockable until end of turn. Other effects may later be used to increase the creature's power beyond 2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2271</id>
  <name>Earth Elemental</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Earth Elementals have the eternal strength of stone and the endurance of mountains. Primordially connected to the land they inhabit, they take a long-term view of things, scorning the impetuous haste of short-lived mortal creatures.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2272</id>
  <name>Earthquake</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Earthquake deals X damage to each creature without flying and each player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Earthquake deals X damage to each player and each creature without flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2273</id>
  <name>Eternal Warrior</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has vigilance.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Attacking does not cause target creature to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Warriors of the Tsunami-nito School spend years in training to master the way of effortless effort.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2274</id>
  <name>Fire Elemental</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Fire Elementals are ruthless infernos, annihilating and consuming their foes in a frenzied holocaust. Crackling and blazing, they sear swift, terrible paths, leaving the land charred and scorched in their wake.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2275</id>
  <name>Fireball</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Fireball deals X damage divided evenly, rounded down, among any number of target creatures and/or players. &lt;br&gt;As an additional cost to play Fireball, pay {1} for each target beyond the first.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Fireball deals X damage, divided evenly (round down) among any number of target creatures and/or players. Pay an additional {1} for each target beyond the first.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2276</id>
  <name>Firebreathing</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: Target creature Firebreathing enchants gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"And topples round the dreary west &lt;br&gt;A looming bastion fringed with fire."&lt;br&gt;--Alfred, Lord Tennyson, "In Memoriam"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2277</id>
  <name>Fissure</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target creature or land. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target land or creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Must not all things at the last be swallowed up in death?"&lt;br&gt;--Plato</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2278</id>
  <name>Flashfires</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all Plains.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all plains.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2279</id>
  <name>Giant Strength</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"O it is excellent&lt;br&gt;To have a giant's strength, but it is tyrannous&lt;br&gt;To use it like a giant."&lt;br&gt;--William Shakespeare, Measure for Measure</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2280</id>
  <name>Goblin Balloon Brigade</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin Warrior</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}: Goblin Balloon Brigade gains flying until end of turn. (It can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: Flying until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"From up here we can drop rocks and arrows and more rocks"&lt;br&gt;"Uh, yeah boss, but how do we get down?"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2281</id>
  <name>Goblin King</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Other Goblin creatures get +1/+1 and have mountainwalk. (They're unblockable as long as defending player controls a Mountain.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>All Goblins gain mountainwalk and get +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText>To become king of the Goblins, one must assassinate the previous king. Thus, only the most foolish seek positions of leadership.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2282</id>
  <name>Goblin Rock Sled</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dennis Detwiller</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Goblin Rock Sled doesn't untap during your untap step if it attacked during your last turn. &lt;br&gt;Goblin Rock Sled can't attack unless defending player controls a Mountain.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Cannot attack if defending player controls no mountains. Rock Sled does not untap during your untap phase if it attacked during your last turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2283</id>
  <name>Gray Ogre</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ogre</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The Ogre philosopher Gnerdel believed the purpose of life was to live as high on the food chain as possible. She refused to eat vegetarians, preferring to live entirely on creatures that preyed on sentient beings.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2284</id>
  <name>Hill Giant</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Fortunately, Hill Giants have large blind spots in which a human can easily hide. Unfortunately, these blind spots are beneath the bottoms of their feet.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2285</id>
  <name>Hurloon Minotaur</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Minotaur</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The Minotaurs of the Hurloon Mountains are known for their love of battle. They are also known for their hymns to the dead, sung for friend and foe alike. These hymns can last for days, filling the mountain valleys with their low, haunting sounds.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2286</id>
  <name>Hurr Jackal</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Hound</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature cannot regenerate this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2287</id>
  <name>Immolation</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/-2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/-2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2288</id>
  <name>Inferno</name>
  <cost>{5}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Inferno deals 6 damage to each creature and each player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Inferno deals 6 damage to all players and all creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Any scrap of compassion that still existed in my soul was permanently snuffed out when they cast me out into the flames."&lt;br&gt;--Mairsil, called the Pretender</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2289</id>
  <name>Ironclaw Orcs</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Ironclaw Orcs can't block creatures with power 2 or greater.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be assigned to block any creature with power greater than 1.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Generations of genetic weeding have given rise to the deviously cowardly Ironclaw clan. To say that Orcs in general are vicious, depraved, and ignoble does not do justice to the Ironclaw.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2290</id>
  <name>Keldon Warlord</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Barbarian</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kev Brockschmidt</artist>
  <oracleText>Keldon Warlord's power and toughness are each equal to the number of non-Wall creatures you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Keldon Warlord has power and toughness each equal to the number of non-wall creatures you control, including Warlord. For example, if you control two other non-wall creatures, Warlord is 3/3. If one of those creatures leaves play, Warlord immediately becomes 2/2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2291</id>
  <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Lightning Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Lightning Bolt deals 3 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2292</id>
  <name>Magnetic Mountain</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Blue creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps. &lt;br&gt;Blue creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {4}. If you do, untap this creature."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Blue creatures do not untap during their controllers' untap phase. During his or her upkeep, a player may pay an additional {4} to untap a blue creature he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2293</id>
  <name>Mana Clash</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>You and target opponent each flip a coin. Mana Clash deals 1 damage to each player whose coin comes up tails. Repeat this process until both players' coins come up heads on the same flip.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You and target opponent each flip a coin. Mana Clash deals 1 damage to any player whose coin comes up tails. Repeat this process until both players' coins come up heads at the same time.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2294</id>
  <name>Mana Flare</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, that player adds one mana of that type to his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, it produces one additional mana of the same type.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2295</id>
  <name>Manabarbs</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player taps a land for mana, Manabarbs deals 1 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each time any land is tapped for mana, Manabarbs deals 1 damage to that land's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2296</id>
  <name>Mons's Goblin Raiders</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The intricate dynamics of Rundvelt Goblin affairs are often confused with anarchy. The chaos, however, is the chaos of a thundercloud, and direction will sporadically and violently appear. Pashalik Mons and his Raiders are the thunderhead that leads in the storm.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2297</id>
  <name>Orcish Artillery</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc Warrior</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Orcish Artillery deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Orcish Artillery deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>In a rare display of ingenuity, the Orcs invented an incredibly destructive weapon. Most Orcish artillerists are those who dared criticize its effectiveness.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2298</id>
  <name>Orcish Oriflamme</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Attacking creatures you control get +1/+0.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All attacking creatures you control get +1/+0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2299</id>
  <name>Power Surge</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Power Surge deals X damage to that player, where X is the number of untapped lands he or she controlled at the beginning of this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During each player's upkeep, Power Surge deals that player 1 damage for each land he or she controls that was untapped at the beginning of the turn, before the untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2300</id>
  <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided any way you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Hi ni ya Behold the man of flint, that's me&lt;br&gt;Four lightnings zigzag from me, strike and return."&lt;br&gt;--Navajo war chant</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2301</id>
  <name>Red Elemental Blast</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Counter target blue spell; or destroy target blue permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target blue spell or destroy target blue permanent.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2302</id>
  <name>Shatter</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2303</id>
  <name>Shivan Dragon</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dragon</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{R}: Shivan Dragon gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{R}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>While it's true most Dragons are cruel, the Shivan Dragon seems to take particular glee in the misery of others, often tormenting its victims much like a cat plays with a mouse before delivering the final blow.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2304</id>
  <name>Sisters of the Flame</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Shaman</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>We are many wicks sharing a common tallow; we feed the skies with the ashes of our prey.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2305</id>
  <name>Smoke</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Players can't untap more than one creature during their untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No player may untap more than one creature during his or her untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2306</id>
  <name>Stone Giant</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature you control with toughness less than Stone Giant's power gains flying until end of turn. Destroy that creature at the beginning of the next end step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature you control, which must have toughness less than Stone Giant's power, gains flying until end of turn. Destroy that creature at end of turn. Other effects may later be used to increase the creature's toughness beyond Stone Giant's power.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2307</id>
  <name>Stone Rain</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target land.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2308</id>
  <name>Tempest Efreet</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Efreet</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Tempest Efreet from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt;{T}, Sacrifice Tempest Efreet: Target opponent may pay 10 life. If that player doesn't, he or she reveals a card at random from his or her hand. Exchange ownership of the revealed card and Tempest Efreet. Put the revealed card into your hand and Tempest Efreet from anywhere into that player's graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Choose a card at random from target opponent's hand and put it in yours. Bury Tempest Efreet in opponent's graveyard. The change in ownership is permanent. Play this ability as an interrupt. Before you choose the card to be switched, the opponent may prevent effect by paying 10 life or conceding game; if this is done, bury Tempest Efreet. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life. Remove Tempest Efreet from your deck before playing if not playing for ante.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2309</id>
  <name>The Brute</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+0. &lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Regenerate enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +1/+0.&lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Regenerate target creature The Brute enchants.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Union may be strength, but it is mere blind brute strength unless wisely directed."&lt;br&gt;--Samuel Butler</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2310</id>
  <name>Tunnel</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target Wall. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target wall.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2311</id>
  <name>Uthden Troll</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Troll</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}: Regenerate Uthden Troll.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Oi oi oi, me gotta hurt in 'ere,&lt;br&gt;Oi oi oi, me smell a ting is near,&lt;br&gt;Gonna bosh 'n gonna nosh&lt;br&gt;'n da hurt'll disappear."&lt;br&gt;--Troll chant</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2312</id>
  <name>Wall of Dust</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever Wall of Dust blocks a creature, that creature can't attack during its controller's next turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No creature blocked by Wall of Dust may attack during its controller's next turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>An ever-moving swarm of dust engulfs and disorients anything that comes near.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2313</id>
  <name>Wall of Fire</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{R}: Wall of Fire gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>Conjured from the bowels of hell, the fiery wall forms an impassable barrier, searing the soul of any creature attempting to pass through its terrible bursts of flame.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2314</id>
  <name>Wall of Stone</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>8</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The Earth herself lends her strength to these walls of living stone, which possess the stability of ancient mountains. These mighty bulwarks thwart ground-based troops, providing welcome relief for weary warriors who defend the land.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2315</id>
  <name>Winds of Change</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players shuffle their hands into their libraries and then draw the same number of cards they originally held.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"'Tis the set of sails, and not the gales, Which tells us the way to go."&lt;br&gt;--Ella Wheeler Wilcox</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2316</id>
  <name>Alabaster Potion</name>
  <cost>{X}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Target player gains X life; or prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Give target player X life, or prevent X damage to any creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Healing is a matter of time, but it is sometimes also a matter of opportunity."&lt;br&gt;--D'Avenant proverb</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2317</id>
  <name>Amrou Kithkin</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kithkin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Amrou Kithkin can't be blocked by creatures with power 3 or greater.</oracleText>
  <printedText>No creature with power greater than 2 may be assigned to block Kithkin.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Quick and agile, Amrou Kithkin can usually escape from even the most fearsome opponents.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2318</id>
  <name>Angry Mob</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>2+*</power>
  <toughness>2+*</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;As long as it's your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each equal to 2 plus the number of Swamps your opponents control. As long as it's not your turn, Angry Mob's power and toughness are each 2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;During your turn, Angry Mob has power and toughness each equal to 2 plus the total number of swamps opponents control. During other turns, Angry Mob has power and toughness 2/2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2319</id>
  <name>Animate Wall</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant Wall &lt;br&gt;Enchanted Wall can attack as though it didn't have defender.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target wall can now attack.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2320</id>
  <name>Armageddon</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2321</id>
  <name>Balance</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Except the player who controls the fewest lands, each player sacrifices lands until all players control the same number of lands as the player who controls the fewest. Players discard cards the same way, then sacrifice creatures the same way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each player sacrifices enough lands to equalize the number of lands all players control. The player who controls the fewest lands cannot sacrifice any in this way. All players then equalize cards in hand and then creatures in play in the same way.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2322</id>
  <name>Benalish Hero</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding</printedText>
  <flavorText>Benalia has a complex caste system that changes with the lunar year. No matter what the season, the only caste that cannot be attained by either heredity or money is that of the Hero.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2323</id>
  <name>Black Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has protection from black. This effect doesn't remove Black Ward.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains protection from black. The protection granted by Black Ward does not destroy Black Ward.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2324</id>
  <name>Blessing</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;{W}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}: Target creature Blessing enchants gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2325</id>
  <name>Blue Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has protection from blue. This effect doesn't remove Blue Ward.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains protection from blue. The protection granted by Blue Ward does not destroy Blue Ward.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2326</id>
  <name>Brainwash</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't attack unless its controller pays {3}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot attack unless its controller pays an additional {3}.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"They're not your friends; they despise you. I'm the only one you can count on. Trust me."</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2327</id>
  <name>Castle</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Untapped creatures you control get +0/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Untapped creatures you control get +0/+2 when not attacking.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2328</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Artifacts</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}: The next time an artifact source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Prevent all damage against you from one artifact source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {2} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2329</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one black source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2330</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one blue source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2331</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one green source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2332</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one red source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2333</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one white source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2334</id>
  <name>Conversion</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Conversion unless you pay {W}{W}. &lt;br&gt;All Mountains are Plains.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All mountains become basic plains. During your upkeep, pay {W}{W} or destroy Conversion.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2335</id>
  <name>Crusade</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>White creatures get +1/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All white creatures get +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2336</id>
  <name>Death Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Regenerate target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Regenerate target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2337</id>
  <name>Disenchant</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target enchantment or artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2338</id>
  <name>Divine Transformation</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +3/+3.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Glory surged through her and radiance surrounded her. All things were possible with the blessing of the Divine.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2339</id>
  <name>Elder Land Wurm</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dragon Wurm</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender, trample &lt;br&gt;When Elder Land Wurm blocks, it loses defender.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Cannot attack until assigned as a blocker.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Sometimes it's best to let sleeping dragons lie.</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2340</id>
  <name>Eye for an Eye</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Eye for an Eye deals X damage to the controller of the source of your choice that dealt damage to you this turn, where X is the damage dealt to you by that source this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may cast Eye for an Eye only when a creature, spell, or effect deals damage to you. Eye for an Eye deals an equal amount of damage to the controller of that creature, spell, or effect. If another spell or effect reduces the amount of damage you receive, it does not reduce the damage dealt by Eye for an Eye.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2341</id>
  <name>Fortified Area</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Wall creatures you control get +1/+0 and have banding.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All walls you control gain banding and get +1/+0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2342</id>
  <name>Green Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has protection from green. This effect doesn't remove Green Ward.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains protection from green. The protection granted by Green Ward does not destroy Green Ward.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2343</id>
  <name>Healing Salve</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Target player gains 3 life; or prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Give target player 3 life, or prevent up to 3 damage to any creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2344</id>
  <name>Holy Armor</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +0/+2. &lt;br&gt;{W}: Enchanted creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +0/+2.&lt;br&gt;{W}: Target creature Holy Armor enchants gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2345</id>
  <name>Holy Strength</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +1/+2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2346</id>
  <name>Island Sanctuary</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>If you would draw a card during your draw step, instead you may skip that draw. If you do, until your next turn, you can't be attacked except by creatures with flying and/or islandwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your draw phase, you may draw one less card from your library. If you do so, until start of your next turn the only creatures that can attack you are those with flying or islandwalk.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2347</id>
  <name>Karma</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Karma deals damage to that player equal to the number of Swamps he or she controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During each player's upkeep, Karma deals 1 damage to that player for each swamp he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2348</id>
  <name>Kismet</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Artifacts, creatures, and lands your opponents control come into play tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All of target player's creatures, lands, and artifacts come into play tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2349</id>
  <name>Land Tax</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent controls more lands than you, you may search your library for up to three basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, if an opponent controls more land than you, you may search your library and remove up to three basic land cards and put them into your hand. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2350</id>
  <name>Mesa Pegasus</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Pegasus</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, banding</printedText>
  <flavorText>Before a woman marries in the village of Sursi, she must visit the land of the Mesa Pegasus. Legend has it that if the woman is pure of heart and her love is true, a Mesa Pegasus will appear, blessing her family with long life and good fortune.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2351</id>
  <name>Morale</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"After Lacjsi's speech, the Knights grew determined to crush their ancient enemies clan by clan."&lt;br&gt;--Tivadar of Thorn, History of the Goblin Wars</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2352</id>
  <name>Northern Paladin</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{W}{W}, {T}: Destroy target black permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}{W}, {T}: Destroy target black permanent.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Look to the north; there you will find aid and comfort."The Book of Tal</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2353</id>
  <name>Osai Vultures</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, if a creature was put into a graveyard from play this turn, put a carrion counter on Osai Vultures. &lt;br&gt;Remove two carrion counters from Osai Vultures: Osai Vultures gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;At the end of any turn in which a creature is put into the graveyard from play, put a carrion counter on Vultures.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove two carrion counters to give Vultures +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2354</id>
  <name>Pearled Unicorn</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Unicorn</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"--'Do you know, I always thought Unicorns were fabulous monsters, too? I never saw one alive before' --'Well, now that we have seen each other,' said the Unicorn, --'if you'll believe in me, I'll believe in you.'"&lt;br&gt;--Lewis Carroll</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2355</id>
  <name>Personal Incarnation</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Avatar Incarnation</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kev Brockschmidt</artist>
  <oracleText>{0}: The next 1 damage that would be dealt to Personal Incarnation this turn is dealt to its owner instead. Any player may play this ability, but only if he or she owns Personal Incarnation. &lt;br&gt;When Personal Incarnation is put into a graveyard from play, its owner loses half his or her life, rounded up.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Owner may redirect any or all damage done to Personal Incarnation to self instead. If Personal Incarnation is put into the graveyard from play, owner loses half his or her remaining life, rounding up the loss. Effects that redirect or prevent damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2356</id>
  <name>Piety</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Blocking creatures get +0/+3 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All blocking creatures get +0/+3 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Whoever obeys God and His Prophet, fears God and does his duty to Him, will surely find success."&lt;br&gt;--The Qur'an, 24:52</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2357</id>
  <name>Pikemen</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dennis Detwiller</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding, first strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"As the cavalry bore down, we faced them with swords drawn and pikes hidden in the grass at our feet. --'Don't lift your pikes 'til I give the word,' I said."&lt;br&gt;--Maeveen O'Donagh, Memoirs of a Soldier</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2358</id>
  <name>Purelace</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Target spell or permanent becomes white. (Mana symbols on that permanent remain unchanged.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the color of target spell or target permanent to white. Costs to cast, tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target remain unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2359</id>
  <name>Red Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has protection from red. This effect doesn't remove Red Ward.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains protection from red. The protection granted by Red Ward does not destroy Red Ward.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2360</id>
  <name>Reverse Damage</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage. You gain life equal to the damage prevented this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All damage dealt to you so far this turn by one source is retroactively added to your life total instead of subtracted. Further damage this turn is treated normally.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2361</id>
  <name>Righteousness</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Target blocking creature gets +7/+7 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target blocking creature gets +7/+7 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2362</id>
  <name>Samite Healer</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Prevent 1 damage to any creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Healers ultimately acquire the divine gifts of spiritual and physical wholeness. The most devout are also granted the ability to pass physical wholeness on to others.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2363</id>
  <name>Savannah Lions</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Cat</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The traditional kings of the jungle command a healthy respect in other climates as well. Relying mainly on their stealth and speed, Savannah Lions can take a victim by surprise, even in the endless, flat plains of their homeland.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2364</id>
  <name>Seeker</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or white creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked except by white creatures and artifact creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2365</id>
  <name>Serra Angel</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Angel</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, vigilance (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach, and attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Attacking does not cause Serra Angel to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Born with wings of light and a sword of faith, this heavenly incarnation embodies both fury and purity.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2366</id>
  <name>Spirit Link</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain 1 life for every 1 damage target creature deals. You may gain more life than the toughness or the total life of the creature or player damaged by the creature Spirit Link enchants.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2367</id>
  <name>Swords to Plowshares</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove target creature from the game. Its controller gains life equal to its power.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Remove target creature from the game. The creature's controller gains life equal to its power.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2368</id>
  <name>Tundra Wolves</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolf</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>I heard their eerie howling, the wolves calling their kindred across the frozen plains.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2369</id>
  <name>Visions</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at the top five cards of target player's library. You may then have that player shuffle that library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Look at the top five cards of any library. You may then shuffle that library.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Visions of glory, spare my aching sight,&lt;br&gt;Ye unborn ages, crowd not on my soul"&lt;br&gt;--Thomas Gray, "The Bard"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2370</id>
  <name>Wall of Swords</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender, flying (This creature can't attack, and it can block creatures with flying.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>Just as the evil ones approached to slay Justina, she cast a great spell, imbuing her weapons with her own life force. Thus she fulfilled the prophecy: "In the death of your savior will you find salvation."</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2371</id>
  <name>White Knight</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)&lt;br&gt;Protection from black (This creature can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything black.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>Out of the blackness and stench of the engulfing swamp emerged a shimmering figure. Only the splattered armor and ichor-stained sword hinted at the unfathomable evil the Knight had just laid waste.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2372</id>
  <name>White Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has protection from white. This effect doesn't remove White Ward.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains protection from white. The protection granted by White Ward does not destroy White Ward.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2373</id>
  <name>Wrath of God</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all creatures. They can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury all creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2374</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2375</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2376</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2377</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2378</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2379</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2380</id>
  <name>Strip Mine</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Sacrifice Strip Mine: Destroy target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add one colorless mana to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Sacrifice Strip Mine to destroy target land.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Unlike previous conflicts, the war between Urza and Mishra made Dominia itself a casualty of war.</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2381</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2382</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2383</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2384</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2385</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2386</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2387</id>
  <name>Mishra's Factory</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja &amp; Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{1}: Mishra's Factory becomes a 2/2 Assembly-Worker artifact creature until end of turn. It's still a land. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target Assembly-Worker creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add 1 colorless mana to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{1}: Mishra's Factory becomes an Assembly Worker, a 2/2 artifact creature, until end of turn. Assembly Worker still counts as a land but cannot be tapped for mana the turn it comes into play.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Target Assembly Worker gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2388</id>
  <name>Oasis</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Prevent 1 damage to any creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2389</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2390</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2391</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Fourth Edition</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
</list>
</cards>