<cards>
<name>Ice Age</name>
<releaseDate>1996-06</releaseDate>
<shortname>ICE</shortname><list>
<mc>
  <id>2392</id>
  <name>Adarkar Sentinel</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Soldier</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: Adarkar Sentinel gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: +0/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We encountered the Sentinels in the wastes, near no living thing. Their purpose was inscrutable."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2393</id>
  <name>Aegis of the Meek</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}: Target 1/1 creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Target 1/1 creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"With this marvel, even the weak have a fighting chance"&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson,&lt;br&gt;Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2394</id>
  <name>Amulet of Quoz</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Amulet of Quoz from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Sacrifice Amulet of Quoz: Target opponent may add the top card of his or her library to the ante. If he or she doesn't, you flip a coin. If you win the flip, that player loses the game. If you lose the flip, you lose the game. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Remove Amulet of Quoz from your deck before playing if you are not playing for ante.&lt;br&gt;{0},{T}: Sacrifice Amulet of Quoz. Flip a coin; target opponent calls heads or tails while coin is in the air. If the flip ends up in your favor, that opponent loses the game. Otherwise, you lose the game.&lt;br&gt;Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to prevent this loss of life. Use this ability only during your upkeep. The opponent may ante an additional card to counter this effect.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2395</id>
  <name>Arcum's Sleigh</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Until end of turn, target creature has vigilance as long as defending player controls a snow land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2},{T}: Attacking this turn does not cause target creature to tap. You cannot use this ability if defending player controls no snow-covered lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"With the proper equipment and caution, one can travel anywhere."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2396</id>
  <name>Arcum's Weathervane</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target snow land is no longer snow. &lt;br&gt;{2}, {T}: Target nonsnow basic land becomes snow.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2},{T}: Target snow-covered land becomes a non-snow-covered land of the same type. Mark the changed land with a counter.&lt;br&gt;{2},{T}: Target non-snow-covered basic land becomes a snow-covered land of the same type. Mark the changed land with a counter.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2397</id>
  <name>Arcum's Whistle</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Choose target non-Wall creature the active player has controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn. That player may pay {X}, where X is that creature's converted mana cost. If he or she doesn't, the creature attacks this turn if able, and at end of turn, destroy it if it didn't attack. Play this ability only before attackers are declared.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Target non-wall creature must attack. At end of turn, destroy that creature if it could not attack. Use this ability only during the creature's controller's turn before the attack. The creature's controller may counter this effect by paying X, where X is equal to the creature's casting cost. Arcum's Whistle does not affect creatures brought under their controller's control this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2398</id>
  <name>Barbed Sextant</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Barbed Sextant: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Sacrifice Barbed Sextant to add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2399</id>
  <name>Baton of Morale</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Target creature gains banding until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Goblins would kill to get ahold of this one."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson,&lt;br&gt;Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2400</id>
  <name>Celestial Sword</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Target creature you control gets +3/+3 until end of turn. Destroy it at end of turn. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Target creature you control gets +3/+3 until end of turn. At end of turn, bury that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"So great is its power, only the chosen can wield it and live."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2401</id>
  <name>Crown of the Ages</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: Attach target Aura attached to a creature to another creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4},{T}: Switch target enchantment from one creature to another; the enchantment's new target must be legal. The controller of the enchantment does not change. Treat the enchantment as though it were just cast on the new target.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2402</id>
  <name>Despotic Scepter</name>
  <cost>{1}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Destroy target permanent you own. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Bury target permanent you own.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We were not meant to have such terrible things. They should be left where we found them, if not destroyed"&lt;br&gt;--Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2403</id>
  <name>Elkin Bottle</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Remove the top card of your library from the game. Until the beginning of your next upkeep, you may play that card. At the beginning of your next upkeep, if you haven't played the card, put it into your graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Take the top card from your library and place it face up in front of you. You may play that card as though it were in your hand; if you do not play it by your next upkeep, remove it from the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2404</id>
  <name>Fyndhorn Bow</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Target creature gains first strike until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"With a bow like this, the hunting is always good."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko,&lt;br&gt;Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2405</id>
  <name>Goblin Lyre</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Kimble</artist>
  <oracleText>Sacrifice Goblin Lyre: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, Goblin Lyre deals damage to target opponent equal to the number of creatures you control. If you lose the flip, Goblin Lyre deals damage to you equal to the number of creatures that opponent controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Sacrifice Goblin Lyre. Flip a coin; target opponent calls heads or tails while coin is in the air. If the flip ends up in your favor, Goblin Lyre deals * damage to that opponent, where * is equal to the number of creatures you control. Otherwise, Goblin Lyre deals * damage to you, where * is equal to the number of creatures the opponent controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2406</id>
  <name>Hematite Talisman</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a red spell is played, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Untap target permanent.&lt;br&gt;Use this ability only when a red spell is successfully cast and only once for each red spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2407</id>
  <name>Ice Cauldron</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{X}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Ice Cauldron and remove a nonland card in your hand from the game. As long as that card remains removed from the game, you may play it. Note the type and amount of mana used to pay this activation cost. Play this ability only if there are no charge counters on Ice Cauldron. &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove a charge counter from Ice Cauldron: Add to your mana pool mana of the type and amount last used to put a charge counter on Ice Cauldron. Spend this mana only to play the last card removed from the game with Ice Cauldron.</oracleText>
  <printedText>X,{T}: Put a charge counter on Ice Cauldron, and put a spell card face up on Ice Cauldron. Note the type and amount of mana used to pay this activation cost. Use this ability only if there are no charge counters on Ice Cauldron. You may play that spell card as though it were in your hand.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Remove the charge counter from Ice Cauldron to add mana of the type and amount last used to put a charge counter on Ice Cauldron to your mana pool. This mana is usable only to cast the spell on top of Ice Cauldron.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2408</id>
  <name>Icy Manipulator</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Tap target artifact, creature, or land.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The scavengers who first found it called it the --'Bone Crank.' Not a bad name, I'd say."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2409</id>
  <name>Infinite Hourglass</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a time counter on Infinite Hourglass. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;All creatures get +1/+0 for each time counter on Infinite Hourglass. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{3}: Remove a time counter from Infinite Hourglass. Any player may play this ability but only during any upkeep step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, put a time counter on Infinite Hourglass. During any upkeep, any player may pay {3} to remove a time counter from Infinite Hourglass. All creatures get +1/+0 for each time counter on Infinite Hourglass.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2410</id>
  <name>Jester's Cap</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Jester's Cap: Search target player's library for three cards and remove them from the game. Then that player shuffles his or her library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2},{T}: Sacrifice Jester's Cap to look through target player's library and remove any three of those cards from the game. Reshuffle that library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Know your foes' strengths as well as their weaknesses."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2411</id>
  <name>Jester's Mask</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Jester's Mask comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Jester's Mask: Target opponent puts his or her hand on top of his or her library. Search that library for as many cards as he or she put on top of it this way. That player puts those cards into his or her hand, then shuffles his or her library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Comes into play tapped.&lt;br&gt;{1},{T}: Sacrifice Jester's Mask to look through target opponent's hand and library. Give that player a new hand of as many cards as he or she had before. Reshuffle the remaining cards afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2412</id>
  <name>Jeweled Amulet</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Jeweled Amulet. Note what type of mana was used to pay this activation cost. Play this ability only if there are no charge counters on Jeweled Amulet. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove all charge counters from Jeweled Amulet: Add one mana of the type last used to put a charge counter on Jeweled Amulet to your mana pool. Play this ability only if there are one or more charge counters on Jeweled Amulet.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Put a charge counter on Jeweled Amulet. Note what type of mana was used to pay this activation cost. Use this ability only if there are no charge counters on Jeweled Amulet.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Remove the charge counter from Jeweled Amulet to add one mana of the type last used to put a charge counter on Jeweled Amulet to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2413</id>
  <name>Lapis Lazuli Talisman</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a blue spell is played, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Untap target permanent.&lt;br&gt;Use this ability only when a blue spell is successfully cast and only once for each blue spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2414</id>
  <name>Malachite Talisman</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a green spell is played, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Untap target permanent.&lt;br&gt;Use this ability only when a green spell is successfully cast and only once for each green spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2415</id>
  <name>Nacre Talisman</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a white spell is played, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Untap target permanent.&lt;br&gt;Use this ability only when a white spell is successfully cast and only once for each white spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2416</id>
  <name>Naked Singularity</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {3} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;If tapped for mana, Plains produce {R}, Islands produce {G}, Swamps produce {W}, Mountains produce {U}, and Forests produce {B} instead of any other type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {3}&lt;br&gt;Instead of their normal mana, plains produce {R}, islands produce {G}, swamps produce {W}, mountains produce {U}, and forests produce {B}.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2417</id>
  <name>Onyx Talisman</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a black spell is played, you may pay {3}. If you do, untap target permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Untap target permanent.&lt;br&gt;Use this ability only when a black spell is successfully cast and only once for each black spell cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2418</id>
  <name>Pentagram of the Ages</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4},{T}: Prevent all damage dealt to you from one source. Pentagram of the Ages does not prevent the same source damaging you again later this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Take this item, for instance. How would it destroy us, Relicbane?"&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2419</id>
  <name>Pit Trap</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Pit Trap: Destroy target attacking creature without flying. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2},{T}: Sacrifice Pit Trap to bury target creature without flying that is attacking you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"These traps are truly a symbol of great cruelty and sinister cunning."&lt;br&gt;--Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2420</id>
  <name>Runed Arch</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Runed Arch comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{X}, {T}, Sacrifice Runed Arch: X target creatures with power 2 or less are unblockable this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Comes into play tapped.&lt;br&gt;{X},{T}: Sacrifice Runed Arch. X target creatures with power no greater than 2 cannot be blocked this turn. Other effects may later be used to increase a creature's power beyond 2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2421</id>
  <name>Shield of the Ages</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to you this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Prevent 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This shield is a true rarity: an artifact whose purpose is obvious."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson,&lt;br&gt;Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2422</id>
  <name>Skull Catapult</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}, Sacrifice a creature: Skull Catapult deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Sacrifice a creature to have Skull Catapult deal 2 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let any who doubt the evil of using the ancient devices look at this infernal machine. What manner of fiend would design such a sadistic device?" &lt;br&gt;--Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2423</id>
  <name>Snow Fortress</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{1}: Snow Fortress gets +1/+0 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{1}: Snow Fortress gets +0/+1 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{3}: Snow Fortress deals 1 damage to target creature without flying that's attacking you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counts as a wall&lt;br&gt;{1}: +1/+0 until end of turn&lt;br&gt;{1}: +0/+1 until end of turn&lt;br&gt;{3}: Snow Fortress deals 1 damage to target creature without flying that is attacking you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2424</id>
  <name>Soldevi Golem</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Golem</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Soldevi Golem doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, you may untap target tapped creature an opponent controls. If you do, untap Soldevi Golem.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Untap target creature opponent controls to untap Soldevi Golem at the end of your upkeep. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Slow and steady wins the race.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2425</id>
  <name>Soldevi Simulacrum</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Soldier</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;{1}: Soldevi Simulacrum gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;{1}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>They look human--&lt;br&gt;until they bleed.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2426</id>
  <name>Staff of the Ages</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with landwalk abilities can be blocked as though they didn't have those abilities.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with any landwalk ability may be blocked as though they did not have those abilities.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We found this staff useful on our visit to this very commission. Would Relicbane prefer we had been slain by Lim-Dul's horrors?"&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2427</id>
  <name>Sunstone</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, Sacrifice a snow land: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Sacrifice a snow-covered land to have all creatures deal no damage in combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I dispute Relicbane's hysterical allegations, Commissioner, but it is true that these artifacts can be dangerous."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2428</id>
  <name>Time Bomb</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a time counter on Time Bomb. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{1}, {T}, Sacrifice Time Bomb: Time Bomb deals damage to each creature and each player equal to the number of time counters on Time Bomb.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, put a time counter on Time Bomb.&lt;br&gt;{1},{T}: Sacrifice Time Bomb to have it deal * damage to each creature and player, where * is equal to the number of time counters on Time Bomb.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2429</id>
  <name>Urza's Bauble</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice Urza's Bauble: Look at a card at random in target player's hand. You draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice Urza's Bauble to choose a card at random from target player's hand; look at that card. Ignore this ability if that player has no cards left in hand. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2430</id>
  <name>Vexing Arcanix</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Target player names a card, then reveals the top card of his or her library. If it's the named card, the player puts it into his or her hand. Otherwise, the player puts it into his or her graveyard and Vexing Arcanix deals 2 damage to him or her.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Target player names a card and then turns over the top card of his or her library. If that is the card named, put it into the player's hand. Otherwise, put it into the player's graveyard, and Vexing Arcanix deals 2 damage to that player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2431</id>
  <name>Vibrating Sphere</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>As long as it's your turn, creatures you control get +2/+0. &lt;br&gt;As long as it's not your turn, creatures you control get -0/-2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your turn, all creatures you control get +2/+0. During all other turns, all creatures you control get -0/-2.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Unearthly and invisible fibers emanate from this sphere, entangling all who draw near."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2432</id>
  <name>Walking Wall</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender &lt;br&gt;{3}: Walking Wall gets +3/-1 until end of turn and can attack this turn as though it didn't have defender. Play this ability only once each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counts as a wall&lt;br&gt;{3}: Walking Wall gets +3/-1 until end of turn and can attack this turn. Walking Wall cannot attack the turn it comes under your control. Use this ability only once a turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The fortress is not what it seems."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2433</id>
  <name>Wall of Shields</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding, counts as a wall</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It's the pokey bits that hurt the most."&lt;br&gt;--Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2434</id>
  <name>War Chariot</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3},{T}: Target creature gains trample until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I wouldn't advise using it with a Woolly Mammoth, but it's quite appropriate for many other beasts."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2435</id>
  <name>Whalebone Glider</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target creature with power 3 or less gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2},{T}: Target creature with power no greater than 3 gains flying until end of turn. Other effects may later be used to increase that creature's power beyond 3.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It's no Ornithopter, but then I'm no Urza."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2436</id>
  <name>Zuran Orb</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Sacrifice a land: You gain 2 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Sacrifice a land to gain 2 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I will go to any length to achieve my goal. Eternal life is worth any sacrifice."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2437</id>
  <name>Abyssal Specter</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Specter</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Whenever Abyssal Specter deals damage to a player, that player discards a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Whenever Abyssal Specter damages any player, that player chooses and discards a card from his or her hand. Ignore this ability if the player has no cards in hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Open the gates, and bid them enter."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2438</id>
  <name>Ashen Ghoul</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Haste &lt;br&gt;{B}: Return Ashen Ghoul from your graveyard to play. Play this ability only during your upkeep and only if three or more creature cards are above Ashen Ghoul.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Ashen Ghoul can attack the turn it comes into play.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Return Ashen Ghoul to play under your control. Use this ability only at the end of your upkeep and only if Ashen Ghoul is in your graveyard with at least three creature cards above it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2439</id>
  <name>Brine Shaman</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric Shaman</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{1}{U}{U}, Sacrifice a creature: Counter target creature spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice a creature to give target creature +2/+2 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;{1}{U}{U}: Sacrifice a creature to counter target summon spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Shamans of Marit Lage do her bidding in secret, but they do it gladly."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2440</id>
  <name>Burnt Offering</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>As an additional cost to play Burnt Offering, sacrifice a creature. &lt;br&gt;Add X mana in any combination of {B} and/or {R} to your mana pool, where X is the sacrificed creature's converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sacrifice a creature to add that creature's casting cost in any combination of red and/or black mana to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"My foes serve me twice: in dying, and in death."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2441</id>
  <name>Cloak of Confusion</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature attacks and isn't blocked, you may have it deal no combat damage this turn. If you do, defending player discards a card at random.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target creature you control attacks and is not blocked, you may choose to have it deal no damage to defending player this turn. If you do so, that player discards a card at random from his or her hand. Ignore this ability if that player has no cards in hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2442</id>
  <name>Dance of the Dead</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature card in a graveyard &lt;br&gt;When Dance of the Dead comes into play, if it's in play, it loses "enchant creature card in a graveyard" and gains "enchant creature put into play with Dance of the Dead." Return enchanted creature card to play tapped under your control and attach Dance of the Dead to it. When Dance of the Dead leaves play, that creature's controller sacrifices it. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.  &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {1}{B}. If he or she does, untap that creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Take target creature from any graveyard and put it directly into play under your control, tapped, with +1/+1. Treat that creature as though it were just summoned. The creature does not untap during its controller's untap phase. At the end of his or her upkeep, its controller may pay an additional {1}{B} to untap it. If Dance of the Dead is removed, bury the creature in its owner's graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2443</id>
  <name>Dark Banishing</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target non-black creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Will not the mountains quake and hills melt at the coming of the darkness? Share this vision with your enemies, Lim-Dul, and they shall wither."&lt;br&gt;--Leshrac, Walker of Night</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2444</id>
  <name>Dark Ritual</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Add {B}{B}{B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Leshrac, my liege, grant me the power I am due."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2445</id>
  <name>Demonic Consultation</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Name a card. Remove the top six cards of your library from the game, then reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal the named card. Put that card into your hand and remove all other cards revealed this way from the game.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Name a card. Remove the top six cards of your library from the game and reveal the next card to all players. If it is the card named, put it into your hand. If not, remove that card from the game and continue revealing the top card of your library and removing it from the game until the named card appears.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2446</id>
  <name>Dread Wight</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of combat, put a paralyzation counter on all creatures blocking or blocked by Dread Wight and tap those creatures. They gain "If this creature has a paralyzation counter on it, it doesn't untap during its controller's untap step" and "{4}: Remove a paralyzation counter from this creature."</oracleText>
  <printedText>At end of combat, put a paralyzation counter on any creature blocking or blocked by Dread Wight and tap that creature. As long as the creature has a paralyzation counter on it, it does not untap during its controller's untap phase. As a non-interrupt fast effect, the creature's controller may pay {4} to remove a paralyzation counter.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2447</id>
  <name>Drift of the Dead</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Drift of the Dead's power and toughness are each equal to the number of snow lands you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Drift of the Dead has power and toughness each equal to the number of snow-covered lands you control.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Take their dead, and entomb them in the snow. Risen, they shall serve a new purpose."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2448</id>
  <name>Fear</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has fear. (It can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked except by artifact creatures or black creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Even the bravest of warriors yet knows the dark clutch of fright upon his stalwart heart."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2449</id>
  <name>Flow of Maggots</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Flow of Maggots can't be blocked by non-Wall creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;Cannot be blocked by non-wall creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The very earth seemed alive and made a sound like the writhing of the damned."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2450</id>
  <name>Foul Familiar</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Foul Familiar can't block. &lt;br&gt;{B}, Pay 1 life: Return Foul Familiar to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be declared as a blocking creature.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Pay 1 life to return Foul Familiar to owner's hand. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Serve me, and live forever."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2451</id>
  <name>Gangrenous Zombies</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice Gangrenous Zombies: Gangrenous Zombies deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. If you control a snow Swamp, Gangrenous Zombies deals 2 damage to each creature and each player instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice Gangrenous Zombies to have it deal 1 damage to each creature and player. If you control any snow-covered swamps, Gangrenous Zombies instead deals 2 damage to each creature and player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2452</id>
  <name>Gaze of Pain</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Until end of turn, whenever a creature you control attacks and isn't blocked, you may choose to have it deal damage equal to its power to a target creature. If you do, it deals no combat damage this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For each creature you control that attacks and is not blocked, you may choose to have it deal no damage to defending player this turn. If you do so, it instead deals damage equal to its power to any target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Remove the guardians to ensure your victory.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2453</id>
  <name>Gravebind</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature can't be regenerated this turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot regenerate this turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>One foot in the grave,&lt;br&gt;firmly planted.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2454</id>
  <name>Hecatomb</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>When Hecatomb comes into play, sacrifice Hecatomb unless you sacrifice four creatures. &lt;br&gt;Tap an untapped Swamp you control: Hecatomb deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Hecatomb comes into play, sacrifice four creatures.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Tap target swamp you control to have Hecatomb deal 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2455</id>
  <name>Hoar Shade</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Shade</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: Hoar Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The creature we fought in the western waste was doubly dangerous: mortally wounded, it rebounded and attacked again."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2456</id>
  <name>Howl from Beyond</name>
  <cost>{X}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +X/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"From the mouths of my servants, my voice shall emerge to shake the souls of my foes."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2457</id>
  <name>Hyalopterous Lemure</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{0}: Hyalopterous Lemure gets -1/-0 and gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Flying and -1/-0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Lemures looked harmless, until they descended on my troops. Within moments, only bones remained."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2458</id>
  <name>Icequake</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target land. If that land was a snow land, Icequake deals 1 damage to that land's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target land. If that land is a snow-covered land, Icequake deals 1 damage to the land's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"When the earth shakes, and their animals are swallowed up by the ground, perhaps they will think twice before attacking again."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2459</id>
  <name>Infernal Darkness</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep-Pay {B} and 1 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;If a land is tapped for mana, it produces {B} instead of any other type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {B} and 1 life&lt;br&gt;All mana-producing lands produce {B} instead of their normal mana.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I thought the day had brought enough horrors for our ragged band, but the night was far worse."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2460</id>
  <name>Infernal Denizen</name>
  <cost>{7}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Demon</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice two Swamps. If you can't, tap Infernal Denizen, and an opponent may gain control of a creature you control of his or her choice. That opponent retains control of that creature as long as Infernal Denizen remains in play. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target creature as long as Infernal Denizen remains in play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, sacrifice two swamps. If you cannot, tap Infernal Denizen, and target opponent may gain control of target creature of his or her choice you control. The opponent loses control of that creature if Infernal Denizen leaves play.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target creature. Lose control of that creature if Infernal Denizen leaves play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2461</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Dead</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Skeleton</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>When Kjeldoran Dead comes into play, sacrifice a creature. &lt;br&gt;{B}: Regenerate Kjeldoran Dead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Kjeldoran Dead comes into play, sacrifice a creature.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"They shall kill those whom once they loved."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2462</id>
  <name>Knight of Stromgald</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from white &lt;br&gt;{B}: Knight of Stromgald gains first strike until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: Knight of Stromgald gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from white&lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: +1/+0 until end of turn&lt;br&gt;{B}: First strike until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Kjeldorans should rule supreme, and to the rest, death"&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2463</id>
  <name>Krovikan Elementalist</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{R}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{U}{U}: Target creature you control gains flying until end of turn. Sacrifice it at end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{R}: Target creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;{U}{U}: Target creature you control gains flying until end of turn. At end of turn, bury that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Elementalists' talents could be useful if turned to other purposes."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2464</id>
  <name>Krovikan Fetish</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;When Krovikan Fetish comes into play, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Draw a card at the beginning of the upkeep of the turn after Krovikan Fetish comes into play.&lt;br&gt;Target creature gets +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Some Krovikans find strength in the ears and eyes of their victims and wear such fetishes into battle.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2465</id>
  <name>Krovikan Vampire</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Vampire</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of turn, if a creature dealt damage by Krovikan Vampire this turn was put into a graveyard, put that card into play under your control. Sacrifice the creature when you lose control of Krovikan Vampire.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of a turn in which any creature is damaged by Krovikan Vampire and put into any graveyard, put that creature directly into play under your control. Treat the creature as though it were just summoned. If you lose control of Krovikan Vampire or Krovikan Vampire leaves play, bury the creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2466</id>
  <name>Legions of Lim-Dul</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Snow swampwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Snow-covered swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I have seen the faces of my dead friends among that grim band, and I can bear no more."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2467</id>
  <name>Leshrac's Rite</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has swampwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains swampwalk.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Bind me to thee, my soul to thine. I am your servant and your slave. I shall hunger for your word and thirst for your blessing. Blood for blood, flesh for flesh, Leshrac, my lord."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2468</id>
  <name>Leshrac's Sigil</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent plays a green spell, you may pay {B}{B}. If you do, look at that player's hand and choose a card from it. The player discards that card. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: Return Leshrac's Sigil to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{B}: When any opponent successfully casts a green spell, look at that player's hand and choose a card; he or she then discards that card. Use this ability only once each time a green spell is cast.&lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: Return Leshrac's Sigil to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2469</id>
  <name>Lim-Dul's Cohort</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Lim-Dul's Cohort blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, that creature can't be regenerated this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures blocking or blocked by Lim-Dul's Cohort cannot regenerate this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Join me in the place of power, you risen dead. Join me where the waters weep and the trees have no hearts."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2470</id>
  <name>Lim-Dul's Hex</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, for each player, Lim-Dul's Hex deals 1 damage to that player unless he or she pays {B} or {3}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, Lim-Dul's Hex deals 1 damage to each player. Each player may pay {B} or {3} to prevent the damage to himself or herself.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The weak shall fall. The strong shall remain."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2471</id>
  <name>Mind Ravel</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player discards a card. &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player chooses and discards a card from his or her hand.&lt;br&gt;Ignore this ability if that player has no cards in hand. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>An end to reason, an end to order. Forget all that has been.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2472</id>
  <name>Mind Warp</name>
  <cost>{X}{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at target player's hand and choose X cards from it. That player discards them.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Look at target player's hand and choose X cards; that player then discards those cards. If the player does not have enough cards in hand, his or her entire hand is discarded.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2473</id>
  <name>Mind Whip</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {3}. If he or she doesn't, Mind Whip deals 2 damage to that player and you tap that creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During target creature's controller's upkeep, he or she pays {3} or Mind Whip deals 2 damage to him or her. If Mind Whip deals damage in this way, tap that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A mind in agony is a sparrow without wings."Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2474</id>
  <name>Minion of Leshrac</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Demon Minion</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from black &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature other than Minion of Leshrac. If you can't, tap Minion of Leshrac and it deals 5 damage to you. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Destroy target creature or land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, sacrifice a creature or Minion of Leshrac deals 5 damage to you. If Minion of Leshrac deals damage to you in this way, tap it. You cannot sacrifice Minion of Leshrac to itself.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Destroy target creature or land.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2475</id>
  <name>Minion of Tevesh Szat</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Demon Minion</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, Minion of Tevesh Szat deals 2 damage to you unless you pay {B}{B}. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature gets +3/-2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {B}{B} or Minion of Tevesh Szat deals 2 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature gets +3/-2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A minion given over to Tevesh Szat is a stronger minion gained."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2476</id>
  <name>Mole Worms</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Worm</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Mole Worms during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Tap target land. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step as long as Mole Worms remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may choose not to untap Mole Worms during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Tap target land. As long as Mole Worms remains tapped, that land does not untap during its controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2477</id>
  <name>Moor Fiend</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let them close the gates of Krov from dusk until dawn if they so choose. It matters not. My fiends shall yet rend their flesh from their bones."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2478</id>
  <name>Necropotence</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Skip your draw step. &lt;br&gt;If you would discard a card, discard it, but remove it from the game instead of putting it into your graveyard. &lt;br&gt;Pay 1 life: Remove the top card of your library from the game face down. Put that card into your hand at the end of your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Skip your draw phase. If you discard a card from your hand, remove that card from the game.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Pay 1 life to set aside the top card of your library. At the beginning of your next discard phase, put that card into your hand. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2479</id>
  <name>Norritt</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Imp</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Untap target blue creature. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Choose target non-Wall creature the active player has controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn. That creature attacks this turn if able. If it doesn't, destroy it at end of turn. Play this ability only before attackers are declared.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Untap target blue creature.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Force target non-wall creature to attack. If creature cannot attack, destroy it at end of turn. Use this ability only during target creature's controller's turn, before the attack. Cannot target creatures brought under their controller's control this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2480</id>
  <name>Oath of Lim-Dul</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever you lose life, sacrifice a permanent other than Oath of Lim-Dul or discard a card for each 1 life you lost. (Damage dealt to you causes you to lose life.) &lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: Draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For each 1 damage dealt to you or 1 life you lose, sacrifice a permanent you control or choose and discard a card from your hand. You cannot sacrifice Oath of Lim-Dul in this way. Ignore this effect if you control no permanents other than Oath of Lim-Dul and have no cards in hand.&lt;br&gt;{B}{B}: Draw a card.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2481</id>
  <name>Pestilence Rats</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Rat</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Pestilence Rats's power is equal to the total number of other Rats in play. (For example, as long as there are two other Rats in play, Pestilence Rats's power and toughness are 2/3.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pestilence Rats has power equal to the total number of other Rats in play, no matter who controls them. For example, as long as there are two other Rats in play, Pestilence Rats has power and toughness 2/3.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2482</id>
  <name>Pox</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>Each player loses a third of his or her life, then discards a third of the cards in his or her hand, then sacrifices a third of the creatures he or she controls, then sacrifices a third of the lands he or she controls. Round up each time.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each player loses 1/3 of his or her life; then chooses and discards 1/3 of the cards in his or her hand; then sacrifices 1/3 of the creatures he or she controls; and finally sacrifices 1/3 of the lands he or she controls. Round each loss up. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter the this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2483</id>
  <name>Seizures</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, Seizures deals 3 damage to that creature's controller unless that player pays {3}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever target creature becomes tapped, that creature's controller pays {3} or Seizures deals 3 damage to him or her.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sheathe your sword, warrior, lest ye fall on it when stricken."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2484</id>
  <name>Songs of the Damned</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Add {B} to your mana pool for each creature card in your graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Add {B} to your mana pool for each creature in your graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Not wind, but the breath of the dead.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2485</id>
  <name>Soul Burn</name>
  <cost>{X}{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Spend only black and/or red mana on X. &lt;br&gt;Soul Burn deals X damage to target creature or player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt, but not more than the amount of {B} spent on X, the player's life total before Soul Burn dealt damage, or the creature's toughness.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Soul Burn deals 1 damage to a single target creature or player for each {B} or {R} you pay in addition to the casting cost. Gain 1 life for each {B} you spend in this way. You cannot gain more life than the toughness of the creature or the total life of the targeted player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2486</id>
  <name>Soul Kiss</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;{B}, Pay 1 life: Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Play this ability no more than three times each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Soul Kiss comes into play, choose target creature.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Pay 1 life to give creature Soul Kiss enchants +2/+2 until end of turn. You cannot spend more than {B}{B}{B} in this way each turn. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2487</id>
  <name>Spoils of Evil</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>For each artifact or creature card in an opponent's graveyard, add {1} to your mana pool and you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For each artifact or creature in target opponent's graveyard, add one colorless mana to your mana pool and gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Virtue has its rewards, as does its opposite." &lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2488</id>
  <name>Spoils of War</name>
  <cost>{X}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>X can't be more than the number of artifact and/or creature cards in an opponent's graveyard as you play Spoils of War. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Distribute X +1/+1 counters among any number of target creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put X +1/+1 counters on any number of target creatures, distributed any way you choose, where X is equal to the number of creatures and artifacts in target opponent's graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This is the fun part"&lt;br&gt;--Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2489</id>
  <name>Stench of Evil</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all Plains. For each land put into a graveyard this way, Stench of Evil deals 1 damage to that land's controller unless he or she pays {2}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all plains. Stench of Evil deals 1 damage to each player for each plains he or she controls that is destroyed in this way. Each player may pay {2} for each 1 damage he or she wishes to prevent from Stench of Evil.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2490</id>
  <name>Stromgald Cabal</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target white spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Pay 1 life to counter target white spell. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Kjeldor must be supreme at any cost."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2491</id>
  <name>Touch of Death</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Touch of Death deals 1 damage to target player. You gain 1 life. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Touch of Death deals 1 damage to target player, and you gain 1 life. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What was yours is mine. Your land, your people, and now your life."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2492</id>
  <name>Withering Wisps</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of turn, if no creatures are in play, sacrifice Withering Wisps. &lt;br&gt;{B}: Withering Wisps deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. Spend no more {B} this way each turn than the number of snow Swamps you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of any turn, if there are no creatures in play, bury Withering Wisps.&lt;br&gt;{B}: Withering Wisps deals 1 damage to each creature and each player. You cannot spend more {B} in this way each turn than the number of snow-covered swamps you control.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2493</id>
  <name>Arnjlot's Ascent</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;{1}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {U}&lt;br&gt;{1}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The dreams of a child fulfilled:&lt;br&gt;The wind on my brow,&lt;br&gt;the air 'neath my feet."&lt;br&gt;--Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2494</id>
  <name>Balduvian Conjurer</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Until end of turn, target snow land becomes a 2/2 creature that's still a land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target snow-covered land becomes a 2/2 creature until end of turn. The target still counts as land but cannot be tapped for mana if it came into play on a side this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The very lands of Balduvia are alive."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2495</id>
  <name>Balduvian Shaman</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric Shaman</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Change the text of target white enchantment you control that doesn't have cumulative upkeep by replacing all instances of one color word with another. That enchantment gains "Cumulative upkeep {1}." (For example, you may change "counters black spells" to "counters blue spells.")</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Permanently change the text of target white enchantment you control that does not have cumulative upkeep by replacing all instances of one color word with another. For example, you may change "Counters black spells" to "Counters blue spells." Balduvian Shaman cannot change mana symbols. That enchantment now has Cumulative Upkeep: {1}.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2496</id>
  <name>Binding Grasp</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Binding Grasp unless you pay {1}{U}. &lt;br&gt;You control enchanted creature. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +0/+1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {1}{U} or bury Binding Grasp.&lt;br&gt;Gain control of target creature; that creature gets +0/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What I want, I take."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2497</id>
  <name>Brainstorm</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Draw three cards, then put two cards from your hand on top of your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Draw three cards; then, take two cards from your hand and put them on top of your library in any order.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I reeled from the blow, and then suddenly, I knew exactly what to do. Within moments, victory was mine."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2498</id>
  <name>Breath of Dreams</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Green creatures have "Cumulative upkeep {1}."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {U}&lt;br&gt;Green creatures each require an additional Cumulative Upkeep: {1}.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Get up, blast you They're attacking Why are you all so slow?"&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2499</id>
  <name>Clairvoyance</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at target player's hand. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Look at target player's hand. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"As we followed the ice wall, we had the distinct feeling of being watched. Many of the party wanted to turn back."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2500</id>
  <name>Counterspell</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The duel was going badly for me, and Zur thought I was finished. He boasted that he would eat my soul--but all he ate were his words."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2501</id>
  <name>Deflection</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>Change the target of target spell with a single target.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target spell, which must have a single target, targets a new legal target of your choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Up and down,&lt;br&gt;over and through,&lt;br&gt;back around--&lt;br&gt;the joke's on you.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2502</id>
  <name>Dreams of the Dead</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{U}: Return target white or black creature card from your graveyard to play. That creature gains "Cumulative upkeep {2}." If the creature would leave play, remove it from the game instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{U}: Take target white or black creature from your graveyard and put it directly into play as though it were just summoned. That creature now requires an additional Cumulative Upkeep: {2}. If the creature leaves play, remove it from the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2503</id>
  <name>Enervate</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap target artifact, creature, or land. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap target artifact, creature, or land. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Worlds turn in crucial moments of decision. Make your choice."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2504</id>
  <name>Errant Minion</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, that player may pay {1} or {2}. Errant Minion deals damage to that player equal to 2 minus the amount of mana paid this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During target creature's controller's upkeep, Errant Minion deals 2 damage to him or her. He or she may pay {1} for each 1 damage he or she wishes to prevent from Errant Minion.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Abandon not your faith when others abandon you.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2505</id>
  <name>Essence Flare</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+0. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -0/-1 counter on that creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+0. During each of its controller's upkeeps, put a -0/-1 counter on the creature. These counters remain even if Essence Flare is removed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Never underestimate the power of the soul unleashed.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2506</id>
  <name>Force Void</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell unless that spell's caster pays an additional {1}. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"My mind and spirit are one--a barrier not readily passed."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2507</id>
  <name>Glacial Wall</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"We are farther west than any could have imagined possible, but I still wish to press on. Unfortunately, huge walls of ice block further travel. We can't believe they are natural."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2508</id>
  <name>Hydroblast</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Counter target spell if it's red; or destroy target permanent if it's red.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell if it is red or destroy target permanent if it is red.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Heed the lessons of our time: the forms of water may move the land itself and hold captive the fires within."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2509</id>
  <name>Iceberg</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Iceberg comes into play with X ice counters on it. &lt;br&gt;{3}: Put an ice counter on Iceberg. &lt;br&gt;Remove an ice counter from Iceberg: Add {1} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Iceberg comes into play, put X ice counters on it.&lt;br&gt;{3}: Put an ice counter on Iceberg.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove an ice counter from Iceberg to add one colorless mana to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2510</id>
  <name>Icy Prison</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>When Icy Prison comes into play, remove target creature from the game. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Icy Prison unless any player pays {3}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;When Icy Prison leaves play, return the removed creature to play under its owner's control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Icy Prison comes into play, remove target creature from the game. When Icy Prison leaves play, return that creature to play under its owner's control as though it were just summoned. During your upkeep, destroy Icy Prison. Any player may pay {3} to prevent this.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2511</id>
  <name>Illusionary Forces</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {U}</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Cumulative Upkeep: {U}</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This school was founded in secret, operates in secret, and exists for the teaching of secrets. Those who would alter reality must first escape it."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2512</id>
  <name>Illusionary Presence</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, choose a land type. Illusionary Presence gains landwalk of the chosen type until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {U}&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, Illusionary Presence gains a landwalk ability of your choice until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We could feel the Shaman's power, as surely as we felt the storm."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2513</id>
  <name>Illusionary Terrain</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;As Illusionary Terrain comes into play, choose two basic land types. &lt;br&gt;Basic lands of the first chosen type are of the second chosen type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {2}&lt;br&gt;All basic lands of one type become basic lands of a different type of your choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The drawing of maps is fruitless in the west near the ice walls; the very earth is formless."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2514</id>
  <name>Illusionary Wall</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion Wall</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender, flying, first strike &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {U}</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, first strike&lt;br&gt;Cumulative Upkeep: {U}</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let them see what is not there and feel what does not touch them. When they no longer trust their senses, that is the time to strike."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2515</id>
  <name>Illusions of Grandeur</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {2} &lt;br&gt;When Illusions of Grandeur comes into play, you gain 20 life. &lt;br&gt;When Illusions of Grandeur leaves play, you lose 20 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {2}&lt;br&gt;When Illusions of Grandeur comes into play, gain 20 life. When Illusions of Grandeur leaves play, lose 20 life. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2516</id>
  <name>Infuse</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Untap target artifact, creature, or land. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Untap target artifact, creature, or land. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The potential for change lies in all things. Know a thing's nature, know its possibilities, and know it anew."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2517</id>
  <name>Krovikan Sorcerer</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Discard a card: Draw a card. &lt;br&gt;{T}, Discard a black card: Draw two cards, then discard one of them.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Choose and discard a card from your hand to draw a card. If the card discarded was black, draw two cards instead of one; keep one and discard the other.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"These Sorcerers always seem to have another surprise up their sleeves."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2518</id>
  <name>Magus of the Unseen</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{U}, {T}: Untap target artifact an opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. If it's an artifact creature, it gains haste until end of turn. When you lose control of the artifact, tap it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{U},{T}: Untap target artifact opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. If that artifact is an artifact creature, it can attack, and you may use any of its abilities that require {T} as part of the activation cost. When you lose control of the artifact, tap it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2519</id>
  <name>Mesmeric Trance</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;{U}, Discard a card: Draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;{U}: Discard a card from your hand to draw a card.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Magic overused can freeze the mind. Creativity is more important than power."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2520</id>
  <name>Mistfolk</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{U}: Counter target spell that targets Mistfolk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{U}: Counter target spell that targets Mistfolk.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Although my official log will state there is no evidence pointing to the existence of the Mistfolk, my certainty is lessened by the cursed consistency of the expedition's eyewitness accounts."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2521</id>
  <name>Musician</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature gains "At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy this creature unless you pay {1}." (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;{T}: Put a music counter on target creature. During that creature's controller's upkeep, he or she pays {1} for each music counter on the creature, or destroy the creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2522</id>
  <name>Mystic Might</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land you control &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {1}{U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}{U}&lt;br&gt;When Mystic Might comes into play, choose target land you control.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Tap land Mystic Might enchants to give target creature +2/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2523</id>
  <name>Mystic Remora</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} &lt;br&gt;Whenever an opponent plays a noncreature spell, you may draw a card unless that player pays {4}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;Whenever target opponent successfully casts a non-creature spell, you may draw a card. That player may pay {4} to counter this effect.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2524</id>
  <name>Phantasmal Mount</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion Horse</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature you control with toughness 2 or less gets +1/+1 and gains flying until end of turn. When Phantasmal Mount leaves play this turn, sacrifice that creature. When the creature leaves play this turn, sacrifice Phantasmal Mount.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature you control, which has toughness less than 3, gains flying and gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Other effects may later be used to increase that creature's toughness beyond 3. If Phantasmal Mount leaves play before end of turn, bury the creature. If the creature leaves play before end of turn, bury Phantasmal Mount.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2525</id>
  <name>Polar Kraken</name>
  <cost>{8}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kraken</type>
  <power>11</power>
  <toughness>11</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Polar Kraken comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep-Sacrifice a land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Cumulative Upkeep: Sacrifice a land.&lt;br&gt;Comes into play tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It was big. Really, really, big. No, bigger than that. It was big"&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>11</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2526</id>
  <name>Portent</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at the top three cards of target player's library, then put them back in any order. You may have that player shuffle his or her library. &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Look at the top three cards of target player's library; then, either shuffle that library or put those three cards on top of the library in any order. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2527</id>
  <name>Power Sink</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {X}. If he or she doesn't, that player taps all lands he or she controls and empties his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell unless that spell's caster pays an additional {X}. That player must draw and pay all available mana from lands and mana pool until {X} is paid; he or she may also pay mana from other sources if desired.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2528</id>
  <name>Ray of Command</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Untap target creature an opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature gains haste until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;When you lose control of the creature, tap it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Untap target creature opponent controls and gain control of it until end of turn. That creature can attack or use abilities that require {T} as part of the activation cost. When you lose control of the creature, tap it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2529</id>
  <name>Ray of Erasure</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard. &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player takes the top card of his or her library and puts it in his or her graveyard. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What is real can be unreal."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2530</id>
  <name>Reality Twist</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>James Ernest</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1}{U}{U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;If tapped for mana, Plains produce {R}, Swamps produce {G}, Mountains produce {W}, and Forests produce {B} instead of any other type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}{U}{U}&lt;br&gt;Instead of their normal mana, plains produce {R}, swamps produce {G}, mountains produce {W}, and forests produce {B}.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Nothing is as it seems."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2531</id>
  <name>Sea Spirit</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>{U}: Sea Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{U}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It rose above our heads, above the ship, and still higher yet. No foggy, ice-laden sea in the world could frighten me more."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2532</id>
  <name>Shyft</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may have Shyft become the color or colors of your choice. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, you may change the color of Shyft to any color or combination of colors.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Capturing this specimen was not easy. Study it well, that you someday might be as versatile."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2533</id>
  <name>Sibilant Spirit</name>
  <cost>{5}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Whenever Sibilant Spirit attacks, defending player may draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Whenever Sibilant Spirit is declared as an attacker, defending player may draw a card.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Relax. I'm sure it's just a snake hissing."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2534</id>
  <name>Silver Erne</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, trample</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, trample</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I've seen a larger Erne knock a Giant to the ground and stay airborne. They move not with the wind, but as the wind."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2535</id>
  <name>Sleight of Mind</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. (For example, you may change "target black spell" to "target blue spell.") (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another. For example, you may change "Counters black spells" to "Counters blue spells." Sleight of Mind cannot change mana symbols.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2536</id>
  <name>Snow Devil</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has flying. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has first strike as long as it's blocking and you control a snow land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains flying. As long as you control any snow-covered lands, that creature also gains first strike when blocking.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Give me wings to fly and speed to strike. In return, the glory I earn shall be yours."Steinar Icefist, Balduvian Shaman</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2537</id>
  <name>Snowfall</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {U} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever an Island is tapped for mana, its controller may add {U} to his or her mana pool. If that Island is snow, its controller may add {U}{U} to his or her mana pool instead. Spend this mana only to pay for cumulative upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {U}&lt;br&gt;Islands may produce an additional {U} when tapped for mana. This mana is usable only for cumulative upkeep.&lt;br&gt;Snow-covered islands may produce either an additional {U}{U} or an additional {U} when tapped for mana. This mana is usable only for cumulative upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2538</id>
  <name>Soldevi Machinist</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard Artificer</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to play activated abilities of artifacts.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add two colorless mana to your mana pool. This mana may only be used to pay the activation cost of an artifact. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Perhaps this time the power of the artificers shall be used wisely." &lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2539</id>
  <name>Soul Barrier</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent plays a creature spell, Soul Barrier deals 2 damage to that player unless he or she pays {2}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever target opponent casts a summon spell, Soul Barrier deals 2 damage to him or her. That player may pay {2} to prevent this damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There's more than one way to skin an Ouphe--or thwart a mage."&lt;br&gt;--Gustha Ebbasdotter,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Royal Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2540</id>
  <name>Thunder Wall</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Flying &lt;br&gt;{U}: Thunder Wall gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{U}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Lemures had barely taken wing when the sky roared with thunder. The swarm of little beasts wavered, divided, and fell, crashing to the earth."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2541</id>
  <name>Updraft</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gains flying until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains flying until end of turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The power of flight has but one equal in battle: surprise. Understanding how to use both is the key to victory."&lt;br&gt;--Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2542</id>
  <name>Wind Spirit</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Wind Spirit can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Cannot be blocked by only one creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"To visit the sky requires bravery, and thought, and little else. To master the sky requires the binding of its masters, and little else."&lt;br&gt;--Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2543</id>
  <name>Winter's Chill</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Winter's Chill only during combat before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt;X can't be greater than the number of snow lands you control. &lt;br&gt;Destroy X target attacking creatures at end of combat. For each attacking creature, its controller may pay {1} or {2} to prevent this effect. If that player pays only {1} for that creature, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cast only during combat before defense is chosen. At end of combat, destroy X target attacking creatures; X cannot be greater than the number of snow-covered lands you control. For each attacking creature, its controller may pay {1} or {2} to prevent it from being destroyed in this way. If that player pays {1}, the creature neither deals nor receives damage in combat. If that player pays {2}, the creature deals and receives damage in combat as normal.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2544</id>
  <name>Word of Undoing</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Return target creature and all white Auras you own attached to it to their owners' hands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Return target creature to owner's hand. Return any white enchantments you own on that creature to your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It was in Urza's journals that I finally found the secret at the core of the summonings."&lt;br&gt;--Journal, author unknown</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2545</id>
  <name>Wrath of Marit Lage</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>When Wrath of Marit Lage comes into play, tap all red creatures.&lt;br&gt;Red creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Wrath of Marit Lage comes into play, tap all red creatures. Red creatures do not untap during their controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Dread Marit Lage lies dreaming, not dead.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2546</id>
  <name>Zur's Weirding</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Players play with their hands revealed. &lt;br&gt;If a player would draw a card, he or she reveals it instead. Then any other player may pay 2 life. If a player does, put that card into its owner's graveyard. Otherwise, that player draws a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players play with the cards in their hands face up on the table. Whenever any player draws a card, any other player may pay 2 life to force the drawing player to discard that card. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2547</id>
  <name>Zuran Enchanter</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Play this ability only during your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{B},{T}: Target player chooses and discards one card from his or her hand. Ignore this ability if that player has no cards in his or her hand. Use this ability only during your turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We are Kjeldorans no more."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2548</id>
  <name>Zuran Spellcaster</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Zuran Spellcaster deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Zuran Spellcaster deals 1 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A mage must be precise as well as potent; cautious, as well as clever."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2549</id>
  <name>Aurochs</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Aurochs</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Whenever Aurochs attacks, it gets +1/+0 until end of turn for each other attacking Aurochs.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;When attacking, Aurochs gets +1/+0 for each other Aurochs that attacks.</printedText>
  <flavorText>One Auroch may feed a village, but a herd will flatten it.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2550</id>
  <name>Balduvian Bears</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bear</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"They're a hardy bunch, but I'd still bet that they just slept through the worst of the cold times."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2551</id>
  <name>Blizzard</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Blizzard only if you control a snow land. &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Creatures with flying don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {2}&lt;br&gt;You cannot cast Blizzard if you control no snow-covered lands. Creatures with flying do not untap during their controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2552</id>
  <name>Brown Ouphe</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ouphe</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{G}, {T}: Counter target activated ability from an artifact source. (Mana abilities can't be targeted.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{G},{T}: Counter target artifact ability requiring an activation cost. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Ouphes love trinkets and love to take them apart. I only wish they wouldn't do so with the magical ones."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2553</id>
  <name>Chub Toad</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Frog</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Chub Toad blocks or becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Chub Toad gets +2/+2 until end of turn when blocking or blocked.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Chub Toad, Chub Toad&lt;br&gt;At the door.&lt;br&gt;Run away quick&lt;br&gt;Or you'll run no more.&lt;br&gt;--Traditional children's rhyme</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2554</id>
  <name>Dire Wolves</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolf</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Dire Wolves has banding as long as you control a Plains.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gains banding if you control any plains.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It's amazing how scared a city kid can get at a dog. Now, of course, I'd cross Terisiare alone, and keep no watch if I had a pack of greys hanging on my flanks as I went."&lt;br&gt;--Oddveig Ulfsson, caravan scout</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2555</id>
  <name>Earthlore</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land you control &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{T}: Target blocking creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn."</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Earthlore comes into play, choose target land you control.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Tap land Earthlore enchants to give target blocking creature +1/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Even the ground is our friend."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2556</id>
  <name>Elder Druid</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Cleric Druid</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}{G}, {T}: You may tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}{G},{T}: Tap or untap target artifact, creature, or land.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I am older than any Elder Druid before me, and still no child has been born with the Mark to take my place. When will the wheel turn?"&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2557</id>
  <name>Essence Filter</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Destroy all enchantments; or destroy all nonwhite enchantments.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all enchantments or destroy all non-white enchantments.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Freyalise has cleansed our bodies and minds of the plagues of Kjeldor; all she asks in return is that we keep pure our newly given home in Fyndhorn." &lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2558</id>
  <name>Fanatical Fever</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +3/+0 and gains trample until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains trample and gets +3/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let go your fury, and hone your anger. Become the fist of Freyalise"&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2559</id>
  <name>Folk of the Pines</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dryad</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas & Catherine Buck</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{G}: Folk of the Pines gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{G}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Our friends of the forest take many forms, yet all serve the will of Freyalise."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2560</id>
  <name>Forbidden Lore</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land you control &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{T}: Target creature gets +2/+1 until end of turn."</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Forbidden Lore comes into play, choose target land.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Tap land Forbidden Lore enchants to give target creature +2/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2561</id>
  <name>Forgotten Lore</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Target opponent chooses a card in your graveyard. You may pay {G}. If you do, repeat this process except that opponent can't choose a card already chosen for Forgotten Lore. Then put the last chosen card into your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target opponent chooses target card from your graveyard. You may pay {G} to have that opponent choose a new target that he or she has not already chosen. Put the last target card in your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>In ashes are the gems of history.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2562</id>
  <name>Foxfire</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>Untap target attacking creature. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by that creature this turn. &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Untap target attacking creature. That creature neither receives nor deals damage in combat this turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Only the foolish fear Foxfire."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2563</id>
  <name>Freyalise Supplicant</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth & Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice a red or white creature: Freyalise Supplicant deals damage to target creature or player equal to half the sacrificed creature's power, rounded down.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice a red or white creature to have Freyalise Supplicant deal an amount of damage equal to half the creature's power, rounded down, to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We have joined with the Druids of the Juniper Order. Our faith is one."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2564</id>
  <name>Freyalise's Charm</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent plays a black spell, you may pay {G}{G}. If you do, you draw a card. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{G}{G}: Return Freyalise's Charm to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}{G}: When any opponent successfully casts a black spell, draw a card. Use this ability only once each time a black spell is cast.&lt;br&gt;{G}{G}: Return Freyalise's Charm to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2565</id>
  <name>Freyalise's Winds</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a permanent becomes tapped, put a wind counter on it. That permanent gains "This permanent doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a wind counter on it" and "At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a wind counter from this permanent."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever a permanent becomes tapped, put a wind counter on it. Permanents with any wind counters on them do not untap during their controller's untap phase; instead, remove all wind counters from those permanents.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2566</id>
  <name>Fyndhorn Brownie</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ouphe</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{G}, {T}: Untap target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{G},{T}: Untap target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I've been insulted by drunks in a hundred inns, but never as skillfully or annoyingly as by those blasted Brownies."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2567</id>
  <name>Fyndhorn Elder</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G}{G} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Do we know what we're doing? Yes--the will of Freyalise."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2568</id>
  <name>Fyndhorn Elves</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Living side by side with the Elves for so long leaves me with no doubt that we serve the same goddess."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2569</id>
  <name>Fyndhorn Pollen</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;All creatures get -1/-0. &lt;br&gt;{1}{G}: All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;All creatures get -1/-0.&lt;br&gt;{1}{G}: All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I breathed deeply, and suddenly I knew not who or where I was."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2570</id>
  <name>Giant Growth</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +3/+3 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Here in Fyndhorn, the goddess Freyalise is generous to her children."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2571</id>
  <name>Gorilla Pack</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ape</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Gorilla Pack can't attack unless defending player controls a Forest. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;When you control no Forests, sacrifice Gorilla Pack.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gorilla Pack cannot attack if defending player controls no forests. Bury Gorilla Pack if you control no forests.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We learned this at a dear price: once you cross the great river, get through the Yavimaya forest at top speed."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2572</id>
  <name>Hot Springs</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land you control &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn."</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Hot Springs comes into play, choose target land you control.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Tap land Hot Springs enchants to prevent 1 damage to any creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Warmth is life; heat is peace.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2573</id>
  <name>Hurricane</name>
  <cost>{X}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Hurricane deals X damage to each creature with flying and each player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This was quite possibly the least pleasant occurrence on the entire expedition."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2574</id>
  <name>Johtull Wurm</name>
  <cost>{5}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wurm</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Johtull Wurm becomes blocked, it gets -2/-1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For each blocking creature assigned to Johtull Worm beyond the first, Johtull Worm gets -2/-1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"To bring her down we must be on all sides at once--leave one avenue open and we'll all be dead."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2575</id>
  <name>Juniper Order Druid</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Untap target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Untap target land. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The filthy towns of Kjeldor are no place for anyone to live. Fyndhorn is our home now."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2576</id>
  <name>Lhurgoyf</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Lhurgoyf</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>1+*</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Lhurgoyf's power is equal to the number of creature cards in all graveyards and its toughness is equal to that number plus 1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Lhurgoyf has power equal to the total number of creatures in all graveyards and toughness equal to 1 plus the total number of creatures in all graveyards.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Ach Hans, run It's the Lhurgoyf"&lt;br&gt;--Saffi Eriksdotter, last words</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2577</id>
  <name>Lure</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures able to block target creature must do so. Lure does not prevent a creature from blocking more than one creature if blocker has that ability. If blocker is forced to block more creatures than it is allowed to, defender chooses which of these creatures to block, but must block as many creatures as allowed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2578</id>
  <name>Maddening Wind</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {G} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, Maddening Wind deals 2 damage to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {G}&lt;br&gt;During target creature's controller's upkeep, Maddening Wind deals 2 damage to that player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It is Freyalise, walking on the world."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2579</id>
  <name>Nature's Lore</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Search your library for a Forest card and put that card into play. Then shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Search your library for any forest and put it directly into play. This does not count towards your one land per turn limit. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Fyndhorn is our home."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2580</id>
  <name>Pale Bears</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bear</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Islandwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Islandwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Daughter, on the day you have killed your Pale Bear, then will I give you your true name."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2581</id>
  <name>Pygmy Allosaurus</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Lizard</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I don't understand the appeal of keeping these things as pets, unless you want your children eaten."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2582</id>
  <name>Pyknite</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ouphe</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward P. Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>When Pyknite comes into play, draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Draw a card at the beginning of the upkeep of the turn after Pyknite comes into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Never cross a Pyknite, if you value your scalp."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2583</id>
  <name>Regeneration</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate enchanted creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Regeneration comes into play, choose target creature.&lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate creature Regeneration enchants.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Faith in Freyalise has given me the gift, not the curse, of unprecedented longevity."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2584</id>
  <name>Rime Dryad</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dryad</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Snow forestwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Snow-covered forestwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Dryads told us to stay, as no new horrors would come when it was so cold. Three of us left anyway. The rest believed their lies, and their skeletons weren't found until the thaw."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2585</id>
  <name>Ritual of Subdual</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;If tapped for mana, lands produce colorless mana instead of any other type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {2}&lt;br&gt;All mana-producing lands produce colorless mana instead of their normal mana.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"That which does not bend to the will of Freyalise shall surely break."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2586</id>
  <name>Scaled Wurm</name>
  <cost>{7}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wurm</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"Flourishing during the Ice Age, these Wurms were the bane of all Kjeldorans. Their great size and ferocity made them the subject of countless nightmares--they embodied the worst of the Ice Age."&lt;br&gt;--Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2587</id>
  <name>Shambling Strider</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Yeti</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}{G}: Shambling Strider gets +1/-1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}{G}: +1/-1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>Freyalise forbid that any stranger should wander into the Striders' territory.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2588</id>
  <name>Snowblind</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets -X/-Y. If that creature is attacking, X is the number of snow lands defending player controls. Otherwise, X is the number of snow lands its controller controls. Y is equal to X or to enchanted creature's toughness minus 1, whichever is smaller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets -*/-*. When that creature attacks, * is equal to the number of snow-covered lands defending player controls. At other times, * is equal to the number of snow-covered lands its controller controls. If this reduces the creature's toughness to less than 1, the creature's toughness is 1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2589</id>
  <name>Stampede</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Attacking creatures get +1/+0 and gain trample until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All attacking creatures gain trample and get +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We could see the horizon blacken with the great beasts, but it was too late. The icefield offered no immediate safety, but luckily most of us reached a crevasse in which we could take cover."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2590</id>
  <name>Stunted Growth</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Target player chooses three cards from his or her hand and puts them on top of his or her library in any order.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player chooses three cards from his or her hand and puts them on top of his or her library in any order. If that player does not have enough cards in hand, his or her entire hand is put on top of his or her library in any order.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2591</id>
  <name>Tarpan</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horse</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>When Tarpan is put into a graveyard from play, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Tarpan is put into the graveyard from play, gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A good Tarpan will serve you, faithful and true. A bad one will kick you in the head."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2592</id>
  <name>Thermokarst</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target land. If that land was a snow land, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target land. If that land is a snow-covered land, gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Finally we understand the lesson of our home: loss begets renewal."&lt;br&gt;--Kolbjorn, Elder Druid of the Juniper Order</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2593</id>
  <name>Thoughtleech</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an Island an opponent controls becomes tapped, you may gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever an island controlled by target opponent becomes tapped, gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A resourceful mage has many sources of information. The best one is your foe."&lt;br&gt;--Zur the Enchanter</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2594</id>
  <name>Tinder Wall</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Plant Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Sacrifice Tinder Wall: Add {R}{R} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{R}, Sacrifice Tinder Wall: Tinder Wall deals 2 damage to target creature it's blocking.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Sacrifice Tinder Wall to add {R}{R} to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.&lt;br&gt;{R}: Sacrifice Tinder Wall to have it deal 2 damage to target creature it blocks.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2595</id>
  <name>Touch of Vitae</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gains haste and "{0}: Untap this creature. Play this ability only once." until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature may untap one additional time this turn. That creature may attack or use abilities that require {T} as part of the activation cost this turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2596</id>
  <name>Trailblazer</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature is unblockable this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Our Elvish Hunter Taaveti led us swiftly along hidden paths through the dense forest. We caught the Orcs from behind, and completely by surprise."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2597</id>
  <name>Venomous Breath</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of combat, destroy all creatures that blocked or were blocked by target creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At end of combat, destroy all creatures blocking or blocked by target creature this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2598</id>
  <name>Wall of Pine Needles</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Plant Wall</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate Wall of Pine Needles.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>The power of the forest takes a hundred forms. Some are more surprising than others.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2599</id>
  <name>Whiteout</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures lose flying until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;Sacrifice a snow land: Return Whiteout from your graveyard to your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures with flying lose flying until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;If Whiteout is in your graveyard, you may sacrifice a snow-covered land to return Whiteout to your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2600</id>
  <name>Wiitigo</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Yeti</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>0</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Wiitigo comes into play with six +1/+1 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, put a +1/+1 counter on Wiitigo if it has blocked or been blocked since your last upkeep. Otherwise, remove a +1/+1 counter from it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Wiitigo comes into play, put six +1/+1 counters on it.&lt;br&gt;During your upkeep, put a +1/+1 counter on Wiitigo if it has blocked or been blocked since your last upkeep. Otherwise, remove a +1/+1 counter from Wiitigo. Ignore this effect if there are no counters left on Wiitigo.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2601</id>
  <name>Wild Growth</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted land is tapped for mana, its controller adds {G} to his or her mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Wild Growth adds {G} to your mana pool whenever target land is tapped for mana.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Here in Fyndhorn, where Freyalise's power is strongest, the forest has its own opinion."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2602</id>
  <name>Woolly Mammoths</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elephant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Woolly Mammoths has trample as long as you control a snow land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gains trample as long as you control any snow-covered lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Mammoths may be good to ride on, but they're certainly bad to fall off of"&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2603</id>
  <name>Woolly Spider</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spider</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever Woolly Spider blocks a creature with flying, Woolly Spider gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Can block creatures with flying.&lt;br&gt;If Woolly Spider is assigned to block a creature with flying, Woolly Spider gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We need not fear the forces of the air; I've yet to see a Spider without an appetite."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2604</id>
  <name>Yavimaya Gnats</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate Yavimaya Gnats.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}: Regenerate</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It is our third day of travel on the Yavimaya River, and still these creatures plague us. Davin Lansson, our naturalist, has facetiously labeled them --'gnats,' and the name has stuck."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2605</id>
  <name>Aggression</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant non-Wall creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has first strike and trample. &lt;br&gt;At the end of enchanted creature's controller's turn, destroy that creature if it didn't attack this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target non-wall creature gains first strike and trample. At the end of its controller's turn, destroy that creature if it did not attack that turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The star that burns twice as bright burns half as long.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2606</id>
  <name>Anarchy</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all white permanents.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy all white permanents.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Shaman waved the staff, and the land itself went mad."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2607</id>
  <name>Avalanche</name>
  <cost>{X}{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy X target snow lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy X target snow-covered lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The pass was completely blocked by the avalanche; we're forced to turn back. Nevertheless, we've gone farther and seen more than any before us."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2608</id>
  <name>Balduvian Barbarians</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Barbarian</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"Barbarian raids were a concern to those living in the northwest provinces, but the Skyknights never dealt with the problem in a systematic way. They thought of the Balduvians as an --'amusing model' of their forebears' culture."&lt;br&gt;--Kjeldor: Ice Civilization</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2609</id>
  <name>Balduvian Hydra</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Hydra</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Balduvian Hydra comes into play with X +1/+0 counters on it. &lt;br&gt;Remove a +1/+0 counter from Balduvian Hydra: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Balduvian Hydra this turn. &lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Put a +1/+0 counter on Balduvian Hydra. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Balduvian Hydra comes into play, put X +1/+0 counters on it.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove a +1/+0 counter from Balduvian Hydra to prevent 1 damage to Balduvian Hydra.&lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Put a +1/+0 counter on Balduvian Hydra. Use this ability only during your upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2610</id>
  <name>Barbarian Guides</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Barbarian</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{R}, {T}: Choose a land type. Target creature you control gains snow landwalk of the chosen type until end of turn. Return that creature to its owner's hand at end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{R},{T}: Target creature you control gains a snow-covered landwalk ability of your choice until end of turn. At end of turn, return that creature to its owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2611</id>
  <name>Battle Frenzy</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Green creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Nongreen creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All green creatures you control get +1/+1 until end of turn. All non-green creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"One day you, too, shall drink the blood of your foes. It is something to look forward to."&lt;br&gt;--Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2612</id>
  <name>Bone Shaman</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant Shaman</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: Until end of turn, Bone Shaman gains "Creatures dealt damage by Bone Shaman this turn can't be regenerated this turn."</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Any creature damaged by Bone Shaman this turn cannot regenerate until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Rattle me bones as I cross the floor &lt;br&gt;And the bones in your grave will rattle no more.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2613</id>
  <name>Brand of Ill Omen</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Cumulative upkeep {R} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature's controller can't play creature spells.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {R}&lt;br&gt;Target creature's controller cannot cast summon spells.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let those who bear the brand receive no shelter, no kindness, and no comfort from our people."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2614</id>
  <name>Chaos Lord</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike, haste &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if the number of permanents is even, that player gains control of Chaos Lord. &lt;br&gt;When Chaos Lord comes into play, it loses haste until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;Chaos Lord can attack the first turn it comes into play on a side, except the turn it first comes into play. During your upkeep, count the number of permanents. If that number is even, target opponent gains control of Chaos Lord.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2615</id>
  <name>Chaos Moon</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each upkeep, count the number of permanents. If the number is odd, until end of turn, red creatures get +1/+1 and whenever a player taps a Mountain for mana, that player adds {R} to his or her mana pool. If the number is even, until end of turn, red creatures get -1/-1 and if a player taps a Mountain for mana, that Mountain produces colorless mana instead of any other type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During each player's upkeep, count the number of permanents. If that number is odd, all red creatures get +1/+1 and mountains produce an additional {R} when tapped for mana until end of turn. If the number is even, all red creatures get -1/-1 and mountains produce colorless mana instead of their normal mana until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2616</id>
  <name>Conquer</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;You control enchanted land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain control of target land.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Why do we trade with those despicable Elves? You don't live in forests, you burn them"&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2617</id>
  <name>Curse of Marit Lage</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>When Curse of Marit Lage comes into play, tap all Islands. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Islands don't untap during their controllers' untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Curse of Marit Lage comes into play, tap all islands. Islands do not untap during their controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Our world has not felt her thundering steps in lifetimes, but Marit Lage's presence is still with us."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2618</id>
  <name>Dwarven Armory</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, Sacrifice a land: Put a +2/+2 counter on target creature. Play this ability only during any upkeep step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Sacrifice a land to put a +2/+2 counter on target creature. Use this ability only during upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Few of us left, now. Confounded Yeti have opened all the vents. We'd best hide here with the weapons."&lt;br&gt;--Perena Deepcutter,&lt;br&gt;Dwarven Armorer</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2619</id>
  <name>Errantry</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +3/+0 and can only attack alone.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +3/+0. If that creature attacks, no other creatures can attack this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There is no shame in solitude. The lone Knight may succeed where a hundred founder."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2620</id>
  <name>Flame Spirit</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}: Flame Spirit gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The spirit of the flame is the spirit of change."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2621</id>
  <name>Flare</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Flare deals 1 damage to target creature or player. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flare deals 1 damage to target creature or player. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I strive for elegance and speed in my work."&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2622</id>
  <name>Game of Chaos</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Flip a coin. If you win the flip, you gain 1 life and target opponent loses 1 life, and you decide whether to flip again. If you lose the flip, you lose 1 life and that opponent gains 1 life, and that player decides whether to flip again. Double the life stakes with each flip.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flip a coin; target opponent calls heads or tails while coin is in the air. If the flip ends up in your favor, you gain 1 life and that opponent loses 1 life. Otherwise, you lose 1 life and the opponent gains 1 life. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life. The winner of each round decides whether to continue. Double the stakes in life each round.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2623</id>
  <name>Glacial Crevasses</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>Sacrifice a snow Mountain: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Sacrifice a snow-covered mountain. No creatures deal damage in combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We were chasing Lim-Dul when the ridge in front of us suddenly crumbled. I can't believe it was mere coincidence."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2624</id>
  <name>Goblin Mutant</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin Mutant</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Goblin Mutant can't attack if defending player controls an untapped creature with power 3 or greater. &lt;br&gt;Goblin Mutant can't block creatures with power 3 or greater.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Cannot attack if defending player controls an untapped creature with power greater than 2. Cannot be assigned to block any creature with power greater than 2.</printedText>
  <flavorText>If only it had three brains, too.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2625</id>
  <name>Goblin Sappers</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature you control is unblockable this turn. Destroy it and Goblin Sappers at end of combat. &lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature you control is unblockable this turn. Destroy it at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}{R},{T}: Target creature you control cannot be blocked this turn. At end of combat, destroy that creature and Goblin Sappers.&lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}{R},{T}: Target creature you control cannot be blocked this turn. At end of combat, destroy that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2626</id>
  <name>Goblin Ski Patrol</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{R}: Goblin Ski Patrol gets +2/+0 and gains flying until end of turn. Destroy it at end of turn. It can't be regenerated. Play this ability only once and only if you control a snow Mountain.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{R}: Flying and +2/+0. At end of turn, bury Goblin Ski Patrol. Use this ability only once and only if you control any snow-covered mountains.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"AIIIEEEE"&lt;br&gt;--Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2627</id>
  <name>Goblin Snowman</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goblin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Goblin Snowman blocks, prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by it this turn. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Goblin Snowman deals 1 damage to target creature it's blocking.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When blocking, Goblin Snowman neither deals nor receives damage in combat.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Goblin Snowman deals 1 damage to target creature it blocks.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Strength in numbers? Right."&lt;br&gt;--Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2628</id>
  <name>Grizzled Wolverine</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolverine</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Grizzled Wolverine becomes blocked, you may pay {R}. If you do, Grizzled Wolverine gets +2/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: +2/+0 until end of turn. Use this ability only when a creature is assigned to block Grizzled Wolverine and only once each turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Before you release a Woverine from the trap, make sure it's really dead."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2629</id>
  <name>Imposing Visage</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked by only one creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I can't believe they expect me to fight with this rabble. A Goblin in a big mask sends --'em running for cover."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2630</id>
  <name>Incinerate</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Incinerate deals 3 damage to target creature or player. A creature dealt damage this way can't be regenerated this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Incinerate deals 3 damage to target creature or player. No creature damaged by Incinerate can regenerate this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Yes, I think --'toast' is an appropriate description."&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2631</id>
  <name>Jokulhaups</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all artifacts, creatures, and lands. They can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury all artifacts, creatures, and lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I was shocked when I first saw the aftermath of the Yavimaya Valley disaster. The raging waters had swept away trees, bridges, and even houses. My healers had much work to do."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2632</id>
  <name>Karplusan Giant</name>
  <cost>{6}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap an untapped snow land you control: Karplusan Giant gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Tap target snow-covered land you control to give Karplusan Giant +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"They aren't the brightest or the quickest of Giants. For that matter, the same holds true if you compare them to rocks."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2633</id>
  <name>Karplusan Yeti</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Yeti</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Karplusan Yeti deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to Karplusan Yeti.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Karplusan Yeti deals an amount of damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals an amount of damage equal to its power to Karplusan Yeti.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What's that smell?"&lt;br&gt;--Perena Deepcutter,&lt;br&gt;Dwarven Armorer</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2634</id>
  <name>Lava Burst</name>
  <cost>{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Lava Burst deals X damage to target creature or player. If Lava Burst would deal damage to a creature, that damage can't be prevented or dealt instead to another creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Lava Burst deals X damage to target creature or player. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to protect that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Overkill? This isn't a game of Kick-the-Ouphe"&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2635</id>
  <name>Mrton Stromgald</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Mrton Stromgald attacks, other attacking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each attacking creature other than Mrton Stromgald. &lt;br&gt;Whenever Mrton Stromgald blocks, other blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn for each blocking creature other than Mrton Stromgald.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Marton Stromgald attacks, all other attacking creatures get +*/+* until end of turn, where * is equal to the number of other attacking creatures. If Marton blocks, all other blocking creatures get +*/+* until end of turn, where * is equal to the number of other blocking creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2636</id>
  <name>Melee</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Melee only during your combat phase before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt;Instead of defending player, you choose how each creature blocks this turn. &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature attacks and isn't blocked this turn, untap it and remove it from combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cast only on your turn during combat before defense is chosen. Choose how attacking creatures you control are blocked; all defense must be legal. After declaring blocking, untap any unblocked attacking creature. Treat those creatures as though they had not attacked.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2637</id>
  <name>Melting</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>All lands are no longer snow.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All snow-covered lands become non-snow-covered lands of the same type.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Who needs the sun when you've got me around?"&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2638</id>
  <name>Meteor Shower</name>
  <cost>{X}{X}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>Meteor Shower deals X+1 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Meteor Shower deals X+1 damage divided any way you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Eenie, meenie, minie, moe . . . oh, why not all of them?"&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2639</id>
  <name>Mountain Goat</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Goat</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>Mountainwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Mountainwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Folklore has it that to capture a Mountain Goat is a sign of divine blessing. I just know it's a sign that dinner is on the way."&lt;br&gt;--Klazina Jansdotter, Leader of the Order of the Sacred Torch</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2640</id>
  <name>Mudslide</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures without flying don't untap during their controllers' untap steps. &lt;br&gt;Creatures without flying have "At the beginning of your upkeep, you may pay {2}. If you do, untap this creature."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures without flying do not untap during their controller's untap phase. At the end of his or her upkeep, each player may pay an additional {2} per creature to untap a creature without flying he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2641</id>
  <name>Orcish Cannoneers</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc Warrior</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Orcish Cannoneers deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Orcish Cannoneers deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It's a thankless job, and you'll probably die in an explosion. But the pay is pretty good."&lt;br&gt;--Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2642</id>
  <name>Orcish Conscripts</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Orcish Conscripts can't attack unless at least two other creatures attack. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Orcish Conscripts can't block unless at least two other creatures block.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be declared as attacking unless at least two other creatures are also declared as attacking. Cannot be assigned to block unless at least two other creatures are also assigned to block.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2643</id>
  <name>Orcish Farmer</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target land becomes a Swamp until its controller's next untap step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target land becomes a swamp until its controller's next untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Yes, the Farmers keep our soldiers fed. But why do they have to make every battlefield a pigpen?"&lt;br&gt;--Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2644</id>
  <name>Orcish Healer</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}{R}, {T}: Target creature can't be regenerated this turn. &lt;br&gt;{B}{B}{R}, {T}: Regenerate target black or green creature. &lt;br&gt;{R}{G}{G}, {T}: Regenerate target black or green creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}{R},{T}: Target creature cannot regenerate this turn.&lt;br&gt;{R}{B}{B},{T}: Regenerate target black or green creature.&lt;br&gt;{R}{G}{G},{T}: Regenerate target black or green creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2645</id>
  <name>Orcish Librarian</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{R}, {T}: Look at the top eight cards of your library. Remove four of them at random from the game, then put the rest on top of your library in any order.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R},{T}: Take the top eight cards of your library; remove four of them at random from the game. Put the remaining four on top of your library in any order.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Us hungry, need food . . . .&lt;br&gt;Lots of books . . . . Hmm . . . .</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2646</id>
  <name>Orcish Lumberjack</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice a Forest: Add three mana in any combination of {R} and/or {G} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice a forest to add three mana in any combination of red and/or green to your mana pool. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"How did I ever let myself get talked into this project?"&lt;br&gt;--Toothlicker Harj, Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2647</id>
  <name>Orcish Squatters</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Orc</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Orcish Squatters attacks and isn't blocked, you may gain control of target land defending player controls for as long as you control Orcish Squatters. If you do, Orcish Squatters deals no combat damage this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Orcish Squatters attacks and is not blocked, you may gain control of target land controlled by defending player. If you do so, Orcish Squatters deals no damage in combat this turn. Lose control of that land if Orcish Squatters leaves play or if you lose control of Orcish Squatters.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2648</id>
  <name>Panic</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Kimble</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Panic only during combat before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Target creature can't block this turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot block this turn. Cast only during combat before defense is chosen. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"If you'd been there, you would've run from that deer, too"&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2649</id>
  <name>Pyroblast</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Counter target spell if it's blue; or destroy target permanent if it's blue.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target spell if it is blue or destroy target permanent if it is blue.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Just the thing for those pesky water mages."&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2650</id>
  <name>Pyroclasm</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>Pyroclasm deals 2 damage to each creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pyroclasm deals 2 damage to each creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Leaves more room for the big ones to fight in, you know."&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2651</id>
  <name>Sabretooth Tiger</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Cat</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Daughter, it is now your turn to hunt the Tiger, and make a blanket of its fur."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2652</id>
  <name>Shatter</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let the past be the past. Do not call up that which you cannot put down. Destroy that which destroyed us, so long ago."&lt;br&gt;--Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2653</id>
  <name>Stone Rain</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target land.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"May the forces that took Argoth beneath the waves never come among us again."&lt;br&gt;--Arcum Dagsson, Soldevi Machinist</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2654</id>
  <name>Stone Spirit</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Stone Spirit can't be blocked by creatures with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be blocked by creatures with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The spirit of the stone is the spirit of strength."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2655</id>
  <name>Stonehands</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +0/+2. &lt;br&gt;{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +0/+2.&lt;br&gt;{R}: Creature Stonehands enchants gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Trust in the power of stone. Stone is strong; stone shatters swords; stone breaks bones. Trust in stone."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2656</id>
  <name>Tor Giant</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"What do you do then? Run. Run very fast. Don't stop until you see the camp--or a bigger Giant."&lt;br&gt;--Toothlicker Harj,&lt;br&gt;Orcish Captain</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2657</id>
  <name>Total War</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player attacks with one or more creatures, destroy all untapped non-Wall creatures that player controls that didn't attack, except for creatures the player hasn't controlled continuously since the beginning of the turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever any player declares an attack, destroy all untapped non-wall creatures that player controls that don't attack. Do not destroy creatures the player did not control at the beginning of the turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2658</id>
  <name>Vertigo</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>Vertigo deals 2 damage to target creature with flying. That creature loses flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Vertigo deals 2 damage to target creature with flying; that creature loses flying until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I saw the wizard gesturing, but I didn't guess his plan until my Aesthir cried out and went into a dive."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2659</id>
  <name>Wall of Lava</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{R}: Wall of Lava gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}: +1/+1 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Now there's something you don't see every day."&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2660</id>
  <name>Word of Blasting</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target Wall. It can't be regenerated. Word of Blasting deals damage equal to that Wall's converted mana cost to the Wall's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target wall. Word of Blasting deals an amount of damage equal to that wall's casting cost to the wall's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Walls? What walls?"&lt;br&gt;--Jaya Ballard, Task Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2661</id>
  <name>Adarkar Unicorn</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Unicorn</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add either {U} or {1}{U} to your mana pool. Spend this mana only for cumulative upkeep abilities.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add either {U} or {U} and one colorless mana to your mana pool. This mana is usable only for cumulative upkeep. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There is no nobler creature in all of Terisiare."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2662</id>
  <name>Arctic Foxes</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Fox</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with power 2 or greater can't block Arctic Foxes as long as defending player controls a snow land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If defending player controls any snow-covered lands, no creature with power greater than 1 may be assigned to block Arctic Foxes.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Those Foxes are wily, swift, and ferocious. They are the warriors of the snows."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2663</id>
  <name>Arenson's Aura</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>{W}, Sacrifice an enchantment: Destroy target enchantment. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{3}{U}{U}: Counter target enchantment spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}: Sacrifice an enchantment to destroy target enchantment.&lt;br&gt;{3}{U}{U}: Counter target enchantment.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I have my faith, and I have my prayers. But if push comes to shove, I've also got a little something extra."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2664</id>
  <name>Armor of Faith</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+1. &lt;br&gt;{W}: Enchanted creature gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +1/+1.&lt;br&gt;{W}: Creature Armor of Faith enchants gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Keep your chainmail, warrior. I have my own form of protection."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2665</id>
  <name>Battle Cry</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Untap all white creatures you control. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature blocks this turn, it gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Untap all white creatures you control. Any creature that blocks this turn gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"In the thick of battle, you must keep your wits about you. Yelling a lot helps, too."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2666</id>
  <name>Black Scarab</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked by black creatures. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a black permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2 as long as any opponent controls any black cards. That creature cannot be blocked by black creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2667</id>
  <name>Blessed Wine</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>You gain 1 life. &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Gain 1 life. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"May the bounty of Kjeld enrich your days."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2668</id>
  <name>Blinking Spirit</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>{0}: Return Blinking Spirit to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{0}: Return Blinking Spirit to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Don't look at it Maybe it'll go away"&lt;br&gt;--Ib Halfheart, Goblin Tactician</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2669</id>
  <name>Blue Scarab</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked by blue creatures. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a blue permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2 as long as any opponent controls any blue cards. That creature cannot be blocked by blue creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2670</id>
  <name>Call to Arms</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>As Call to Arms comes into play, choose a color and an opponent. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;White creatures get +1/+1. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;When the chosen color isn't the most common color among permanents the chosen opponent controls, sacrifice Call to Arms.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Choose a color. As long as target opponent controls more cards of that color than any other color, all white creatures get +1/+1. If at any time that opponent does not control more cards of that color than any other color, bury Call to Arms.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2671</id>
  <name>Caribou Range</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land you control &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{W}{W}, {T}: Put a 0/1 white Caribou creature token into play." &lt;br&gt;Sacrifice a Caribou token: You gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Caribou Range comes into play, choose target land you control.&lt;br&gt;{W}{W}: Tap land Caribou Range enchants to put a Caribou token into play. Treat this token as a 0/1 white creature.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Sacrifice a Caribou token to gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2672</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Black</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a black source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one black source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2673</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Blue</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a blue source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one blue source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2674</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Green</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a green source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one green source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2675</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: Red</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one red source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2676</id>
  <name>Circle of Protection: White</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: The next time a white source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: Prevent all damage against you from one white source. If a source deals damage to you more than once in a turn, you may pay {1} each time to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2677</id>
  <name>Cold Snap</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {2} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Cold Snap deals damage to that player equal to the number of snow lands he or she controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {2}&lt;br&gt;During each player's upkeep, Cold Snap deals 1 damage to that player for each snow-covered land he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Who knows from whence the winter comes?</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2678</id>
  <name>Cooperation</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has banding.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains banding.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Elves train our healers, and we keep the Orcs at bay. Most Elvish bargains aren't as fair."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2679</id>
  <name>Death Ward</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Regenerate target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Regenerate target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sometimes, a soul is not ready to complete its journey to the next world."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson,&lt;br&gt;Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2680</id>
  <name>Disenchant</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target artifact or enchantment.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I implore you not to forget the horrors of the past. You would have us start the Brothers' War anew"&lt;br&gt;--Sorine Relicbane, Soldevi Heretic</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2681</id>
  <name>Drought</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Drought unless you pay {W}{W}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;As an additional cost to play spells with {B} in their mana costs and activated abilities with {B} in their activation costs, that spell or ability's controller sacrifices a Swamp for each {B} in that cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {W}{W} or destroy Drought. Before a spell that requires {B} as part of its casting cost may be cast or an ability that requires {B} as part of its activation cost may be played, the controller of that spell or ability sacrifices a swamp for each {B} in the spell's casting cost or the ability's activation cost.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2682</id>
  <name>Elvish Healer</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rick Emond</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn. If that creature is green, prevent the next 2 damage instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Prevent 1 damage to any non-green creature or any player or up to 2 damage to any green creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Kjeldorans keep the Orcs at bay and we train their healers. Most human bargains aren't as fair."&lt;br&gt;--Laina of the Elvish Council</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2683</id>
  <name>Enduring Renewal</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Play with your hand revealed. &lt;br&gt;If you would draw a card, reveal the top card of your library instead. If it's a creature card, put it into your graveyard. Otherwise, draw a card. &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature is put into your graveyard from play, return it to your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Play with the cards in your hand face up on the table. If you draw a creature card from your library, discard it. Whenever a creature goes to your graveyard from play, put that creature into your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>That which lasts longest serves best.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2684</id>
  <name>Energy Storm</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt by instant and sorcery spells. &lt;br&gt;Creatures with flying don't untap during their controller's untap step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;Damage dealt by instants, interrupts, and sorceries is reduced to 0.&lt;br&gt;Creatures with flying do not untap during their controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2685</id>
  <name>Formation</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ken Meyer, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gains banding until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains banding until end of turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I have been a warrior for over four hundred years, and yet each generation of Kjeldorans teaches me new tricks. There can be no better allies."&lt;br&gt;--Taaveti of Kelsinko, Elvish Hunter</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2686</id>
  <name>Fylgja</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward P. Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Fylgja comes into play with four healing counters on it. &lt;br&gt;Remove a healing counter from Fylgja: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature this turn. &lt;br&gt;{2}{W}: Put a healing counter on Fylgja.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Fylgja comes into play, put four healing counters on it.&lt;br&gt;{0}: Remove a healing counter from Fylgja to prevent 1 damage to creature Fylgja enchants.&lt;br&gt;{2}{W}: Put a healing counter on Fylgja.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2687</id>
  <name>General Jarkeld</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Switch the blocking creatures of two target attacking creatures. Play this ability only during the declare blockers step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Switch the blocking creatures of two target attacking creatures; all defense must remain legal. Use this ability only during combat after defense is chosen and before damage is dealt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2688</id>
  <name>Green Scarab</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked by green creatures. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a green permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2 as long as any opponent controls any green cards. That creature cannot be blocked by green creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2689</id>
  <name>Hallowed Ground</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{W}{W}: Return target nonsnow land you control to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}{W}: Return target non-snow-covered land you control to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"On this site where Kjeld's blood was spilled, let none raise a fist or deny a beggar."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2690</id>
  <name>Heal</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Prevent 1 damage to any creature or player. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sometimes even the smallest boon can save a life."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2691</id>
  <name>Hipparion</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horse</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Hipparion can't block creatures with power 3 or greater unless you pay {1}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be assigned to block a creature with power 3 or greater unless you pay an additional {1}.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Someone once said that Hipparions are to Warriors what Aesthir are to Skyknights. Don't believe it."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2692</id>
  <name>Justice</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Justice unless you pay {W}{W}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Whenever a red creature or spell deals damage, Justice deals that much damage to that creature's or spell's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {W}{W} or destroy Justice. Whenever a red creature or spell deals damage, Justice deals an equal amount of damage to the controller of that creature or spell. If another spell or effect reduces the amount of damage a red creature or spell deals, it does not reduce the amount of damage dealt by Justice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2693</id>
  <name>Kelsinko Ranger</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{W}: Target green creature gains first strike until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{W}: Target green creature gains first strike until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Rangers not trained by the Elves just aren't the same."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2694</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Elite Guard</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. When that creature leaves play this turn, sacrifice Kjeldoran Elite Guard. Play this ability only during combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn. If that creature leaves play this turn, bury Kjeldoran Elite Guard. Use this ability only when attack or defense is announced.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The winged helms of the Guard are put on for pageants--but taken off for war.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2695</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Guard</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. When that creature leaves play this turn, sacrifice Kjeldoran Guard. Play this ability only during combat and only if defending player controls no snow lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn. If that creature leaves play this turn, bury Kjeldoran Guard. Use this ability only when attack or defense is announced and only if defending player controls no snow-covered lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2696</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Knight</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ron Spencer</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding &lt;br&gt;{1}{W}: Kjeldoran Knight gets +1/+0 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{W}{W}: Kjeldoran Knight gets +0/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding&lt;br&gt;{1}{W}: +1/+0 until end of turn&lt;br&gt;{W}{W}: +0/+2 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Those who do not ride the wind on Aesthir still command loyalty and respect."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2697</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Phalanx</name>
  <cost>{5}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding, first strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There's nothing I like better than watching a street full of soldiers kicking down the doors of the guilty and the impure."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2698</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Royal Guard</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: All combat damage that would be dealt to you by unblocked creatures this turn is dealt to Kjeldoran Royal Guard instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Redirect to Kjeldoran Royal Guard all damage dealt to you from unblocked creatures this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Honorable in battle,&lt;br&gt;generous in death."&lt;br&gt;--Motto of the Kjeldoran Royal Guard</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2699</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Skycaptain</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding, flying, first strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding, flying, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"If we do our duty and uphold our honor, Kjeldor shall stand for a thousand years."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2700</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Skyknight</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding, flying, first strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding, flying, first strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"My Aesthir is my most trusted ally. We fight as one and live as one, and we will die as one."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2701</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Warrior</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Give me a thousand such Warriors and I could change the world."&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2702</id>
  <name>Lightning Blow</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gains first strike until end of turn. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains first strike until end of turn. Draw a card at the beginning of the next turn's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"If you do it right, they'll never know what hit them."&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2703</id>
  <name>Lost Order of Jarkeld</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>1+*</power>
  <toughness>1+*</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>As Lost Order of Jarkeld comes into play, choose an opponent. &lt;br&gt;Lost Order of Jarkeld's power and toughness are each equal to 1 plus the number of creatures that opponent controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Lost Order of Jarkeld has power and toughness each equal to 1 plus the number of creatures target opponent controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Let us remember brave Jarkeld and his troops, who perished in the Adarkar Wastes so long ago."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2704</id>
  <name>Mercenaries</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Mercenary</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Cornelius Brudi</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by this creature. Any player may play this ability.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever Mercenaries damages a player, that player may pay {3} to prevent that damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Blasted amateurs Doesn't the queen think we can fight well enough on our own?"&lt;br&gt;--Avram Garrisson, Leader of the Knights of Stromgald</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2705</id>
  <name>Order of the Sacred Torch</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Pay 1 life: Counter target black spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Pay 1 life to destroy target black spell. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life. Play this ability as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2706</id>
  <name>Order of the White Shield</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Ruth Thompson</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from black &lt;br&gt;{W}: Order of the White Shield gains first strike until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{W}{W}: Order of the White Shield gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black&lt;br&gt;{W}: First strike until end of turn&lt;br&gt;{W}{W}: +1/+0 until end of turn</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Shall we turn away a worthy soul because his parents were peasants? I think not."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2707</id>
  <name>Prismatic Ward</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;As Prismatic Ward comes into play, choose a color. &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature by sources of the chosen color.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Prismatic Ward comes into play, choose a color; all damage dealt to target creature by sources of that color is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"These, of all spells, must have common components I can isolate and use."Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2708</id>
  <name>Rally</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All blocking creatures get +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Stand your ground, troops This shall be our finest hour"&lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox, last words</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2709</id>
  <name>Red Scarab</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked by red creatures. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a red permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2 as long as any opponent controls any red cards. That creature cannot be blocked by red creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2710</id>
  <name>Sacred Boon</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent the next 3 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn. At end of turn, put a +0/+1 counter on that creature for each 1 damage prevented this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Prevent up to 3 damage to target creature. At end of turn, put a +0/+1 counter on that creature for each 1 damage prevented by Sacred Boon.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Divine gifts are granted to those who are worthy."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2711</id>
  <name>Seraph</name>
  <cost>{6}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Angel</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature dealt damage by Seraph this turn is put into a graveyard, put that card into play under your control at end of turn. Sacrifice the creature when you lose control of Seraph.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;At the end of a turn in which any creature is damaged by Seraph and put into the graveyard, put that creature directly into play under your control as though it were just summoned. If you lose control of Seraph or if Seraph leaves play, bury the creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2712</id>
  <name>Shield Bearer</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding</printedText>
  <flavorText>"You have almost completed your four years, my son. Soon you shall be a Skyknight."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2713</id>
  <name>Snow Hound</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Hound</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}, {T}: Return Snow Hound and target blue or green creature you control to their owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1},{T}: Return Snow Hound to owner's hand and target blue or green creature you control to owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"If you're starving, eat your horses, your dead, or yourself--but never eat your dog." &lt;br&gt;--General Jarkeld, the Arctic Fox</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2714</id>
  <name>Swords to Plowshares</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove target creature from the game. Its controller gains life equal to its power.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Remove target creature from the game. That creature's controller gains life equal to its power.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The so-called Barbarians will not respect us for our military might--they will respect us for our honor."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2715</id>
  <name>Warning</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target attacking creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target attacking creature deals no damage in combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The folk of the Karplusan Mountains are impossible to ambush."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2716</id>
  <name>White Scarab</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked by white creatures. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 as long as an opponent controls a white permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +2/+2 as long as any opponent controls any white cards. That creature cannot be blocked by white creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2717</id>
  <name>Altar of Bone</name>
  <cost>{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>As an additional cost to play Altar of Bone, sacrifice a creature. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Search your library for a creature card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sacrifice a creature to look through your library for a creature card; put that card into your hand after showing it to all other players. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2718</id>
  <name>Centaur Archer</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Centaur Archer</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Centaur Archer deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Centaur Archer deals 1 damage to target creature with flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Centaurs will kill our Aesthir if they can; they've always been enemies. Destroy the horse-people on sight."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2719</id>
  <name>Chromatic Armor</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;As Chromatic Armor comes into play, choose a color. &lt;br&gt;Chromatic Armor comes into play with a sleight counter on it. &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to enchanted creature by a source of the last chosen color. &lt;br&gt;{X}: Put a sleight counter on Chromatic Armor and choose a color. X is the number of sleight counters on Chromatic Armor.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Chromatic Armor comes into play, put a sleight counter on it and choose a color. Any damage dealt to target creature by a source of that color is reduced to 0.&lt;br&gt;{X}: Put a sleight counter on Chromatic Armor and change the color that it protects against. X is equal to the number of sleight counters on Chromatic Armor.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2720</id>
  <name>Diabolic Vision</name>
  <cost>{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at the top five cards of your library. Put one of them into your hand and the rest on top of your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Look at the top five cards of your library and put one of them into your hand. Put the remaining four on top of your library in any order.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"I have seen the true path. I will not warm myself by the fire--I will become the flame."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2721</id>
  <name>Earthlink</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Earthlink unless you pay {2}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature is put into a graveyard from play, that creature's controller sacrifices a land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {2} or bury Earthlink.&lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature is put into the graveyard from play, that creature's controller sacrifices a land. Ignore this effect if that player controls no lands.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2722</id>
  <name>Elemental Augury</name>
  <cost>{U}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}: Look at the top three cards of target player's library and put them back on top of that player's library in any order.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}: Look at the top three cards of target player's library. Put them on the top of that player's library in any order.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It is the changing of perception that is important."&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2723</id>
  <name>Essence Vortex</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target creature unless its controller pays life equal to its toughness. A creature destroyed this way can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bury target creature. That creature's controller may counter this spell by paying the creature's toughness in life. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Masters who sacrifice for servants will receive the gift of loyalty.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2724</id>
  <name>Fiery Justice</name>
  <cost>{R}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Fiery Justice deals 5 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players. Target opponent gains 5 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Fiery Justice deals 5 damage divided any way you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players. Target opponent gains 5 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The fire of justice burns like nothing else."Lovisa Coldeyes, Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2725</id>
  <name>Fire Covenant</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>As an additional cost to play Fire Covenant, pay X life. &lt;br&gt;Fire Covenant deals X damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Fire Covenant deals X damage, divided any way you choose among any number of target creatures, where X is equal to the amount of life you pay. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2726</id>
  <name>Flooded Woodlands</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Green creatures have "This creature can't attack unless you sacrifice a land."</oracleText>
  <printedText>No green creature can attack unless its controller sacrifices a land whenever that creature attacks.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Freyalise's tears bring life and renewal, though they also bring trouble.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2727</id>
  <name>Fumarole</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Drew Tucker</artist>
  <oracleText>As an additional cost to play Fumarole, pay 3 life. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Destroy target creature and target land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pay 3 life to destroy target creature and target land. Effects that prevent or redirect damage cannot be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Too many of us have died in the explosions that wrack these hills."&lt;br&gt;--Klazina Jansdotter, Leader of the Order of the Sacred Torch</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2728</id>
  <name>Ghostly Flame</name>
  <cost>{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Gallegos</artist>
  <oracleText>Black and/or red permanents and spells are colorless sources of damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Both black and red permanents and spells are considered colorless sources of damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Walk slowly when in the nether world, and seek that which calls."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2729</id>
  <name>Giant Trap Door Spider</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spider</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{R}{G}, {T}: Remove from the game Giant Trap Door Spider and target creature without flying that's attacking you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{R}{G},{T}: Remove from the game target creature, which doesn't have flying and is attacking you, and Giant Trap Door Spider.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"So large and so quiet--a combination best avoided."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2730</id>
  <name>Glaciers</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Glaciers unless you pay {W}{U}. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;All Mountains are Plains.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, pay {W}{U} or destroy Glaciers. All mountains become plains.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Even the highest mountain can be ground to dust."&lt;br&gt;--Lucilde Fiksdotter, Leader of the Order of the White Shield</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2731</id>
  <name>Hymn of Rebirth</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Put target creature card in a graveyard into play under your control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Take target creature from any graveyard and put it directly into play under your control as though it were just summoned.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There will come soft rains, and spring shall be amongst us, a welcome friend."&lt;br&gt;--Halvor Arenson, Kjeldoran Priest</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2732</id>
  <name>Kjeldoran Frostbeast</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Beast</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Kjeldoran Frostbeast blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At end of combat, destroy all creatures blocking or blocked by Kjeldoran Frostbeast.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Two of my Warriors found that the creature was dangerous not only in combat, but also in simple proximity."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2733</id>
  <name>Merieke Ri Berit</name>
  <cost>{W}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Merieke Ri Berit doesn't untap during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target creature as long as you control Merieke Ri Berit. When Merieke Ri Berit leaves play or becomes untapped, destroy that creature. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Does not untap during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target creature. Lose control of that creature if you lose control of Merieke Ri Berit. If Merieke Ri Berit leaves play or becomes untapped, bury the creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2734</id>
  <name>Monsoon</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>At the end of each player's turn, tap all untapped Islands that player controls and Monsoon deals X damage to the player, where X is the number of Islands tapped this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Whenever any island is untapped at the end of its controller's turn, tap it; Monsoon deals 1 damage to that player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"No one in her right mind would venture off the coast of Kjeldor during this season."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2735</id>
  <name>Mountain Titan</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{R}{R}: Until end of turn, whenever you play a black spell, put a +1/+1 counter on Mountain Titan.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{R}{R}: For the rest of the turn, put a +1/+1 counter on Mountain Titan whenever you successfully cast a black spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The Titans claimed to draw strength from the rocks, but I suspect them of some darker allegiance."&lt;br&gt;--Disa the Restless, journal entry</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2736</id>
  <name>Reclamation</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dameon Willich</artist>
  <oracleText>Black creatures have "This creature can't attack unless you sacrifice a land."</oracleText>
  <printedText>No black creature can attack unless its controller sacrifices a land whenever that creature attacks.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"We shall oppose Lim-Dul and his forces by any means necessary, even if the very earth be torn asunder."&lt;br&gt;--Arna Kennerud, Skyknight</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2737</id>
  <name>Skeleton Ship</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Skeleton</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber & Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>When you control no Islands, sacrifice Skeleton Ship. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If at any time you control no islands, bury Skeleton Ship.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The sea gives up her dead as easily as the soil."&lt;br&gt;--Lim-Dul, the Necromancer</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2738</id>
  <name>Spectral Shield</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Margaret Organ-Kean</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +0/+2 and can't be the target of spells.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gets +0/+2. That creature cannot be the target of further spells.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"What can be a stronger shield than concealment? Have you ever defeated an enemy you didn't know existed?"&lt;br&gt;--Gerda Aagesdotter,&lt;br&gt;Archmage of the Unseen</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2739</id>
  <name>Storm Spirit</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{T}: Storm Spirit deals 2 damage to target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{T}: Storm Spirit deals 2 damage to target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Come to us, with your lightning. Come to us, with your thunder. Serve us with your strength, and smite our foes with your power."&lt;br&gt;--Steinar Icefist, Balduvian Shaman</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2740</id>
  <name>Stormbind</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas & Phillip Mosness</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, Discard a card at random: Stormbind deals 2 damage to target creature or player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}: Discard a card at random from your hand to have Stormbind deal 2 damage to target creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Once, our people could call down the storm itself to do our bidding."&lt;br&gt;--Lovisa Coldeyes,&lt;br&gt;Balduvian Chieftain</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2741</id>
  <name>Wings of Aesthir</name>
  <cost>{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 and has flying and first strike.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains flying and first strike and gets +1/+0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"For those of courage, even the sky holds no limit."&lt;br&gt;--Arnjlot Olasson, Sky Mage</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2742</id>
  <name>Snow-Covered Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Snow Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>[B]</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2743</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2744</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2745</id>
  <name>Swamp</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Swamp</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>B</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2746</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2747</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2748</id>
  <name>Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>G</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2749</id>
  <name>Snow-Covered Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Snow Land - Forest</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pat Morrissey</artist>
  <oracleText>[G]</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2750</id>
  <name>Adarkar Wastes</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Raabe</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Adarkar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. Adarkar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. Adarkar Wastes deals 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2751</id>
  <name>Brushland</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Brushland deals 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. Brushland deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Brushland deals 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2752</id>
  <name>Glacial Chasm</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep-Pay 2 life. (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;If Glacial Chasm would come into play, sacrifice a land instead. If you do, put Glacial Chasm into play. If you don't, put it into its owner's graveyard. &lt;br&gt;Skip your combat phase. &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: 2 life&lt;br&gt;When Glacial Chasm comes into play, sacrifice a land. You cannot attack. All damage dealt to you is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2753</id>
  <name>Halls of Mist</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Cumulative upkeep {1} (At the beginning of your upkeep, put an age counter on this permanent, then sacrifice it unless you pay its upkeep cost for each age counter on it.) &lt;br&gt;Creatures that attacked during their controller's last turn can't attack.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cumulative Upkeep: {1}&lt;br&gt;No creature can attack if it attacked during its controller's last turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2754</id>
  <name>Ice Floe</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Ice Floe during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Tap target creature without flying that's attacking you. It doesn't untap during its controller's untap step as long as Ice Floe remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may choose not to untap Ice Floe during your untap phase.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Tap target creature without flying that is attacking you. As long as Ice Floe remains tapped, that creature does not untap during its controller's untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2755</id>
  <name>Karplusan Forest</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Karplusan Forest deals 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Karplusan Forest deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Karplusan Forest deals 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2756</id>
  <name>Land Cap</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>L. A. Williams</artist>
  <oracleText>Land Cap doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Land Cap. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Land Cap.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If there are any depletion counters on Land Cap, it does not untap during your untap phase. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Land Cap.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Land Cap.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Land Cap.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2757</id>
  <name>Lava Tubes</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>Lava Tubes doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Lava Tubes. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Lava Tubes.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If there are any depletion counters on Lava Tubes, it does not untap during your untap phase. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Lava Tubes.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Lava Tubes.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Lava Tubes.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2758</id>
  <name>River Delta</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>River Delta doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from River Delta. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on River Delta.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If there are any depletion counters on River Delta, it does not untap during your untap phase. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from River Delta.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on River Delta.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on River Delta.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2759</id>
  <name>Sulfurous Springs</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool. Sulfurous Springs deals 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Sulfurous Springs deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Sulfurous Springs deals 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2760</id>
  <name>Timberline Ridge</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Timberline Ridge doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Timberline Ridge. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Timberline Ridge.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If there are any depletion counters on Timberline Ridge, it does not untap during your untap phase. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Timberline Ridge.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Timberline Ridge.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Timberline Ridge.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2761</id>
  <name>Underground River</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Underground River deals 1 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. Underground River deals 1 damage to you.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Underground River deals 1 damage to you.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2762</id>
  <name>Veldt</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>Veldt doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a depletion counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Veldt. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Veldt.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If there are any depletion counters on Veldt, it does not untap during your untap phase. At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a depletion counter from Veldt.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Veldt.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Put a depletion counter on Veldt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2763</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2764</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2765</id>
  <name>Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>R</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2766</id>
  <name>Snow-Covered Mountain</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Snow Land - Mountain</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>[R]</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2767</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2768</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2769</id>
  <name>Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>U</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2770</id>
  <name>Snow-Covered Island</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Snow Land - Island</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>[U]</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2771</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2772</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2773</id>
  <name>Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>W</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>2774</id>
  <name>Snow-Covered Plains</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Basic Snow Land - Plains</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Ice Age</edition>
  <rarity>Land</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>[W]</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
</list>
</cards>