<cards>
<name>Legends</name>
<releaseDate>1994-06-01</releaseDate>
<shortname>LE</shortname><list>
<mc>
  <id>1398</id>
  <name>Al-abara's Carpet</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{5}, {T}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you this turn by attacking creatures without flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{5}{T}: Prevents all damage done to you by attacking non-flying creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Al-abara simply laughed and lifted one finger, and the carpet carried her high out of our reach.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1399</id>
  <name>Alchor's Tomb</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Target permanent you control becomes the color of your choice. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Change the color of target permanent you control to a color of your choice. Use counters. Cost to cast, tap, maintain, or use a special ability of card remains unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1400</id>
  <name>Arena of the Ancients</name>
  <cost>{3}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Legendary creatures don't untap during their controllers' untap steps. &lt;br&gt;When Arena of the Ancients comes into play, tap all legendary creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All legends become tapped when Arena comes into play. Legends do not untap as normal during the untap phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1401</id>
  <name>Black Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Black Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Black Mana Battery: Add {B} to your mana pool, then add an additional {B} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Put one counter on Black Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. Remove as many counters as you wish. For each counter removed add {B} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1402</id>
  <name>Blue Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Blue Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Blue Mana Battery: Add {U} to your mana pool, then add an additional {U} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Put one counter on Blue Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. Remove as many counters as you wish. For each counter removed add {U} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1403</id>
  <name>Bronze Horse</name>
  <cost>{7}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Horse</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;If you control another creature, prevent all damage that would be dealt to Bronze Horse by spells that target it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Damage done to Bronze Horse by spells which target it is reduced to zero as long as you control another creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1404</id>
  <name>Forethought Amulet</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Forethought Amulet unless you pay {3}. &lt;br&gt;If an instant or sorcery spell would deal 3 or more damage to you, it deals 2 damage to you instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pay {3} during your upkeep or Forethought Amulet is destroyed. If you receive more than 2 damage from a sorcery or instant source, that damage is reduced to 2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1405</id>
  <name>Gauntlets of Chaos</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{5}, Sacrifice Gauntlets of Chaos: Exchange control of target artifact, creature, or land an opponent controls and a permanent you control if they share one of those types. Destroy all Auras attached to those permanents.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{5}: Sacrifice Gauntlets of Chaos. Take control of target land, creature, or artifact. Then give former controller of that permanent control of a target permanent of the same type under your control. You each control these permanents until game ends. Gauntlets of Chaos does not tap or untap these permanents. Enchantments on traded permanents are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1406</id>
  <name>Green Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Green Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Green Mana Battery: Add {G} to your mana pool, then add an additional {G} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Put one counter on Green Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. Remove as many counters as you wish. For each counter removed add {G} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1407</id>
  <name>Horn of Deafening</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Target creature deals no damage during combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"A blast, an echo . . . then silence."</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1408</id>
  <name>Knowledge Vault</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>When Knowledge Vault leaves play, put all cards removed from the game with Knowledge Vault into their owner's graveyard at end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{2}, {T}: Remove the top card of your library from the game face down. &lt;br&gt;Sacrifice Knowledge Vault: Discard your hand, then put all cards removed from the game with Knowledge Vault into their owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Take a card from your library without looking at it and place it face down under Knowledge Vault. Sacrifice Knowledge Vault to discard entire hand and take the cards under the vault into your hand. If Knowledge Vault leaves play, put all cards under it in your graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1409</id>
  <name>Kry Shield</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Prevent all damage that would be dealt this turn by target creature you control. That creature gets +0/+X until end of turn, where X is its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Target creature you control deals no damage this turn, but gains +0/+X until end of turn, where X is the casting cost of target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1410</id>
  <name>Life Chisel</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Sacrifice a creature: You gain life equal to the sacrificed creature's toughness. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sacrifice a creature during your upkeep to gain life equal to creature's toughness.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1411</id>
  <name>Life Matrix</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: Put a matrix counter on target creature and that creature gains "Remove a matrix counter from this creature: Regenerate this creature." Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4}{T}: During your upkeep, put one counter on target creature. You may remove this counter at any time to regenerate that creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1412</id>
  <name>Mana Matrix</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Instant and enchantment spells you play cost up to {2} less to play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pay up to {2} less than required whenever casting an instant, interrupt, or enchantment spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1413</id>
  <name>Marble Priest</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Cleric</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>All Walls able to block Marble Priest do so. &lt;br&gt;Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to Marble Priest by Walls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All walls able to block Marble Priest must do so. Walls able to block more than one creature can still do so. If blocking wall is compelled to block more creatures than it is legally able to, defender chooses which of these attacking creatures to block, but must block as many creatures as it legally can. Damage dealt to Marble Priest from walls during combat is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1414</id>
  <name>Mirror Universe</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice Mirror Universe: Exchange life totals with target opponent. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Sacrifice Mirror Universe during your upkeep, and trade your number of live points with opponent. For example, if you had 2 life points and your opponent had 10, you would now have 10 life points and your opponent would have 2. Effects that prevent or redirect damage may not be used to counter this change of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1415</id>
  <name>North Star</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: For one spell this turn, you may spend mana as though it were mana of any color to pay that spell's mana cost. (Additional costs are still paid normally.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4}{T}: You may cast one spell this turn by paying its casting cost with any type of mana. For example, {2}{G}{G} becomes {4}. However, the card still retains its original color. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1416</id>
  <name>Nova Pentacle</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: The next time a source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, that damage is dealt to target creature of an opponent's choice instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}{T}: Redirect damage done to you from one source to target creature of opponent's choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1417</id>
  <name>Planar Gate</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Creature spells you play cost up to {2} less to play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pay up to {2} less than required whenever casting a summon spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Nireya reached through the Gate, sensing the energies trapped beyond.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1418</id>
  <name>Red Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on Red Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from Red Mana Battery: Add {R} to your mana pool, then add an additional {R} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Put one counter on Red Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. Remove as many counters as you wish. For each counter removed add {R} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1419</id>
  <name>Relic Barrier</name>
  <cost>{2}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Tap target artifact.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target artifact becomes tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1420</id>
  <name>Ring of Immortals</name>
  <cost>{5}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Counter target instant or Aura spell that targets a permanent you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}{T}: Counter target interrupt or enchantment. Can only counter spells which target a permanent under your control. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1421</id>
  <name>Sentinel</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>{0}: Sentinel's toughness becomes 1 plus the power of target creature blocking or blocked by Sentinel. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>The * in the lower right hand corner is 1 when cast. While blocking, you may choose to change * to equal one plus the power of target creature sentinel blocks this turn. While attacking, you may choose to change * to equal one plus the power of target creature that blocks Sentinel this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1422</id>
  <name>Serpent Generator</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>{4}, {T}: Put a 1/1 Snake artifact creature token into play. This creature has "Whenever this creature deals damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter." (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{4}{T}: Put a Poison Snake token into play. Treat this token as a 1/1 artifact creature. If this creature damages opponent, opponent gets a poison counter. If opponent ever has ten or more poison counters, opponent loses game.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1423</id>
  <name>Sword of the Ages</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Sword of the Ages comes into play tapped. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove Sword of the Ages and any number of creatures you control from the game: Sword of the Ages deals X damage to target creature or player, where X is the total power of the creatures removed from the game this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sword of the Ages comes into play tapped.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Sacrifice Sword of the Ages and as many creatures as you choose. Sword does the combined power of these creatures in damage to one target. Sacrificed creatures and Sword are then removed from the game entirely.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1424</id>
  <name>Triassic Egg</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{3}, {T}: Put an incubation counter on Triassic Egg. &lt;br&gt;Remove two incubation counters from Triassic Egg, sacrifice Triassic Egg: You may put a creature card from your hand or graveyard into play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{3}{T}: Put one counter on Triassic Egg. If there are at least two such counters, you may sacrifice Triassic Egg to take any creature from your hand or graveyard and put it directly into play. Treat this creature as though it were just summoned.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1425</id>
  <name>Voodoo Doll</name>
  <cost>{6}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a pin counter on Voodoo Doll. &lt;br&gt;At the end of your turn, if Voodoo Doll is untapped, sacrifice it and it deals damage equal to the number of pin counters on it to you. &lt;br&gt;{X}{X}, {T}: Voodoo Doll deals X damage to target creature or player. X is the number of pin counters on Voodoo Doll.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put one counter on Voodoo Doll during your upkeep. If Voodoo Doll is not tapped at end of your turn, it does X damage to you and is destroyed. X equals the number of counters on Voodoo Doll.&lt;br&gt;{X}{X}{T}: Voodoo Doll does X damage to any one target.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1426</id>
  <name>White Mana Battery</name>
  <cost>{4}</cost>
  <type>Artifact</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}, {T}: Put a charge counter on White Mana Battery. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}, Remove any number of charge counters from White Mana Battery: Add {W} to your mana pool, then add an additional {W} to your mana pool for each charge counter removed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{T}: Put one counter on White Mana Battery.&lt;br&gt;{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. Remove as many counters as you wish. For each counter removed add {W} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1427</id>
  <name>Abomination</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Abomination blocks or becomes blocked by a green or white creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All green or white creatures blocking or blocked by Abomination are destroyed at the end of combat.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1428</id>
  <name>All Hallow's Eve</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove All Hallow's Eve from the game with two scream counters on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, if All Hallow's Eve is removed from the game with a scream counter on it, remove a scream counter from it. If there are no more scream counters on it, put it into your graveyard and each player returns all creature cards from his or her graveyard to play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put two counters on this card. Remove a counter during your upkeep. When you remove the last counter from All Hallow's Eve, all players take all creatures from their graveyards and put them directly into play. Treat these creatures as though they were just summoned. You choose what order they come into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1429</id>
  <name>Blight</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;When enchanted land becomes tapped, destroy it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target land becomes tapped, it is destroyed at the end of the turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1430</id>
  <name>Carrion Ants</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}: Carrion Ants gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"--'War is no picnic,' my father liked to say. But the Ants seemed to disagree."General Chanek Valteroth</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1431</id>
  <name>Chains of Mephistopheles</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>If a player would draw a card except the first one he or she draws in his or her draw step each turn, that player discards a card instead. If the player discards a card this way, he or she draws a card. If the player doesn't discard a card this way, he or she puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Every time a player draws a card, that player must first discard a card from his or her hand. If there are no cards in player's hand, take top card from library and place it in the graveyard instead of drawing. This enchantment does not apply to the first card drawn by a player during the draw phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1432</id>
  <name>Cosmic Horror</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you pay {3}{B}{B}{B}, sacrifice Cosmic Horror and it deals 7 damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;Pay {3}{B}{B}{B} during your upkeep or Cosmic Horror does 7 damage to you and is destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Then flashed the living lightning from her eyes,/ And screams of horror rend th' affrighted skies."&lt;br&gt;--Alexander Pope, The Rape of the Lock</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1433</id>
  <name>Cyclopean Mummy</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>When Cyclopean Mummy is put into a graveyard from play, remove Cyclopean Mummy from the game.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Mummy is placed in the graveyard from play, remove it from the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The ritual of plucking out an eye to gain future sight is but a curse that enables the living to see their own deaths.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1434</id>
  <name>Darkness</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures attack and block as normal, but none deal any damage. All attacking creatures are still tapped. Play any time before attack damage is assigned.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"If I must die, I will encounter darkness as a bride,/ And hug it in my arms."William Shakespeare, Measure for Measure</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1435</id>
  <name>Demonic Torment</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't attack. &lt;br&gt;Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature deals no damage during combat. Creature cannot attack.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1436</id>
  <name>Evil Eye of Orms-by-Gore</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Eye</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>Non-Eye creatures you control can't attack. &lt;br&gt;Evil Eye of Orms-by-Gore can't be blocked except by Walls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>None of your creatures can attack except for Evil Eyes. Evil Eye can only be blocked by walls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The highway of fear is the shortest route to defeat."</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1437</id>
  <name>Fallen Angel</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Angel</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Sacrifice a creature: Fallen Angel gets +2/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Sacrifice a creature to give Fallen Angel +2/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1438</id>
  <name>Ghosts of the Damned</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature gets -1/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature gets -1/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The voices of the dead ring in the heart long after they have faded from the ears.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1439</id>
  <name>Giant Slug</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Slug</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{5}: At the beginning of your next upkeep, choose a basic land type. Giant Slug gains landwalk of the chosen type until the end of that turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{5}: During controller's next upkeep Giant Slug gains landwalk ability of controller's choice until end of turn. The type of landwalk chosen must correspond with one of the five basic land types.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1440</id>
  <name>Glyph of Doom</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of combat, destroy all creatures that were blocked by target Wall this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures blocked by target wall are destroyed at the end of combat.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"He knows he has a short span of life, that the day will come when he must pass through the wall of oblivion . . ."William Faulkner</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1441</id>
  <name>Greed</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}, Pay 2 life: Draw a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Draw an extra card and lose 2 life. Effects that prevent or redirect damage may not be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"There is no calamity greater than lavish desires./ There is no greater guilt than discontentment./ And there is no greater disaster than greed."Tao Te Ching 46</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1442</id>
  <name>Headless Horseman</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie Knight</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . The ghost rides forth to the scene of battle in nightly quest of his head . . . he sometimes passes along the Hollow, like a midnight blast . . ."Washington Irving, The Legend of Sleepy Hollow</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1443</id>
  <name>Hell Swarm</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures get -1/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The brightness of day turned in an instant to dusk as the swarm descended upon the battlefield.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1444</id>
  <name>Hell's Caretaker</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Horror</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}, Sacrifice a creature: Return target creature card from your graveyard to play. Play this ability only during your upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: During your upkeep sacrifice a creature and take a creature from your graveyard and put it directly into play. Treat this creature as though it were just summoned.</printedText>
  <flavorText>You might leave here, Chenndra, should another take your place . . . .</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1445</id>
  <name>Hellfire</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all nonblack creatures. Hellfire deals X plus 3 damage to you, where X is the number of creatures put into all graveyards this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All non-black creatures are destroyed. Hellfire does X + 3 damage to you; X is the number of creatures placed in the graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"High on a throne of royal state . . . insatiate to pursue vain war with heav'n."John Milton, Paradise Lost</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1446</id>
  <name>Horror of Horrors</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Sacrifice a Swamp: Regenerate target black creature. (The next time that creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Allows caster to sacrifice a swamp to regenerate a target black creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"And a horror of outer darkness after,/ &lt;br&gt;And dust returneth to dust again."Adam Lindsay Gordon, The Swimmer</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1447</id>
  <name>Imprison</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever a player plays an activated ability of enchanted creature with {T} in its cost that isn't a mana ability, you may pay {1}. If you do, counter that ability. If you don't, sacrifice Imprison. &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature attacks or blocks, you may pay {1}. If you do, tap the creature and remove it from combat. Creatures it blocked that no other creatures blocked this combat become unblocked. If you don't pay {1}, sacrifice Imprison.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pay 1 each time target creature attempts to attack, block, or tap. That action is prevented and the creature becomes tapped. Destroy enchantment if mana is not paid.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1448</id>
  <name>Infernal Medusa</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Gorgon</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Infernal Medusa blocks or becomes blocked by a non-Wall creature, destroy that creature at end of combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All non-wall creatures blocking Medusa are destroyed at the end of combat, as are all creatures blocked by Medusa.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1449</id>
  <name>Jovial Evil</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Jovial Evil deals X damage to target opponent, where X is twice the number of white creatures that player controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Jovial Evil does 2 damage to opponent for each white creature he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Today, for a lark, let's visit the plains. I'm sure we'll find something to entertain us."</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1450</id>
  <name>Lesser Werewolf</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Wolf</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: If Lesser Werewolf's power is 1 or more, it gets -1/-0 until end of turn and put a -0/-1 counter on target creature blocking or blocked by Lesser Werewolf. Play this ability only during the declare blockers step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Lesser Werewolf gets -1/-0 until end of turn. Put a -0/-1 counter on target creature that blocks or is blocked by the Werewolf. Use this ability after defense is chosen but before damage is dealt. You may not use this ability to reduce the Lesser Werewolf's power below 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1451</id>
  <name>Lost Soul</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit Minion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>She walks in the twilight, her steps make no sound,/ Her feet leave no tracks on the dew-covered ground./ Her hand gently beckons, she whispers your name--/ But those who go with her are never the same.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1452</id>
  <name>Mold Demon</name>
  <cost>{5}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Fungus Demon</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>When Mold Demon comes into play, sacrifice it unless you sacrifice two Swamps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Mold Demon is brought into play, controller must sacrifice two swamps or Mold Demon is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1453</id>
  <name>Nether Void</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays a spell, counter it unless its controller pays {3}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All spells cast are countered unless their casters pay an additional {3}.</printedText>
  <flavorText>These days, some wizards are finding that they have a little too much spell left at the end of their mana.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1454</id>
  <name>Pit Scorpion</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Scorpion</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Pit Scorpion deals damage to a player, that player gets a poison counter. (A player with ten or more poison counters loses the game.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Scorpion damages opponent, opponent gets a poison counter. If opponent ever has ten or more poison counters, opponent loses game.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Sometimes the smallest nuisance can be the greatest pain.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1455</id>
  <name>Quagmire</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with swampwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have swampwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with swampwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1456</id>
  <name>Shimian Night Stalker</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Nightstalker</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}, {T}: All damage that would be dealt to you this turn by target attacking creature is dealt to Shimian Night Stalker instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{T}: Redirect all damage done to you from any one attacking creature to the Shimian Night Stalker.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"--'Tis now the very witching time of night,/ When churchyards yawn and hell itself breathes out/ Contagion to this world."William Shakespeare, Hamlet</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1457</id>
  <name>Spirit Shackle</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature becomes tapped, put a -0/-2 counter on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put a -0/-2 counter on target creature every time it becomes tapped. Counters remain even if enchantment is removed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1458</id>
  <name>Syphon Soul</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Syphon Soul deals 2 damage to each other player. You gain life equal to the damage dealt this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Syphon Soul does 2 damage to all players except caster. Caster gains life points equal to the amount of damage done by Syphon Soul.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Her lips suck forth; see, where it flies"&lt;br&gt;--Christopher Marlowe, The Tragical History of Doctor Faustus</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1459</id>
  <name>Takklemaggot</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, put a -0/-1 counter on that creature. &lt;br&gt;When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, that creature's controller returns a card named Takklemaggot from its owner's graveyard to play. If Takklemaggot can't be attached to a creature, it comes into play as an enchantment under that player's control with "At the beginning of your upkeep, Takklemaggot deals 1 damage to you" instead and it's no longer an Aura.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put a 0/-1 counter on target creature during its controller's upkeep. If the creature is placed in the graveyard, its controller chooses a new target for Takklemaggot. If there are no legal targets, Takklemaggot becomes an enchantment and does 1 damage to the controller of the last creature Takklemaggot was on, during his or her upkeep. Takklemaggot does not revert to a creature enchantment even if other creatures are afterwards brought into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1460</id>
  <name>The Abyss</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, destroy target nonartifact creature that player controls of his or her choice. It can't be regenerated.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players bury one target non-artifact creature under their control, if they have any, during their upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"An immense river of oblivion is sweeping us away into a nameless abyss."Ernest Renan, Souvenirs d'Enfance et de Jeunesse</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1461</id>
  <name>The Wretched</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Demon</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>At end of combat, gain control of all creatures blocking The Wretched as long as you control The Wretched.</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of combat take control of all creatures that blocked The Wretched. The Wretched does not tap or untap these creatures. You lose control of these creatures if The Wretched leaves play or if you lose control of The Wretched.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1462</id>
  <name>Touch of Darkness</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Any number of target creatures become black until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Changes the color of one or more target creatures to black until end of turn. You choose which and how many creatures are affected. Cost to tap, maintain, or to use a special ability of target creatures remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Black spirits and white, red spirits and gray,/ Mingle, mingle, mingle, you that mingle may."Thomas Middleton, The Witch</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1463</id>
  <name>Transmutation</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Until end of turn, target creature's power and toughness are switched. Effects that alter power alter toughness instead, and vice versa.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"You know what I was,/ You see what I am: change me, change me"&lt;br&gt;--Randall</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1464</id>
  <name>Underworld Dreams</name>
  <cost>{B}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent draws a card, Underworld Dreams deals 1 damage to him or her.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Underworld Dreams does one damage to opponent for each card he or she draws.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"In the drowsy dark cave of the mind dreams build their nest with fragments dropped from day's caravan."Rabindranath Tagore</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1465</id>
  <name>Vampire Bats</name>
  <cost>{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bat</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying (This creature can't be blocked except by creatures with flying or reach.) &lt;br&gt;{B}: Vampire Bats gets +1/+0 until end of turn. Play this ability no more than twice each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, {B}: +1/+0 until end of turn. No more than {B}{B} may be spent in this way per turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"For something is amiss or out of place/ When mice with wings can wear a human face."Theodore Roethke, "The Bat"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1466</id>
  <name>Walking Dead</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Zombie</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}: Regenerate Walking Dead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}: Regenerates</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Walking Dead are the remains of freakish experiments by the Necromantic Lords.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1467</id>
  <name>Wall of Putrid Flesh</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Protection from white &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Wall of Putrid Flesh by enchanted creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from white&lt;br&gt;Damage done to wall by creatures with enchantment cards played on them is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1468</id>
  <name>Wall of Shadows</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Pete Venters</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Wall of Shadows by creatures it's blocking. &lt;br&gt;Wall of Shadows can't be the target of spells that can target only Walls or of abilities that can target only Walls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Damage Wall of Shadows receives from creatures it blocks is reduced to 0. Effects that target only walls may not target Wall of Shadows.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1469</id>
  <name>Wall of Tombstones</name>
  <cost>{1}{B}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, Wall of Tombstones's toughness becomes 1 plus the number of creature cards in your graveyard. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>At the end of your upkeep, the * below is set to the number of creatures in your graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1470</id>
  <name>Acid Rain</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all Forests.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroys all forests in play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1471</id>
  <name>Anti-Magic Aura</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be the target of spells and can't be enchanted. This effect doesn't remove Anti-Magic Aura.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All enchantments on target creature are destroyed. Target creature cannot be further targeted by instants, sorceries, or enchantments.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1472</id>
  <name>Azure Drake</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Drake</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Azure Drake would be more powerful were it not so easily distracted.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1473</id>
  <name>Backfire</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to you, Backfire deals that much damage to that creature's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For each point of damage done to you from target creature Backfire does one point of damage to target creature's controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1474</id>
  <name>Boomerang</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Return target permanent to owner's hand; enchantments on target permanent are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"O call back yesterday, bid time return."William Shakespeare, King Richard the Second</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1475</id>
  <name>Brine Hag</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Hag</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>When Brine Hag is put into a graveyard from play, all creatures that dealt damage to it this turn become 0/2. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>On the turn during which Hag is placed in the graveyard, all creatures who dealt damage to Hag that turn become 0/2 creatures. Use counters to mark these creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1476</id>
  <name>Devouring Deep</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Fish</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Islandwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Islandwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Full fathom five thy father lies;/ Of his bones are coral made;/ Those are pearls that were his eyes;/ Nothing of him that doth fade,/ But doth suffer a sea-change/ Into something rich and strange."William Shakespeare, The Tempest</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1477</id>
  <name>Dream Coat</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anthony Waters</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;{0}: Enchanted creature becomes the color or colors of your choice. Play this ability only once each turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Caster may change target creature's color to any other color. This ability is played as an interrupt. Limit of one change per turn. Cost to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creature remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Adopt the character of the twisting octopus, which takes on the appearance of the nearby rock. Now follow in this direction, now turn a different hue."Theognis, Elegies 1, 215</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1478</id>
  <name>Elder Spawn</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you sacrifice an Island, sacrifice Elder Spawn and it deals 6 damage to you. &lt;br&gt;Elder Spawn can't be blocked by red creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Elder Spawn cannot be blocked by red creatures. Sacrifice one of your islands during your upkeep or Elder Spawn does 6 damage to you and is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1479</id>
  <name>Enchantment Alteration</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Attach target Aura attached to a creature or land to another permanent of that type.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Switch target enchantment from one creature to another or from one land to another. The controller of the enchantment does not change. New target of enchantment must be valid or this spell has no effect. Treat this as if the enchantment had just been cast on the new target.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1480</id>
  <name>Energy Tap</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap target untapped creature you control. If you do, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that creature's converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target untapped creature you control becomes tapped. Add an amount of colorless mana equal to target creature's casting cost to your mana pool.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1481</id>
  <name>Field of Dreams</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Players play with the top card of their libraries revealed.</oracleText>
  <printedText>The top card of each player's library is always face up.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Some people say that the world is round, and if you travel far enough you'll come to the other side, where everything is upside down.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1482</id>
  <name>Flash Counter</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target instant spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counters target interrupt or instant spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"She grinned at me--a wicked grin. --'I hope you weren't relying too heavily on that, my dear.'"Medryn Silverwand, Diary</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1483</id>
  <name>Flash Flood</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Destroy target red permanent; or return target Mountain to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target red permanent, or return target mountain to owner's hand. Enchantments on target land are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Many people say that no power can bring the mountains low. Many people are fools.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1484</id>
  <name>Force Spike</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell unless its controller pays {1}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target spell is countered unless its caster spends an additional {1}.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1485</id>
  <name>Gaseous Form</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to and dealt by enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Damage done to target creature by creatures it blocks, or that block it, is reduced to 0. Creature deals no damage during combat.</printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . And gives to airy nothing/ A local habitation and a name."William Shakespeare, A Midsummer-Night's Dream</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1486</id>
  <name>Glyph of Delusion</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Put X glyph counters on target creature that target Wall blocked this turn, where X is the power of that blocked creature. The creature gains "This creature doesn't untap during your untap step if it has a glyph counter on it" and "At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a glyph counter from this creature."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put X counters on one target creature that target wall blocked during this turn; X is the power of the blocked creature. Creature does not untap as normal while it has one or more of these counters on it. Remove one counter during creature's controller's upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1487</id>
  <name>In the Eye of Chaos</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays an instant spell, counter it unless that player pays {X}, where X is its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All instants and interrupts are countered unless their caster pays an additional {X}, where X is the casting cost of the spell being cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1488</id>
  <name>Invoke Prejudice</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent plays a nonartifact creature spell that doesn't share a color with a creature you control, counter that spell unless its controller pays {X}, where X is its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If opponent casts a Summon spell that does not match the color of one of the creatures under your control, that spell is countered unless the caster pays an additional {X} where X is the casting cost of the Summon spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1489</id>
  <name>Juxtapose</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>You and target player exchange control of the creature you each control with the highest converted mana cost. Then exchange control of artifacts the same way. If two or more permanents a player controls are tied for highest cost, their controller chooses one of them.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player and caster each choose one of the creatures they control with the highest casting cost. Exchange control of these creatures. Then do the same for artifacts. Juxtapose does not tap or untap these cards. The control of any enchantment cards played on these permanents is unchanged. If one player does not have an artifact or creature do not trade that type of card.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1490</id>
  <name>Land Equilibrium</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>If an opponent who controls at least as many lands as you do would put a land into play, that player instead puts that land into play then sacrifices a land.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If your opponent controls at least as much land as you do, he or she must sacrifice a land for each land he or she puts into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1491</id>
  <name>Mana Drain</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target spell. At the beginning of your next main phase, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is that spell's converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counters target spell. At the beginning of your next main phase, add {X} to your mana pool, where X is the casting cost of target spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1492</id>
  <name>Part Water</name>
  <cost>{X}{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>X target creatures gain islandwalk until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>X target creatures gain islandwalk until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . and the waters were a wall unto them on their right hand, and on their left."Exodus, 14:22</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1493</id>
  <name>Psionic Entity</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Illusion</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Psionic Entity deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 3 damage to itself.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Psionic Entity does 2 damage to any target but does 3 damage to itself.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Creatures of the Aether are notorious for neglecting their own well-being.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1494</id>
  <name>Psychic Purge</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Psychic Purge deals 1 damage to target creature or player. &lt;br&gt;When a spell or ability an opponent controls causes you to discard Psychic Purge, that player loses 5 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Psychic Purge does 1 damage to any target. If a spell cast by opponent or a permanent under opponent's control causes you to discard this card, opponent loses 5 life. Effects that prevent or redirect damage may not be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1495</id>
  <name>Puppet Master</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;When enchanted creature is put into a graveyard, return that card to its owner's hand and you may pay {U}{U}{U}. If you do, return a card named Puppet Master from your graveyard to your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target creature is placed in the graveyard, return creature to owner's hand. All enchantments on target creature are destroyed. You may pay {U}{U}{U} to return Puppet Master to its owner's hand if target creature returns to its owner's hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1496</id>
  <name>Recall</name>
  <cost>{X}{X}{U}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Discard X cards, then return a card from your graveyard to your hand for each card discarded this way. Remove Recall from the game.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Sacrifice X cards from your hand and then bring X cards from your graveyard to your hand. Then remove Recall from the game.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1497</id>
  <name>Relic Bind</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant artifact an opponent controls &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted artifact becomes tapped, choose one - Relic Bind deals 1 damage to target player; or target player gains 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When target artifact is tapped, the controller of Relic Bind can choose to do 1 damage to any player or give 1 life to any player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1498</id>
  <name>Remove Soul</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target creature spell.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target summon spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Nethya stiffened suddenly, head cocked as if straining to hear some distant sound, then felt lifeless to the ground.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1499</id>
  <name>Reset</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Reset only during an opponent's turn after his or her upkeep step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Untap all lands you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your lands untap. Reset can only be played on an opponent's turn after his or her upkeep phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1500</id>
  <name>Reverberation</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>All damage that would be dealt this turn by target sorcery spell is dealt to that spell's controller instead.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Damage from one sorcery spell is redirected to its caster.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1501</id>
  <name>Sea Kings' Blessing</name>
  <cost>{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Any number of target creatures become blue until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Changes the color of one or more target creatures to blue until end of turn. You choose which and how many creatures are affected. Cost to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creature(s) remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1502</id>
  <name>Segovian Leviathan</name>
  <cost>{4}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Leviathan</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Islandwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Islandwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Leviathan, too Can you catch him with a fish-hook/ or run a line round his tongue?"Job 40:25</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1503</id>
  <name>Silhouette</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn by spells or abilities that target it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Until end of turn, damage done to target creature by spells or effects that target it is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1504</id>
  <name>Spectral Cloak</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has shroud as long as it's untapped. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be the target of instants, sorceries, fast effects, or enchantments unless creature is tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1505</id>
  <name>Telekinesis</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap target creature. Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by that creature this turn. It doesn't untap during its controller's next two untap steps.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature deals no damage during combat this turn. Creature becomes tapped and may not untap as normal during its controller's next two untap phases.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1506</id>
  <name>Teleport</name>
  <cost>{U}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Teleport only during combat before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt;Target creature is unblockable this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked until end of turn. Play after attack is declared and before defense is chosen.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1507</id>
  <name>Time Elemental</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>When Time Elemental attacks or blocks, at end of combat, sacrifice it and it deals 5 damage to you. &lt;br&gt;{2}{U}{U}, {T}: Return target permanent that isn't enchanted to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{U}{U}{T}: Return target permanent to owner's hand. Cannot target permanents with enchantment cards played on them.&lt;br&gt;If Time Elemental blocks or attacks it is destroyed and does 5 damage to controller.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1508</id>
  <name>Undertow</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with islandwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have islandwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with islandwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1509</id>
  <name>Venarian Gold</name>
  <cost>{X}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Venarian Gold comes into play with X sleep counters on it. &lt;br&gt;When Venarian Gold comes into play, tap enchanted creature. &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step if Venarian Gold has a sleep counter on it. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of the upkeep of enchanted creature's controller, remove a sleep counter from Venarian Gold.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put X counters on target creature. Target creature becomes tapped when Venarian Gold is cast. Creature does not untap as normal if it has any of these counters on it. Remove one counter during creature's controller's upkeep phase.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1510</id>
  <name>Wall of Vapor</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Prevent all damage that would be dealt to Wall of Vapor by creatures it's blocking.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Damage done to Wall of Vapor by creatures it blocks is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Walls of a castle are made out of stone,/ Walls of a house out of bricks or of wood./ My walls are made out of magic alone,/ Stronger than any that ever have stood."Chrysoberyl Earthsdaughter, Incantations</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1511</id>
  <name>Wall of Wonder</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{2}{U}{U}: Wall of Wonder gets +4/-4 until end of turn and can attack this turn as though it didn't have defender.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{U}{U}: Gain +4/-4 and allow Wall of Wonder to attack this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>So confusing is the Wall's appearance that few of is victims even see it move.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1512</id>
  <name>Zephyr Falcon</name>
  <cost>{1}{U}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, vigilance</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;Attacking does not cause Zephyr Falcon to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Although greatly prized among falconers, the Zephyr Falcon is capricious and not easily tamed.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{U}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1513</id>
  <name>Aisling Leprechaun</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Faerie</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Aisling Leprechaun blocks or becomes blocked by a creature, that creature becomes green. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures that block or are blocked by Leprechaun become green creatures. Use counters to indicate changed creatures. Cost to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creature remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1514</id>
  <name>Arboria</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures can't attack a player who didn't play a spell and didn't put a card into play during his or her last turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If a player does not cast a spell or put a card into play on his or her turn, no creatures may attack that player until after his or her next turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1515</id>
  <name>Avoid Fate</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target instant or Aura spell that targets a permanent you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counters target interrupt or enchantment. Can only counter spells that target a permanent under your control.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1516</id>
  <name>Barbary Apes</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ape</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Unpredictable in the extreme, these carnivorous apes will prey even upon their own kind.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1517</id>
  <name>Cat Warriors</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Cat Warrior</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Forestwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Forestwalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>These stealthy felines have survived so many battles that some believe they must possess many lives.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1518</id>
  <name>Cocoon</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature you control &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature doesn't untap during your untap step if Cocoon has a pupa counter on it. &lt;br&gt;When Cocoon comes into play, tap enchanted creature and put three pupa counters on Cocoon. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove a pupa counter from Cocoon. If you can't, sacrifice it and enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and gains flying. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap target creature you control and put three counters on it. Target creature does not untap as normal while it has one or more of these counters on it. Remove one counter during your upkeep. During the upkeep phase after the one in which the last counter was removed, Cocoon is destroyed and target creature gains a +1/+1 counter and flying ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1519</id>
  <name>Concordant Crossroads</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures have haste.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures may attack or use abilities that include the {T} symbol during the turn they are brought into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1520</id>
  <name>Craw Giant</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Rampage: 2</printedText>
  <flavorText>Harthag gave a jolly laugh as he surveyed the army before him. "Ho ho ho Midgets You think you can stand in my way?"</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1521</id>
  <name>Deadfall</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with forestwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have forestwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with forestwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1522</id>
  <name>Durkwood Boars</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Boar</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mike Kimble</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"And the unclean spirits went out, and entered the swine; and the herd ran violently . . ."Mark 5:13</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1523</id>
  <name>Elven Riders</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elf</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa A. Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Elven Riders can't be blocked except by Walls and/or creatures with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Cannot be blocked by any creatures except walls and flying creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sometimes it is better to be swift of foot than strong of swordarm."Eleven Proverb</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1524</id>
  <name>Emerald Dragonfly</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}{G}: Emerald Dragonfly gains first strike until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, {G}{G}: First strike until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Flittering, wheeling,/ darting in to strike, and then/ gone just as you blink." &lt;br&gt;--"Dragonfly Haiku," poet unkown</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1525</id>
  <name>Eureka</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Starting with you, each player may put a permanent card from his or her hand into play. Repeat this process until no one puts a card into play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Both players may take any permanent in their hand and put it directly into play. Players take turns playing one card from their hand until neither wants to play more permanents. No other spells or effects of any kind may be used while Eureka is in effect. If a spell has an X in its casting cost, X is 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1526</id>
  <name>Fire Sprites</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Faerie</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}, {T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1527</id>
  <name>Floral Spuzzem</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever Floral Spuzzem attacks and isn't blocked, you may destroy target artifact defending player controls. If you do, Floral Spuzzem deals no combat damage this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Floral Spuzzem attacks an opponent and is not blocked, then Floral Spuzzem may choose to destroy a target artifact under that opponent's control and deal no damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1528</id>
  <name>Giant Turtle</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Turtle</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Giant Turtle can't attack if it attacked during your last turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Giant Turtle may not attack if it attacked during your last turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The turtle lives 'twixt plated decks/ Which practically conceal its sex./ I think it clever of the turtle/ In such a fix to be so fertile."Ogden Nash, "The Turtle"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1529</id>
  <name>Glyph of Reincarnation</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Glyph of Reincarnation only during the end of combat step. &lt;br&gt;Destroy all creatures that were blocked by target Wall this turn. They can't be regenerated. For each creature put into a graveyard this way, choose a creature card from the graveyard of that creature's controller and return that card to play under its owner's control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Play after combat is over. All surviving creatures blocked by target wall this turn are buried. For each creature buried in this manner, choose one creature from attacker's graveyard and return it to play under attacker's control. Treat these creatures as if they were just summoned. If there are not enough creatures in attacker's graveyard, all creatures in attacker's graveyard are returned to play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1530</id>
  <name>Hornet Cobra</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Snake</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Then inch by inch out of the grass rose up the head and spread hood of Nag, the big black cobra, and he was five feet long from tongue to tail."Rudyard Kipling, The Jungle Books</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1531</id>
  <name>Ichneumon Druid</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Druid</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever an opponent plays an instant spell other than the first instant spell that player plays each turn, Ichneumon Druid deals 4 damage to him or her.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Ichneumon Druid does 4 damage to any opponent casting an instant. This does not apply to the first instant cast by that opponent in each turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1532</id>
  <name>Killer Bees</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Insect</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}: Killer Bees gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}: +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The communal mind produces a savage strategy, yet no one could predict that this vicious crossbreed would unravel the secret of steel.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1533</id>
  <name>Living Plane</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>All lands are 1/1 creatures that are still lands.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Treat all land in play as both lands and 1/1 creatures. They may not be tapped for mana the first turn they are brought into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1534</id>
  <name>Master of the Hunt</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{G}{G}: Put a 1/1 green Wolf creature token named Wolves of the Hunt into play. That creature has "bands with other Wolves."</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{G}{G}: Put a Wolves of the Hunt token into play. Treat this token as a 1/1 green creature with the ability bands with other Wolves of the Hunt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1535</id>
  <name>Moss Monster</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>After the battle, an eerie silence gripped the forest. The losers' remains were lightly dusted with green.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1536</id>
  <name>Pixie Queen</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Faerie</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{G}{G}{G}, {T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}{G}{G}{T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1537</id>
  <name>Pradesh Gypsies</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Nomad</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{G}{T}: Target creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1538</id>
  <name>Rabid Wombat</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wombat</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Vigilance &lt;br&gt;Rabid Wombat gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Wombat gains +2/+2 for each creature enchantment on it. Attacking does not cause Rabid Wombat to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1539</id>
  <name>Radjan Spirit</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Spirit</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature loses flying until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target creature loses flying ability until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1540</id>
  <name>Rebirth</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Rebirth from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Each player may put the top card of his or her library into the ante. If a player does, his or her life total becomes 20.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Each player may choose to be healed to 20 life. Any player choosing to be healed antes an additional card from the top of his or her library. Remove this card from your deck before playing if you are not playing for ante.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1541</id>
  <name>Reincarnation</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose target creature. When that creature is put into a graveyard this turn, return a creature card from that graveyard to play under the control of that creature's owner.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If target creature is placed in graveyard this turn, bring a creature from that graveyard directly into play under the control of the owner of the target creature. Treat this creature as though it were just summoned.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1542</id>
  <name>Revelation</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>All players play with their hands revealed.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players play with the cards in their hands face up on the table.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Many are in high place, and of renown: but mysteries are revealed unto the meek."Ecclesiastes 3:19</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1543</id>
  <name>Rust</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Counter target activated ability from an artifact source.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Counter target artifact effect, which must require an activation cost.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"How dull it is to pause, to make an end,/ To rust unburnished, not to shine in use,/ As though to breathe were life"Alfred, Lord Tennyson, "Ulysses"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1544</id>
  <name>Shelkin Brownie</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ouphe</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target creature loses all "bands with other" abilities until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Remove the bands with other ability from target creature until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Leave a bowl of milk on your doorstep each night for the brownies, or they'll cause you no end of mischief.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1545</id>
  <name>Storm Seeker</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Storm Seeker deals damage equal to the number of cards in target player's hand to that player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Storm Seeker does 1 damage to opponent for every card in his or her hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1546</id>
  <name>Subdue</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn. That creature gets +0/+X until end of turn, where X is its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature deals no damage during combat but gains X toughness until end of turn; X is target creature's casting cost.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1547</id>
  <name>Sylvan Library</name>
  <cost>{1}{G}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your draw step, you may draw two cards. If you do, choose two cards in your hand drawn this turn. For each of those cards, pay 4 life or put the card on top of your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may draw two extra cards during your draw phase, then either put two of the cards drawn this turn back on top of your library (in any order), or lose 4 lives per card not replaced. Effects that prevent or redirect damage may not be used to counter this loss of life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1548</id>
  <name>Sylvan Paradise</name>
  <cost>{G}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Any number of target creatures become green until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Changes the color of one or more target creatures to green until end of turn. You choose which and how many creatures are affected. Cost to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creatures remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1549</id>
  <name>Typhoon</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Typhoon deals damage to each opponent equal to the number of Islands that player controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Typhoon does 1 damage to each opponent for each island he or she controls.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Fierce winds ripped across the tropical landscape. What they did not destroy with their fiery breath was washed away by torrential rain.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1550</id>
  <name>Untamed Wilds</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Search your library for a basic land card and put that card into play. Then shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Search your library for any one basic land and put it into play. This does not count towards your one land per turn limit. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1551</id>
  <name>Whirling Dervish</name>
  <cost>{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Monk</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from black &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, if Whirling Dervish dealt damage to an opponent this turn, put a +1/+1 counter on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black&lt;br&gt;Gains +1/+1 (use counters) at the end of each turn in which it does damage to opponent.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1552</id>
  <name>Willow Satyr</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Satyr</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Willow Satyr during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target legendary creature as long as you control Willow Satyr and Willow Satyr remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Gain control of target legend. If Willow Satyr becomes untapped, you lose control of this legend; you may choose not to untap Willow Satyr as normal. You also lose control of legend if Willow Satyr leaves play, if you lose control of Willow Satyr, or if the game ends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1553</id>
  <name>Winter Blast</name>
  <cost>{X}{G}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap X target creatures. Winter Blast deals 2 damage to each of those creatures with flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>X target creatures become tapped. Winter Blast does 2 damage to each target creature that has flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Blow, winds, and crack your cheeks rage blow"William Shakespeare, King Lear</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1554</id>
  <name>Wolverine Pack</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolverine</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Rampage: 2</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Give them great meals of beef and iron and steel, they will eat like wolves and fight like devils."William Shakespeare, King Henry V</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1555</id>
  <name>Wood Elemental</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>0</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>As Wood Elemental comes into play, sacrifice any number of untapped Forests. Wood Elemental comes into play with a +1/+1 counter for each Forest sacrificed this way.</oracleText>
  <printedText>*s in the lower right-hand corner are set to the number of untapped forests you sacrifice when Wood Elemental is brought into play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1556</id>
  <name>Active Volcano</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Destroy target blue permanent; or return target Island to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target blue permanent or return target island to owner's hand. Enchantments on target land are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1557</id>
  <name>rathi Berserker</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Berserker</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Rampage 3 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +3/+3 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Rampage: 3</printedText>
  <flavorText>Aerathi children who show promise are left to survive for a year in the wilderness. Those who return are shown the way of the Berserker</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1558</id>
  <name>Backdraft</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>This turn, whenever target sorcery spell deals damage, Backdraft deals half that much damage, rounded down, to that spell's controller.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Backdraft does half of the damage (rounded down) done by one sorcery cast this turn to the caster of the sorcery.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1559</id>
  <name>Beasts of Bogardan</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Beast</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from red &lt;br&gt;Beasts of Bogardan gets +1/+1 as long as any opponent controls a white permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from red&lt;br&gt;Gains +1/+1 if an opponent controls any white cards.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Bogardan is a land as volatile as the creatures who live there.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1560</id>
  <name>Blazing Effigy</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>When Blazing Effigy is put into a graveyard from play, Blazing Effigy deals X damage to target creature, where X is 3 plus the amount of damage dealt to Blazing Effigy this turn by other sources named Blazing Effigy.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When placed in the graveyard from play, Effigy does 3 damage to target creature. If an Effigy is damaged by another Effigy in this manner and is placed in the graveyard that turn, it deals the amount of damage received from the other Effigy in addition to its normal 3.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1561</id>
  <name>Blood Lust</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>If target creature has toughness 5 or greater, it gets +4/-4 until end of turn. Otherwise, it gets +4/-X until end of turn, where X is its toughness minus 1.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creatures gain +4/-4 until end of turn. If this reduces creature's toughness below 1, creature's toughness is 1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1562</id>
  <name>Caverns of Despair</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>No more than two creatures can attack each combat. &lt;br&gt;No more than two creatures can block each combat.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players may attack with no more than two creatures each turn and block with no more than two creatures each turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1563</id>
  <name>Chain Lightning</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Chain Lightning deals 3 damage to target creature or player. Then that player or that creature's controller may pay {R}{R}. If the player does, he or she may copy this spell and may choose a new target for that copy.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Chain Lightning does 3 damage to one target. Each time Chain Lightning does damage, the target or target's controller may then pay {R}{R} to have Chain Lightning do 3 damage to any target of that player's choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1564</id>
  <name>Crevasse</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with mountainwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have mountainwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with mountainwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1565</id>
  <name>Crimson Kobolds</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Crimson Kobolds is red.</oracleText>
  <printedText>This card is a red spell when cast and Kobolds are a red creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Kobolds are harmless."&lt;br&gt;--Bearand the Bold, epitaph</flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1566</id>
  <name>Crimson Manticore</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Manticore</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{R}, {T}: Crimson Manticore deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{R}{T}: Manticore does 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Noted neither for their good looks nor their charm, Crimson Manticores can be fearsome allies. As dinner companions, however, they are best left alone.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1567</id>
  <name>Crookshank Kobolds</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>Crookshank Kobolds is red.</oracleText>
  <printedText>This card is a red spell when cast and Kobolds are a red creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Crookshank military boasts a standing army of nearly twenty-four million, give or take twenty-two million.</flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1568</id>
  <name>Disharmony</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Disharmony only during combat before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Untap target attacking creature. Gain control of that creature until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target attacking creature comes under your control untapped. Return to former controller at end of turn. This creature is no longer considered to have attacked. Play before defense is chosen.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1569</id>
  <name>Dwarven Song</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Any number of target creatures become red until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Changes the color of one or more target creatures to red until end of turn. You choose which and how many creatures are affected. Cost to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creatures remains entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1570</id>
  <name>Eternal Warrior</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature has vigilance.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Attacking does not tap target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Warriors of the Tsunami-nito School spend years in training to master the way of effortless effort.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1571</id>
  <name>Falling Star</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Flip Falling Star onto the playing area from a height of at least one foot. Falling Star deals 3 damage to each creature it lands on. Tap all creatures dealt damage by Falling Star. If Falling Star doesn't turn completely over at least once during the flip, it has no effect.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flip Star onto the playing area from a height of at least one foot. Star must turn at least 360 degrees or it has no effect. When Falling Star lands, Falling Star does 3 damage to each creature that it touches. Any creatures damaged by Falling Star that are not destroyed become tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1572</id>
  <name>Feint</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Tap all creatures blocking target attacking creature. Prevent all combat damage this turn that would be dealt by that creature and all creatures blocking it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures blocking target attacking creature become tapped. Target attacking creature and all creatures blocking it deal no damage during combat.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1573</id>
  <name>Firestorm Phoenix</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Phoenix</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;If Firestorm Phoenix would be put into a graveyard from play, return Firestorm Phoenix to its owner's hand instead. It can't be played again until its owner's next turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;If Phoenix is placed in the graveyard from play, return it to owner's hand instead. It may not be summoned again until owner's next turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The bird of wonder dies, the maiden phoenix,/ Her ashes new-create another heir/ As great in admiration as herself."William Shakespeare, King Henry the Eighth.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1574</id>
  <name>Frost Giant</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Rampage: 2</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Frost Giants have been out in the cold a long, long time, but they have their rage to keep them warm.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1575</id>
  <name>Giant Strength</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains +2/+2</printedText>
  <flavorText>"O it is excellent/ To have a giant's strength, but it is tyrannous/ To use it like a giant."William Shakespeare, Measure for Measure</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1576</id>
  <name>Glyph of Destruction</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Target blocking Wall you control gets +10/+0 until end of combat. Prevent all damage that would be dealt to it this turn. Destroy it at end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target wall you control gains +10/+0 when blocking. Any damage dealt to target wall is reduced to zero. Target wall is destroyed at end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1577</id>
  <name>Gravity Sphere</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures lose flying.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures lose flying ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText>On the morning of the Battle of Gal-Shan, the Sorcerer's cry rang out: "Let no bird fly, let no creature take wing, let all the battle join as one."</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1578</id>
  <name>Hyperion Blacksmith</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Artificer</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: You may tap or untap target artifact an opponent controls.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target artifact controlled by opponent becomes tapped or untapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The smith a mighty man is he/ With large and sinewy hands./ And the muscles of his brawny arms/ Are strong as iron bands."Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, The Village Blacksmith</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1579</id>
  <name>Immolation</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +2/-2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains +2/-2.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1580</id>
  <name>Kobold Drill Sergeant</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold Soldier</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Other Kobold creatures you control get +0/+1 and have trample.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your Kobolds gain +0/+1 and Trample.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Joining this army is easy, boy. Just survive your first battle."</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1581</id>
  <name>Kobold Overlord</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Kobold creatures you control have first strike.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;All your Kobolds gain first strike.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"One for all, all for one; we strike first, and then you're done"Oath of the Kobold Musketeers</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1582</id>
  <name>Kobold Taskmaster</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Other Kobold creatures you control get +1/+0.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your Kobolds gain +1/+0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Taskmaster knows that there is no cure for the common Kobold.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1583</id>
  <name>Kobolds of Kher Keep</name>
  <cost>{0}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Kobolds of Kher Keep is red.</oracleText>
  <printedText>This card is a red spell when cast and Kobolds are a red creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Kher Keep is unique among fortresses: impervious to aerial assault but defenseless from the ground.</flavorText>
  <cmc>0</cmc>
  <color>{_}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1584</id>
  <name>Land's Edge</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Discard a card: If the discarded card is a land card, Land's Edge deals 2 damage to target player. Any player may play this ability.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Any player may discard a card from hand at any time. If that player discards a land, Land's Edge does 2 damage to target player of the discarding player's choice.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1585</id>
  <name>Mountain Yeti</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Yeti</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Mountainwalk, protection from white</oracleText>
  <printedText>Mountainwalk, protection from white.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The Yeti's single greatest asset is its unnerving ability to blend in with its surroundings.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1586</id>
  <name>Primordial Ooze</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ooze</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Primordial Ooze attacks each turn if able. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, put a +1/+1 counter on Primordial Ooze. Then pay {X}, where X is equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on Primordial Ooze, or tap Primordial Ooze and it deals X damage to you.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Must attack each turn if possible. Gains +1/+1 at end of your upkeep. Use counters. Then pay {1} per counter or Ooze deals 1 damage to you for each counter and becomes tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The thick, moving mass from the beginning of evolution swallows and digests the animate and inanimate as it unthinkingly strives to continue its existence.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1587</id>
  <name>Pyrotechnics</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>Pyrotechnics deals 4 damage divided as you choose among any number of target creatures and/or players.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Pyrotechnics does 4 damage divided any way you choose among any number of targets.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Hi ni ya Behold the man of flint, that's me Four lightnings zigzag from me, strike and return."&lt;br&gt;--Navajo war chant</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1588</id>
  <name>Quarum Trench Gnomes</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Gnome</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: If target Plains is tapped for mana, it produces colorless mana instead of any other type. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target plains produces {1} instead of {W} until end of game. Use counters.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"O Great Captain, all is lost. They tunneled, they burrowed, they trenched. They sapped the strength of our defenses."Sorgus, Chronicles of the Quarum Plains</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1589</id>
  <name>Raging Bull</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Ox</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"Sometimes the bulls win, and sometimes the bears win. But the bulls have more fun."Anonymous</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1590</id>
  <name>Spinal Villain</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Beast</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Anson Maddocks</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Destroy target blue creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Destroy target blue creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Striking silent as a dream,/ Cutting short the strangled scream . . ."Tobrian, "Watchdragon"</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1591</id>
  <name>Storm World</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>World Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, Storm World deals X damage to that player, where X is 4 minus the number of cards in his or her hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If any player has less than four cards in hand at the end of his or her upkeep, Storm World does one damage to that player for each card less than four.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1592</id>
  <name>Tempest Efreet</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Efreet</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Remove Tempest Efreet from your deck before playing if you're not playing for ante. &lt;br&gt;{T}, Sacrifice Tempest Efreet: Target opponent may pay 10 life. If that player doesn't, he or she reveals a card at random from his or her hand. Exchange ownership of the revealed card and Tempest Efreet. Put the revealed card into your hand and Tempest Efreet from anywhere into that player's graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Pick a card at random from opponent's hand and place it in yours. Bury Tempest Efreet in opponent's graveyard. The change in ownership is permanent. Play as an interrupt, but opponent may prevent effect by paying 10 life or conceding game before the card to be switched is chosen--if this is done, Tempest Efreet is buried. Effects that prevent or redirect damage may not be used to counter this loss of life. Remove this card from deck if not playing for ante.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1593</id>
  <name>The Brute</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +1/+0. &lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Regenerate enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains +1/+0&lt;br&gt;{R}{R}{R}: Regenerates</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Union may be strength, but it is mere blind brute strength unless wisely directed."Samuel Butler</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1594</id>
  <name>Wall of Dust</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever Wall of Dust blocks a creature, that creature can't attack during its controller's next turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures blocked by Wall of Dust cannot attack during your opponent's next turn. Use counters to mark these creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText>An ever-moving swarm of dust engulfs and disorients anything that comes near.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1595</id>
  <name>Wall of Earth</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>The ground shuddered violently and the earth seemed to come to life. The elemental force contained in the vast wall of earth was trapped, bent to its controller's will.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1596</id>
  <name>Wall of Heat</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.)</oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>At a distance, we mistook the sound for a waterfall . . .</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1597</id>
  <name>Wall of Opposition</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>0</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;{1}: Wall of Opposition gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}: +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Like so many obstacles in life, the Wall of Opposition is but an illusion, held fast by the focus and belief of the one who creates it.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1598</id>
  <name>Winds of Change</name>
  <cost>{R}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players shuffle their hands into their libraries, and then draw the same number of cards they originally held.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"--'Tis the set of sails, and not the gales,/ Which tells us the way to go."Ella Wheeler Wilcox</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1599</id>
  <name>Akron Legionnaire</name>
  <cost>{6}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant Soldier</type>
  <power>8</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Except for creatures named Akron Legionnaire and artifact creatures, creatures you control can't attack.</oracleText>
  <printedText>None of your non-artifact creatures may attack except Akron Legionnaire.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1600</id>
  <name>Alabaster Potion</name>
  <cost>{X}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Harold McNeill</artist>
  <oracleText>Choose one - Target player gains X life; or prevent the next X damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target player gains X life or prevents X damage to any one creature or player.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Healing is a matter of time, but it is sometimes also a matter of opportunity."D'Avenant proverb</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1601</id>
  <name>Amrou Kithkin</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Kithkin</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Amrou Kithkin can't be blocked by creatures with power 3 or greater.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with power greater than 2 may not be assigned to block Kithkin. Blocker's power may be increased after blocking has been assigned.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Quick and agile, Amrou Kithkin can usually escape from even the most fearsome opponents.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1602</id>
  <name>Angelic Voices</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures you control get +1/+1 as long as you control no nonartifact, nonwhite creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>As long as the only creatures you control are white or artifact creatures all your creatures gain +1/+1.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1603</id>
  <name>Cleanse</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy all black creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All black creatures in play are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The clouds broke and the sun's rays burst forth; each foul beast in its turn faltered, and was gone.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1604</id>
  <name>Clergy of the Holy Nimbus</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>If Clergy of the Holy Nimbus would be destroyed, regenerate it. &lt;br&gt;{1}: Clergy of the Holy Nimbus can't be regenerated this turn. Only any opponent may play this ability.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Clergy are destroyed or take lethal damage, unless opponent pays {1} Clergy are regenerated.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1605</id>
  <name>D'Avenant Archer</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier Archer</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: D'Avenant Archer deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Archer does 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1606</id>
  <name>Divine Intervention</name>
  <cost>{6}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>Divine Intervention comes into play with two intervention counters on it. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, remove an intervention counter from Divine Intervention. If there are no intervention counters on it, the game is a draw.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put two counters on this card. Remove a counter during your upkeep. When you remove the last counter from Divine Intervention, the game is over and considered a draw.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1607</id>
  <name>Divine Offering</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Destroy target artifact. You gain life equal to its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Destroy target artifact. You gain life points equal to casting cost of artifact.</printedText>
  <flavorText>D'Haren stared at the twisted lump of metal that had been a prized artifact. The fight was getting ugly.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1608</id>
  <name>Divine Transformation</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains +3/+3.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Glory surged through her and radiance surrounded her. All things were possible with the blessing of the Divine.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1609</id>
  <name>Elder Land Wurm</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Dragon Wurm</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender, trample &lt;br&gt;When Elder Land Wurm blocks, it loses defender.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Wurm cannot attack until it has been assigned as a blocker.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Sometimes it's best to let sleeping dragons lie.</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1610</id>
  <name>Enchanted Being</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to Enchanted Being by enchanted creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Any damage dealt to Enchanted Being during combat by creatures with one or more enchantment cards played on them is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1611</id>
  <name>Equinox</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant land &lt;br&gt;Enchanted land has "{T}: Counter target spell if it would destroy a land you control."</oracleText>
  <printedText>Tap land enchanted with Equinox to counter a spell that destroys one or more of your lands. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1612</id>
  <name>Fortified Area</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Wall creatures you control get +1/+0 and have banding.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your walls gain +1/+0 and banding.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1613</id>
  <name>Glyph of Life</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Susan Van Camp</artist>
  <oracleText>Until end of turn, whenever an attacking creature deals damage to target Wall creature, you gain that much life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Damage done to target wall by attacking creatures is added to your life point total.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Any wall can be battered down, but at what cost?</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1614</id>
  <name>Great Defender</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Target creature gets +0/+X until end of turn, where X is its converted mana cost.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature gains +0/+X until end of turn where X is the creature's casting cost.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1615</id>
  <name>Great Wall</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures with plainswalk can be blocked as though they didn't have plainswalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures with plainswalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1616</id>
  <name>Greater Realm of Preservation</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>{1}{W}: The next time a black or red source of your choice would deal damage to you this turn, prevent that damage.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{1}{W}: Prevents all damage against you from one red or black source. If a source does damage to you more than once in a turn, you must pay {1}{W} each time you want to prevent the damage.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1617</id>
  <name>Heaven's Gate</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Any number of target creatures become white until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Changes the color of one or more target creatures to white until end of turn. You choose which and how many creatures are affected. Costs to tap, maintain, or use a special ability of target creatures remain entirely unchanged.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1618</id>
  <name>Holy Day</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Creatures attack and block as normal, but none deal any damage. All attacking creatures are still tapped. Play any time before attack damage is assigned.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"The day of spirits; my soul's clam retreat/ Which none disturb"Henry Vaughan, "Silex Scintillans"</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1619</id>
  <name>Indestructible Aura</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Until end of turn, prevent all damage that would be dealt to target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Any damage dealt to target creature for remainder of turn is reduced to 0.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Theodar strode the battle lines, snatching swords with his bare hands and casting them aside until all cowered before him.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1620</id>
  <name>Infinite Authority</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature blocks or becomes blocked by a creature with toughness 3 or less, destroy the other creature at end of combat. At end of turn, if that creature was put into a graveyard this way, put a +1/+1 counter on the first creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures with toughness 3 or less blocking target creature or blocked by target creature are destroyed at end of combat. At the end of the turn put a +1/+1 counter on the target creature for each creature destroyed in this manner during the turn. Counters remain on creature even if enchantment leaves play.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1621</id>
  <name>Ivory Guardians</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Giant Cleric</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Protection from red &lt;br&gt;Creatures named Ivory Guardians get +1/+1 as long as an opponent controls a red permanent.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from red&lt;br&gt;All guardians gain +1/+1 if an opponent controls any red cards.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The elite guard of the Mesa High Priests, the Ivory Guardians, were created to protect the innocent and faithful. Some say their actions are above the law.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1622</id>
  <name>Keepers of the Faith</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>And then the Archangel Anthius spoke to them, saying, "Fear shall be vanquished--by the Sword of Faith."</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1623</id>
  <name>Kismet</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Artifacts, creatures, and lands your opponents control come into play tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures, lands, and artifacts played by opponent come into play tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1624</id>
  <name>Land Tax</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent controls more lands than you, you may search your library for up to three basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, if an opponent controls more land than you, you may search your library and remove up to three basic land cards and put them into your hand. Reshuffle your library afterwards.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1625</id>
  <name>Lifeblood</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a Mountain an opponent controls becomes tapped, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You gain 1 life point each time one of opponent's mountains becomes tapped.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Foolish wizard As you tap the power of your lofty keep, so grows my strength."Malvern Xelionos, Letters</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1626</id>
  <name>Moat</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures without flying can't attack.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Non-flying creatures cannot attack.</printedText>
  <flavorText>The purpose of any moat is to impede attack. Some are filled with water, some with thistles. Some are filled with things best left unseen.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1627</id>
  <name>Osai Vultures</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Bird</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Dan Frazier</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At end of turn, if a creature was put into a graveyard from play this turn, put a carrion counter on Osai Vultures. &lt;br&gt;Remove two carrion counters from Osai Vultures: Osai Vultures gets +1/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;At the end of any turn in which a creature is placed in the graveyard from play, put a counter on the Vultures. Remove two counters to give Vultures +1/+1 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>A sign of battle, the Vultures circle and wait for the victorious to depart.</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1628</id>
  <name>Petra Sphinx</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Sphinx</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target player names a card, then reveals the top card of his or her library. If that card is the named card, that player puts it into his or her hand. If it isn't, the player puts it into his or her graveyard.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target player names a card and then turns over the top card of his or her library. If it matches the named card, the card is put in the player's hand; otherwise it is put into the graveyard.</printedText>
  <flavorText>What walks on four legs in the morning, two legs in the afternoon, and three legs in the evening?</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1629</id>
  <name>Presence of the Master</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Whenever a player plays an enchantment spell, counter it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>While Presence of the Master is in play, any new enchantments cast are countered.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1630</id>
  <name>Rapid Fire</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Justin Hampton</artist>
  <oracleText>Play Rapid Fire only before the declare blockers step. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Target creature gains first strike until end of turn. If it doesn't have rampage, that creature gains rampage 2 until end of turn. (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Play before defense is chosen. Target creature gains first strike until end of turn. If the creature does not already have rampage, then it also gains rampage: 2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1631</id>
  <name>Remove Enchantments</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Return all enchantments you own and control to your hand. Then destroy all Auras attached to permanents you control and/or attached to attacking creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Remove all enchantments you control and remove all enchantment cards played on all permanents you control. If this spell is cast during opponent's attack, also remove all enchantment cards played on attacking creatures. All enchantments you own are returned to your hand; all other enchantments are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1632</id>
  <name>Righteous Avengers</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Heather Hudson</artist>
  <oracleText>Plainswalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>Plainswalk</printedText>
  <flavorText>Few can withstand the wrath of the righteous.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1633</id>
  <name>Seeker</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature &lt;br&gt;Enchanted creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or white creatures.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Target creature cannot be blocked by any creatures except white creatures and artifact creatures.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1634</id>
  <name>Shield Wall</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Instant</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Douglas Shuler</artist>
  <oracleText>Creatures you control get +0/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your creatures gain +0/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1635</id>
  <name>Spirit Link</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment - Aura</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Kaja Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>Enchant creature (Target a creature as you play this. This card comes into play attached to that creature.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever enchanted creature deals damage, you gain that much life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>For every point of damage target creature does, you gain 1 life.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1636</id>
  <name>Spiritual Sanctuary</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Enchantment</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Amy Weber</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of each player's upkeep, if that player controls a Plains, he or she gains 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All players with plains under his or her control gains 1 life point during upkeep.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1637</id>
  <name>Thunder Spirit</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Elemental Spirit</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, first strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike, flying.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"It was full of fire and smoke and light and . . . it drove between us and the Efrafans like a thousand thunderstorms with lightning."Richard Adams, Watership Down</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1638</id>
  <name>Tundra Wolves</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wolf</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Quinton Hoover</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>I heard their eerie howling, the wolves calling their kindred across the frozen plains.</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1639</id>
  <name>Visions</name>
  <cost>{W}</cost>
  <type>Sorcery</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Look at the top five cards of target player's library. You may then have that player shuffle that library.</oracleText>
  <printedText>You may look at the top five cards of any library. You may then choose to shuffle that library.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Visions of glory, spare my aching sight,/ Ye unborn ages, crowd not on my soul"&lt;br&gt;--Thomas Gray, The Bard</flavorText>
  <cmc>1</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1640</id>
  <name>Wall of Caltrops</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Common</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Brian Snoddy</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Whenever Wall of Caltrops blocks a creature, if no non-Wall creatures are blocking that creature, Wall of Caltrops gains banding until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Wall of Caltrops and one or more other walls join to block an attacker and no other creatures besides walls block that attacker, Wall of Caltrops gains banding ability until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Ow Ow ow ow Oooh, ow, OW"</flavorText>
  <cmc>2</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1641</id>
  <name>Wall of Light</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}</cost>
  <type>Creature - Wall</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Defender (This creature can't attack.) &lt;br&gt;Protection from black</oracleText>
  <printedText>Protection from black</printedText>
  <flavorText>As many attackers were dazzled by the wall's beauty as were halted by its force.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1642</id>
  <name>Adun Oakenshield</name>
  <cost>{B}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jeff A. Menges</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}{R}{G}, {T}: Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{G}{R}{B}{T}: Select one creature from your graveyard and place it in your hand.</printedText>
  <flavorText>". . . And at his passing, the bodies of the world's great warriors shall rise from their graves and follow him to battle."The Anvilonian Grimoire</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1643</id>
  <name>Angus Mackenzie</name>
  <cost>{G}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{G}{W}{U}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}{U}{G}{T}: Creatures attack and block as normal, but none deal any damage during combat. All attacking creatures are still tapped. Use this ability any time before attack damage is dealt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Battles no longer served a purpose in Karakas."Angus Mackenzie, Diary</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1644</id>
  <name>Arcades Sabboth</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{G}{W}{W}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elder Dragon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Arcades Sabboth unless you pay {G}{W}{U}. &lt;br&gt;Untapped nonattacking creatures you control get +0/+2. &lt;br&gt;{W}: Arcades Sabboth gets +0/+1 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{W}: +0/+1 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;Your untapped creatures gain +0/+2. Attacking creatures do not get this bonus. Pay {W}{G}{U} during your upkeep or Arcades Sabboth is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{U}{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1645</id>
  <name>Axelrod Gunnarson</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{B}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>Trample &lt;br&gt;Whenever a creature dealt damage by Axelrod Gunnarson this turn is put into a graveyard, you gain 1 life and Axelrod deals 1 damage to target player.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Trample&lt;br&gt;Each time a creature is placed in the graveyard during a turn in which Axelrod damaged it, you gain 1 life and Axelrod does 1 damage to target player.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1646</id>
  <name>Ayesha Tanaka</name>
  <cost>{W}{W}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Artificer</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>Banding &lt;br&gt;{T}: Counter target activated ability from an artifact source unless that ability's controller pays {W}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Banding&lt;br&gt;{T}: Artifact effect which requires an activation cost is countered unless its controller spends {W}. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1647</id>
  <name>Barktooth Warbeard</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>He is devious and cunning, in both appearance and deed. Beware the Warbeard, for this brute bites as well as he barks</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1648</id>
  <name>Bartel Runeaxe</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Giant Warrior</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>Vigilance &lt;br&gt;Bartel Runeaxe can't be the target of Aura spells.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Bartel Runeaxe cannot be the target of enchant creature spells. Attacking does not cause Bartel Runeaxe to tap.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Thundering down from Hammerheim, no foe could slow Bartel's charge.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1649</id>
  <name>Boris Devilboon</name>
  <cost>{3}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Zombie Wizard</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Jesper Myrfors</artist>
  <oracleText>{2}{B}{R}, {T}: Put a 1/1 black and red Demon creature token named Minor Demon into play.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{2}{B}{R}{T}: Put a minor demon token into play. Treat this token as a 1/1 red and black creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1650</id>
  <name>Chromium</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{W}{U}{U}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elder Dragon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;Rampage 2 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +2/+2 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.) &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Chromium unless you pay {W}{U}{B}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, Rampage: 2&lt;br&gt;Pay {B}{U}{W} during your upkeep or Chromium is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1651</id>
  <name>Dakkon Blackblade</name>
  <cost>{2}{W}{U}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>*</power>
  <toughness>*</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Dakkon Blackblade's power and toughness are each equal to the number of lands you control.</oracleText>
  <printedText>The *s below equal the number of lands you control.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"My power is as vast as the plains, my strength is that of mountains. Each wave that crashes upon the shore thunders like blood in my veins."Memoirs</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1652</id>
  <name>Gabriel Angelfire</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Angel</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Daniel Gelon</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, choose flying, first strike, trample, or rampage 3. Gabriel Angelfire gains that ability until your next upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>During your upkeep, Gabriel gains one of the following abilities until your next upkeep: flying, first strike, trample, or rampage: 3.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1653</id>
  <name>Gosta Dirk</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{W}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike &lt;br&gt;Creatures with islandwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have islandwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;Creatures with islandwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1654</id>
  <name>Gwendlyn Di Corci</name>
  <cost>{U}{B}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Rogue</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Target player discards a card at random. Play this ability only during your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Target player discards one card from his or her hand at random. This power may only be used during your turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Urborg became the final resting place of many swordsmen of renown, their steel outmatched by the wiles of Gwendlyn.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1655</id>
  <name>Halfdane</name>
  <cost>{1}{W}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Shapeshifter</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, Halfdane's power and toughness become equal to the power and toughness of target creature other than Halfdane, until the end of your next upkeep.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Halfdane comes into play he is 3/3. During your upkeep, Halfdane acquires the current power and toughness of target creature other than Halfdane. If there are no legal targets, Halfdane becomes 3/3.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Hail from Tolaria the ever changing 'Dane.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1656</id>
  <name>Hazezon Tamar</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>When Hazezon Tamar enters the battlefield, put X 1/1 Sand Warrior creature tokens that are red, green, and white onto the battlefield at the beginning of your next upkeep, where X is the number of lands you control at that time.  When Hazezon leaves the battlefield, exile all Sand Warriors.</oracleText>
  <printedText>On your next upkeep after Hazezon is put into play, put * token Sand Warriors into play, where * is the number of lands under your control. Treat the Warriors as 1/1 white, green, and red creatures. If Hazezon leaves play, all Sand Warriors are also removed from game.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1657</id>
  <name>Hunding Gjornersen</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{U}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText>Rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Rampage: 1</printedText>
  <flavorText>"You would never guess, at the terrifying sight of the man, that Hunding was as charming a companion as one could wish for."</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1658</id>
  <name>Jacques le Vert</name>
  <cost>{1}{R}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>Green creatures you control get +0/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your green creatures gain +0/+2.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Abandoning his sword to return to the lush forest of Pendelhaven, Jacques le Vert devoted his life to protecting the creatures of his homeland.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1659</id>
  <name>Jasmine Boreal</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"Peace must prevail, even if the wicked must die."</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1660</id>
  <name>Jedit Ojanen</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Cat Warrior</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Mightiest of the Cat Warriors, Jedit Ojanen forsook the forests of his tribe and took service with the Robaran Mercenaries, rising through their ranks to lead them in the battle for Efrava.</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1661</id>
  <name>Jerrard of the Closed Fist</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Once, the order of the Closed Fist reached throughout the Kb'Briann Highlands. Now, Jerrard alone remains to uphold their standard.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1662</id>
  <name>Johan</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your combat phase, you may have Johan gain "Johan can't attack" until end of combat. If you do, attacking doesn't cause creatures you control to tap this combat if Johan is untapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>If Johan does not attack and is not tapped, any of your creatures may attack without tapping.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1663</id>
  <name>Kasimir the Lone Wolf</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Popular indeed is the tale of how Kasimir was once a Holy man who renounced his order to take up the sword. But this tale is no more likely than any other.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1664</id>
  <name>Kei Takahashi</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Scott Kirschner</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Prevent the next 2 damage that would be dealt to target creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Prevent up to 2 damage to one creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1665</id>
  <name>Lady Caleria</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Archer</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Lady Caleria deals 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Lady Caleria does 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1666</id>
  <name>Lady Evangela</name>
  <cost>{W}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>{W}{B}, {T}: Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt by target creature this turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{W}{T}: Target creature does no damage during combat this turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"When milady was young, the sight of a rainbow would fill her soul with peace. As she grew, she learned to share her rapture with others."Lady Gabriella</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1667</id>
  <name>Lady Orca</name>
  <cost>{5}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Demon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Sandra Everingham</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"I do not remember what he said to her. I remember her fiery eyes, fixed upon him for an instant. I remember a flash, and the hot breath of sudden flames made me turn away. When I looked again, Angus was gone."A Wayfarer, on meeting Lady Orca</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1668</id>
  <name>Livonya Silone</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike, legendary landwalk</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike, Legendary Land-walk.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Livonya's own nature is a matter of mystery. Nothing is known for sure, merely rumors of unearthly stealth, and unholy alliances.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1669</id>
  <name>Lord Magnus</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Druid</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Tedin</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike &lt;br&gt;Creatures with plainswalk can be blocked as though they didn't have plainswalk. &lt;br&gt;Creatures with forestwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have forestwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;Creatures with plainswalk or forestwalk may be blocked as if they did not have either ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1670</id>
  <name>Marhault Elsdragon</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elf Warrior</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>6</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Rampage 1 (Whenever this creature becomes blocked, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each creature blocking it beyond the first.)</oracleText>
  <printedText>Rampage: 1</printedText>
  <flavorText>Marhault follows a strict philosophy, never letting emotions cloud his thoughts. No chance observer could imagine the rage in his heart.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1671</id>
  <name>Nebuchadnezzar</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>{X}, {T}: Name a card. Target opponent reveals X cards at random from his or her hand. That player then discards all cards with that name revealed this way. Play this ability only during your turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{X}{T}: Name a card. Opponent reveals X cards from his or her hand at random, or entire hand if he or she does not have enough cards. Opponent then discards any of those cards that match the one you named. May only use this power during your turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1672</id>
  <name>Nicol Bolas</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}{B}{B}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elder Dragon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Nicol Bolas unless you pay {U}{B}{R}. &lt;br&gt;Whenever Nicol Bolas deals damage to an opponent, that player discards his or her hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;An opponent damaged by Nicol Bolas must discard entire hand. Ignore this effect if opponent has no cards left in hand. Pay {U}{B}{R} during your upkeep or Nicol Bolas is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1673</id>
  <name>Palladia-Mors</name>
  <cost>{2}{R}{R}{G}{G}{W}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elder Dragon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying, trample &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Palladia-Mors unless you pay {R}{G}{W}.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying, Trample&lt;br&gt;Pay {W}{G}{R} during your upkeep or Palladia-Mors is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1674</id>
  <name>Pavel Maliki</name>
  <cost>{4}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>{B}{R}: Pavel Maliki gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{B}{R}: +1/+0 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>We all know the legend: Pavel wanders the realms, helping those in greatest need. But is this a measure of his generosity, or of his obligation to atone?</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1675</id>
  <name>Princess Lucrezia</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.&lt;br&gt;This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1676</id>
  <name>Ragnar</name>
  <cost>{G}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Cleric</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>{G}{W}{U}, {T}: Regenerate target creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{W}{U}{G}{T}: Regenerate target creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"On the field of honor, a soldier need have no fear."</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1677</id>
  <name>Ramirez DePietro</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Pirate</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Phil Foglio</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike</printedText>
  <flavorText>Ramirez DePietro is a most flamboyant pirate. Be careful not to believe his tall tales, especially when you ask his age.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1678</id>
  <name>Ramses Overdark</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{U}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Assassin</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Destroy target enchanted creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Destroys a target creature which has an enchantment card played on it.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1679</id>
  <name>Rasputin Dreamweaver</name>
  <cost>{4}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>1</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>Rasputin Dreamweaver comes into play with seven dream counters on it. &lt;br&gt;Remove a dream counter from Rasputin: Add {1} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;Remove a dream counter from Rasputin: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to Rasputin this turn. &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, if Rasputin started the turn untapped, put a dream counter on it. Rasputin can't have more than seven dream counters on it.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Put seven counters on Rasputin when brought into play. You may remove a counter to prevent one damage to Rasputin or add {1} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt. Put one counter on Rasputin during your upkeep if he started the turn untapped. You may not have more than seven of these counters on Rasputin at any time.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1680</id>
  <name>Riven Turnbull</name>
  <cost>{5}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Advisor</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Political violence is a perfectly legitimate answer to the persecution handed down by dignitaries of the state."</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1681</id>
  <name>Rohgahh of Kher Keep</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}{R}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Kobold</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Edward Beard, Jr.</artist>
  <oracleText>At the beginning of your upkeep, unless you pay {R}{R}{R}, an opponent gains control of Rohgahh of Kher Keep and all creatures you control named Kobolds of Kher Keep. If a player gains control of a creature this way, tap it. (This effect doesn't end at end of turn.) &lt;br&gt;Creatures you control named Kobolds of Kher Keep get +2/+2.</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your Kobolds of Kher Keep gain +2/+2. Pay {R}{R}{R} during your upkeep, or Rohgahh and all Kobolds of Kher Keep become tapped and come under opponent's control.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1682</id>
  <name>Rubinia Soulsinger</name>
  <cost>{2}{G}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Faerie</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Rob Alexander</artist>
  <oracleText>You may choose not to untap Rubinia Soulsinger during your untap step. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Gain control of target creature as long as you control Rubinia and Rubinia remains tapped.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Gain control of target creature. Rubinia does not tap or untap this creature. If Rubinia becomes untapped you lose control of this creature; you may choose not to untap Rubinia as normal during your untap phase. You also lose control of target creature if either Rubinia leaves play or you lose control of Rubinia.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1683</id>
  <name>Sir Shandlar of Eberyn</name>
  <cost>{4}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Knight</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"Remember Sir Shandlar Remember and stand firm"rallying cry of the Eberyn militia</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1684</id>
  <name>Sivitri Scarzam</name>
  <cost>{5}{U}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human</type>
  <power>6</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>NeNe Thomas</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Even the brave have cause to tremble at the sight of Sivitri Scarzam. Who else has tamed Scarzam's Dragon?</flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1685</id>
  <name>Sol'kanar the Swamp King</name>
  <cost>{2}{U}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Demon</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText>Swampwalk &lt;br&gt;Whenever a player plays a black spell, you gain 1 life.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Swampwalk&lt;br&gt;Sol'kanar's controller gains 1 life each time a black spell is cast.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1686</id>
  <name>Stangg</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Warrior</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>When Stangg comes into play, if Stangg is in play, put a legendary 3/4 red and green Human Warrior creature token named Stangg Twin into play. When Stangg leaves play, remove that token from the game. When that token leaves play, sacrifice Stangg.</oracleText>
  <printedText>When Stangg is brought into play, also put a Stangg Twin token into play. Stangg Twin token is a 3/4 green and red legend. If Stangg leaves play, remove Stangg Twin token from game. If Stangg Twin leaves play, bury Stangg.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1687</id>
  <name>Sunastian Falconer</name>
  <cost>{3}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Shaman</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {2} to your mana pool. This ability is played as an interrupt.</printedText>
  <flavorText>Sunastian has roots in both sorcery and swordplay; he has learned never to depend too heavily on the latter.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1688</id>
  <name>Tetsuo Umezawa</name>
  <cost>{U}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Archer</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Julie Baroh</artist>
  <oracleText>Tetsuo Umezawa can't be the target of Aura spells. &lt;br&gt;{U}{B}{B}{R}, {T}: Destroy target tapped or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{R}{B}{B}{U}{T}: Destroy target tapped creature or target blocking creature. Tetsuo may not be a target of an enchant creature spell.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1689</id>
  <name>The Lady of the Mountain</name>
  <cost>{4}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Giant</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Richard Kane Ferguson</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Her given name has been lost in the mists of time. Legend says that her silent vigil will one day be ended by the one who, pure of heart and spirit, calls out that name again.</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1690</id>
  <name>The Tabernacle at Pendrell Vale</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>(none)</artist>
  <oracleText>All creatures have "At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice this creature unless you pay {1}."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All creatures now require an upkeep cost of {1} in addition to any other upkeep costs they may have. If the upkeep cost for a creature is not paid, the creature is destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1691</id>
  <name>Tobias Andrion</name>
  <cost>{3}{W}{U}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Advisor</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>Administrator of the military state of Sheoltun, Tobias is the military right arm of the empire and the figurehead of its freedom.</flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{U}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1692</id>
  <name>Tor Wauki</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}{R}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Archer</type>
  <power>3</power>
  <toughness>3</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Randy Asplund-Faith</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Tor Wauki deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Tor Wauki does 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>5</cmc>
  <color>{B}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1693</id>
  <name>Torsten Von Ursus</name>
  <cost>{3}{G}{G}{W}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Soldier</type>
  <power>5</power>
  <toughness>5</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText></oracleText>
  <printedText></printedText>
  <flavorText>"How can you accuse me of evil? Though these deeds be unsavory, no one will argue: good shall follow from them."</flavorText>
  <cmc>6</cmc>
  <color>{G}{W}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1694</id>
  <name>Tuknir Deathlock</name>
  <cost>{R}{R}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Human Wizard</type>
  <power>2</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Liz Danforth</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{R}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}{R}{T}: Target creature gains +2/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>An explorer of the Aether, Tuknir often discovers himself in the most unusual physical realms.</flavorText>
  <cmc>4</cmc>
  <color>{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1695</id>
  <name>Ur-Drago</name>
  <cost>{3}{U}{U}{B}{B}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elemental</type>
  <power>4</power>
  <toughness>4</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Christopher Rush</artist>
  <oracleText>First strike &lt;br&gt;Creatures with swampwalk can be blocked as though they didn't have swampwalk.</oracleText>
  <printedText>First strike&lt;br&gt;Creatures with swampwalk may be blocked as if they did not have this ability.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>7</cmc>
  <color>{U}{B}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1696</id>
  <name>Vaevictis Asmadi</name>
  <cost>{2}{B}{B}{R}{R}{G}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Elder Dragon</type>
  <power>7</power>
  <toughness>7</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Andi Rusu</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Vaevictis Asmadi unless you pay {B}{R}{G}. &lt;br&gt;{B}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{R}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn. &lt;br&gt;{G}: Vaevictis Asmadi gets +1/+0 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{B}: Gain +1/+0 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;{R}: Gain +1/+0 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;{G}: Gain +1/+0 until end of turn.&lt;br&gt;Pay {B}{R}{G} during your upkeep or Vaevictis Asmadi is buried.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc>8</cmc>
  <color>{B}{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1697</id>
  <name>Xira Arien</name>
  <cost>{B}{R}{G}</cost>
  <type>Legendary Creature - Insect Wizard</type>
  <power>1</power>
  <toughness>2</toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Rare</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Melissa Benson</artist>
  <oracleText>Flying &lt;br&gt;{B}{R}{G}, {T}: Target player draws a card.</oracleText>
  <printedText>Flying&lt;br&gt;{G}{R}{B}{T}: Target player draws one card.</printedText>
  <flavorText>A regular guest at the Royal Masquerade, Arien is the envy of the Court. She appears in a new costume every hour.</flavorText>
  <cmc>3</cmc>
  <color>{B}{G}{R}</color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1698</id>
  <name>Adventurers' Guildhouse</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Green legendary creatures you control have "bands with other legendary creatures."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your green legends gain bands with other legends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1699</id>
  <name>Cathedral of Serra</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>White legendary creatures you control have "bands with other legendary creatures."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your white legends gain bands with other legends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1700</id>
  <name>Hammerheim</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature loses all landwalk abilities until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool&lt;br&gt;{T}: Remove all landwalking ability from target creature until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"--'Tis distance lends enchantment to the view,/ And robes the mountain in its azure hue."Thomas Campbell, "Pleasures of Hope"</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1701</id>
  <name>Karakas</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Return target legendary creature to its owner's hand.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {W} to your mana pool&lt;br&gt;{T}: Return target legend to owner's hand; enchantments on target legend are destroyed.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"To make a prairie it takes a clover and one bee,/ One clover, and a bee,/ And revery."Emily Dickinson</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1702</id>
  <name>Mountain Stronghold</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Red legendary creatures you control have "bands with other legendary creatures."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your red legends may band with other legends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1703</id>
  <name>Pendelhaven</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target 1/1 creature gets +1/+2 until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool&lt;br&gt;{T}: Target 1/1 creature gains +1/+2 until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"This is the forest primeval. The murmuring pines and the hemlocks . . . / Stand like Druids of old."Henry Wadsworth&lt;br&gt;Longfellow, "Evangeline"</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1704</id>
  <name>Seafarer's Quay</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Tom Wanerstrand</artist>
  <oracleText>Blue legendary creatures you control have "bands with other legendary creatures."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your blue legends gain bands with other legends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1705</id>
  <name>Tolaria</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Nicola Leonard</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature loses banding and all "bands with other" abilities until end of turn. Play this ability only during any upkeep step.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool&lt;br&gt;{T}: During upkeep remove the banding or bands with other ability from target creature until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Fairest Isle, all isles excelling,/ Seat of pleasures, and of loves . . ."John Dryden</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1706</id>
  <name>Unholy Citadel</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Mark Poole</artist>
  <oracleText>Black legendary creatures you control have "bands with other legendary creatures."</oracleText>
  <printedText>All your black legends gain bands with other legends.</printedText>
  <flavorText></flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
<mc>
  <id>1707</id>
  <name>Urborg</name>
  <cost></cost>
  <type>Legendary Land</type>
  <power></power>
  <toughness></toughness>
  <edition>Legends</edition>
  <rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
  <setNumber></setNumber>
  <artist>Bryon Wackwitz</artist>
  <oracleText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;{T}: Target creature loses first strike or swampwalk until end of turn.</oracleText>
  <printedText>{T}: Add {B} to your mana pool&lt;br&gt;{T}: Remove first strike ability or swampwalk ability from target creature until end of turn.</printedText>
  <flavorText>"Resignedly beneath the sky/The melancholy waters lie./So blend the turrets and shadows there/That all seem pendulous in air,/While from a proud tower in town/Death looks gigantically down."Edgar Allan Poe, "The City in the Sea"</flavorText>
  <cmc></cmc>
  <color></color>
</mc>
</list>
</cards>